heated I'm Highland today on Highland
cooking and making Chinese
egg rolls which might more properly
called Chinese American and world
because they're
complete bastardization original genuine
spring rolls I'm sure
but anyway these are great for snacks
and appetizers are even Easter
because they're called egg roll get it
but I really through your guests for a
loop
be like one with Chinese we doing here
with him
well
%uh home
%uh
when a person we're going to do is make
are filling
cities have a pre-cooked feeling that
you an
will cook it and cool it before we feel
they are gross madeleine oil
to repay an and starts at a and got some
super
very very finely minced celery and onion
here
so all that's goin'
I've got also here about a half a pound
of ground pork
can use ground turkey you could leave
out the meat completely an ad for
vegetables if you want to
also a minute add to this the
all I've got some brown sugar some corn
starch and feminist
as garlic and ginger so when you add
cornstarch to ground me like this
can help block and moisture to the knee
doesn't dry out
and and and help them find
together cell serving two purposes gonna
make this
with that Grammy here other than
at a table 13 so I thought further and
sound have fair white pepper but black
pepper
had 31 a little bit by fear hello there
salt of anatole another thought to be
national here
of that moisture out but the little bit
both of and at a little quicker
man guitar meet next Sat and add that to
the skillet
of I'll we're just gonna start around
break than the other much as you can
and eventually it'll kinda come into
really really
tiny little crumble so
keep an eye on now and
have Abril while you're waiting because
nothing goes with enrollment fee right
because I have
water but hey look scottie like I'm
saving Kalyanaraman beers that I can
have more
fried a world leader beautiful okay just
a few minutes later it looks like this
in turn the heat off
and you just wanna make sure that any
big chunks in me
are sorta broken out you want really a
very find
filling for these egg rolls then
no transfer to a plate is a baking sheet
or something
we just wanna spread it out so that it
cools off
faster there's any oil left in about a
mere pan you can
try to like keep that behind millions
that
cook the cabbage also okay about aside
and then back in the same skillet
had a tiny and more oil
animal add that cabbage so this is a
shredded napa cabbage artist's life that
really really finally
you can use a regular old green cabbage
too and that'll give you
more sort of texture and find your egg
roll and that's more common in
restaurants pet and am I had napa
cabbage
using cabbage either one fucking you can
also add like bean sprout from things
like that
so we're just gonna stock hey there
until the cabbage is well to it
shouldn't take very long at all
okay so cavett getting
nice and well said you don't want to get
to thought of the UN keep a low and
texture and it'll will continue to curb
even after you turn the heat off for
this looks pretty get the
sleepy part sir presence of but that any
parts are so little crispy
them in turn on/off and I had a fam
water chestnuts and this is just like
these you'd like
at Canon water chestnut but I drained
and
min finally and then I must have an
absolute mushrooms in either
and dried she talkin mushrooms that I
just had soaking in water
for about an hour and Outwood ear
mushrooms I like this black ones that
are really firm
are also commonly used an egg rolls
either a little bit easier to find
usually cell squeeze the water out
and minerals that meant that these
measures
tip
and then finally to the a man at a table
spoon
have regular all-purpose flour and mix
that and and that's just gonna help the
filling
pants taken a firm as it cools little
taken an absolute alternate make an ass
I'm Matthew can
formed a little girl up
gonna spread this out on top a the meet
met
up analyst
put this whole thing in the fridge and
when it get super chilled you can make
the filling and they had a tiny even two
days ahead of time
which is really excellent a when you've
had a lot have
for is okay time to roll these mofos
and this is just gonna happen next year
its
cool lopped how Italy these are my egg
roll wrappers so these you can find
these in the frozen section usually
have pretty much any major grocery store
and you just want to father up
and then and keep the rest of them
covered while you're rolling them so
they don't dry out
that dries out pretty quickly smashed to
hear
cad dement they stick together
stick together like a Hiddink letter B
grower rappers are the best defense
K clam out on guys state and
day I tuned just getting event so
you wanna get a big spoon falling be
like quarter cup or so
your mixture pretty much right in the
center maybe a little bit
below the center but pretty much just
right on Bros an eerie and
role bottom at and what I like to do can
take it over
and then pull it back to DC I didn't
think
so that it gets a nice little tight log
fold this site over for that fight over
man and the form below I've got just to
make sure have
play not flour and water and
about equal parts maybe a little bit
more water it's not
important really am just use your
finger to go or
I liked it exhorted kit the sides here
like that in the lab science and then a
little
points also this is gonna come to glue
it together
and then just roll it over like
that just like that make sure that you
have enough and that little tidbit air
Mary S an arrest other side seam side
down on a plate
you can make these make him unlike
let him step really Tanner 15 minutes
top
but eventually and pretty quickly the
feeling
the liquid in the filling in oil in
Philly is going to soak the wrappers to
you
you can't really make them like really
ahead of time but like I said you can
make the Philly ahead a time
and then just roll up a few and then as
your frying the first batch you or
someone else
ideally you have a little helper a
little kitchen of
well the rolling the next batch so it's
kinda fun thing to do if you had like
friends like to cut to have them over
and
let's all make eggrolls together to make
different fillings you could put shrimp
venom
or you could make vegetarian one
you could put carrots in am
you could pit whatever in an can
tomorrow about fixing these
well I start heating up my oil on S&P no
oil in the skillet
and just and three-quarters of an inch
or so and took
there about three sixty-five degrees
Fahrenheit
kitchen the flip said way there we go
calamander Prince Charles around 365
doing carefully
fry and growth in small batches
for at 12 minutes on each side until
golden brown
our top 10
careful not friend to many at once
because the temperature will drop when
you in a bit greasy and growth
and you of the runner-up overflowing
well
training and rolled highlighted
ball the mine Italian order
appraised so that the ECB welcomed
rip-off
actually day on its way ever learn
what time is it it n roll time what time
is it
it time for egg rolls those don't rhyme
so I've got here stan
Aurion tall hot mustard powder
you can finest in space areas Daisy
could be in such a bitch and that you
did mix up the powder with water to the
desired consistency
I like mine a little bit and so that's
good bird
dampen and that also that Sam sweet
chili sauce
so if you like this egg roll recipe also
took out my channel china's foreign and
delicious fried treat with a Mexican
twist
and also did fresh spring rolls recipe
and
couple years ago there our pride we help
here
and on both with that
skid taste like this happen third
gonna clear out my allergies
all was a fine question ever of
nato I hope you like this arrest you
have to get a shot
if you want printable recipe they are
always available at looking at home
and that's also the best place to reach
me and Helen important question about a
recipe
as I will be churches he does questions
and visit me on twitter facebook
Instagram
all over the place y'all only internet I
mean
had in back
when maybe once in a while
like
good catch
girl
minute
your stomach Martin clatter
I love you enough ranting