hated on Highland today I am I looking
and remaking the second rescue video I
ever did that is
fish tacos can you believe it's been a
long time 18 fish tacos any income on
this is a great start my recipe it comes
together essential nice
depression and flight so that you can
keep your Beachbody think you're right
totally worth
me some really excited to share with you
especially because that all video
sounds like totally effed up dudes pass
well
home
dampening it happen on the fish taco top
and
talk what happened was actually the old
as I can protest so I'm gonna update my
flaw a little bit at that time
green cabbage their shine it up some
white onions diced
and sound had come a so this is the
route
its kinda starches kinda a me the
texture
Robert 80 but its sweet County cap on
cam I'll
sup at add a nice
little play dirty a slot am that that an
hour
starting out for and then and since I'll
super duper simple
pasta recipe hour in a news assault
and lime juice to get it softened up to
get that
cabbage can releasing some water and
get nice and tender so either rock
runs on this raw diet thing but you know
some Robert smalls obviously are good
for you like salad
like celery sticks might care its TX
okay so that's about a teaspoon salt get
that cat tossed around
homes your ha sometimes out you can use
your hands also
nature's tongs use a bigger ball and I
didn't see you don't have to worry about
it
full of out everywhere case assaults
coating everything are going to squeeze
in some lime juice
an FU are be stricken
by Harley high land prices you can use a
lemon juice
just don't tell anyone really expected
margins from now I'm since I paid
33 cents for it hopefully
that close to took a last chance get
that tossed around
toss that salad okay and then an awsome
lamp or fresh coriander
a few are British and I don't bother
pulling off the stems first launcher I
just
chop it up really really find is a lot
of labor in the stands actually
so you can see why don't you can see but
I can see with my life by
at the cabin has already started to
soften up just that little bit and
motion in the ocean summers gonna set
this aside and work on some
other staff and just leave it at room
temperature and how she looks like when
we're done
your BM a test oh my god to be like wow
you're a genius okay for the man as fast
as I can and day and got Sam
man is here I'm going to add some
minced chocolate wrappers so to pull a
intentarlo
they can animal can it's like a dollar
and if the ins and overstock that's
kinda sweetie and
slightly then agree that mostly sweet
and hot
they're smoked jalapeno peppers in an
airport in this
do it fast so whenever I get ajar home
I like to transfer and milk and how much
transfer into a jarring keep in the
fridge in are still intact for
so they're pretty spicy
nice start with have one and just
men sit up and that pretty much just
turned into a paste as you meant sing at
you know a and risk and holler access
pass a
all messed up it's about table stand
chipotle in adobo
plot that innocent man is lick your
finger
cuz who cares I'm like cooking for
myself and this guy doesn't give a shit
okay mad them engines
so many tables women that synth Sol
and a man at a little bit a malt vinegar
which is really really good on fried
fish an
are now
klansmen agreements can have ninety in
sweet anyway if you can't find this then
you can use at smile and use its
scalable tartness but also
kinda nice cuz the whole fish connection
then we're going to mix this up so the
sourness and that an internal and you
should balance out the heat and it's
appalling pretty well
but if it's still a little bit too spicy
for you know I would recommend that you
had a little bit of honey or sugar
and to sorta temper that heat a little
bit but
those tests pretty good to me comes up
though on the set aside and start
working on the fish so I have changed
anything from the original recipe
as far as the seasonings and spices and
putting on it so
the two main things here our son human
seeds and sound an ass
this is not star anise just aniseed
and its kinda liquor she finally flavor
if you can't find that you can leave it
out but it does get really really nicely
with this
finance a whole came and seen said those
here
and Sam chili powder and when I sichuan
patter
me personally I just mean like ground-up
enter chile's ground at New Mexico Chile
I don't mean
like commercial brand Chile para has
garlic salt in our stuff mixed into
other that's what you can find and
that's what you have in your pantry that
AZT
holy totally fine please re-up
tomato mourner and pesto you can use pre
ground spices if you want that
you know me Alex me things harmonies of
super whole spices and and crushing map
can nah my chili powder
are any ground thing
and salt and pepper
cuz to what's life without salt and
pepper
you wouldn't have that song push it for
one thing
next I'll okay now for that reading
reading
heart reading writing weirdo
I'm just using some corn you know if you
are in another country
not the best country in the world
America
can inked I
if you are in another country and you
don't have crime you know anything is
fine plant
basically the same thing that would add
this too thats
an extra renowned it combined
now all we're going to the fish I did
the fish last so that I don't have to
wash my cutting board
between acting like a rock fish jus
on things she mmm
I'm using them while snapper
but you is pretty much any like light
ish fishermen you probably could use
salmon or something like that here
field catfish like and I asked that
fishmonger if you would scan it for me
so
these are skinless and boneless so I'm
just gonna cut them into pieces
maybe an inch wide by however long it is
so that usually ends up being about the
race has to go into attack a
sheer fish channa you're just gonna toss
around
and this cornmeal mixture just to cut it
we don't really need anything
to help here the crime you understand
moisture from the fish
well keep it on their moist sheesh
and you can do this fish coating part
had it I'm goin discover I'm leaving the
French
and after a couple hours and that'll
help that coating
stick on better to him you can leave
them set for a while
okay so officials are coded was gonna
but it's it here
in my little dash for just as long it
takes to heat up a skillet with some oil
in it and then we'll get to fry and the
fish
fish wrap I day I C one here can have
over comedienne I medium-high heat
and then and me 2 tablespoons a canola
oil or corn oil peanut oil something
kinda neutral
the high smoke point
so while around like a lava lamp
down behind get distracted and then you
want to cook your fish
in two matches cut the smaller pieces
with the smaller pieces in the bigger on
Saturday Iran's
and when you land in the hot oil Kali it
away from you just in case
see you know splatter heil on your
beautiful face Jesus
we sell there so therefore we just take
two to three minutes on each side I S
with speaker foley's like
the snapper you might need to do more
than just to size
go ahead and get side
of
something nice and brown on every side
weekend
taken now when you break one open and
fashion the
flaky like hats
these are super hot right now so I'm
cool off for a few minutes and while
it's happening we can hear by tortillas
fishes
way personnel that honor
right to pull away
mayo sauce so if you're interested be
sure to check out the original
fish typo video for some really whole
areas
fish taco jokes and and also make sure
to check out by looking at home for this
printable recipe and
all rescue and if you make this clear
time me on Instagram Twitter and send me
a picture
I love to see that and alright look at
that
gorgeous colorful mmm
hmm I did it again you're welcome
running in writing have a great day
when on
idk Corp