%uh
on
are on
on be hi
that nearly every but copycat dot com
don't you just love Cracker Barrel
fried apples but guess what finish show
you how to make
cracker pearls be the pride of old at
home in your own kitchen
right I'm just finishing chopping up my
Apple doesn't make this recipe with
about five or even six a wholesome
my recipe calls for either fighter or
they can make your pain
now the Cracker Barrel doesn't use
om thank you for being and their Aquino
what
is really good with bacon drippings and
that's my grandma used to do it
self my mom I think testified that that
make them
very very specific this recipe have a
few ingredients that
about five or six tart apple are
from brown sugar all little but not mad
from sediment and lemon juice so happy
finished lightening up all her holes
you want to keep lights pretty color
so we're going to add just a little bit
let me just say this: and give it a stir
before we take the cover to the so
and start cooking are fried apple okay
three it started our apples were gonna
take our butter and milk Latin Obama
skillet
again you can go ahead and you've bacon
drippings
if you happen to have bacon drippings it
is this a good
know what that better get nice and not
good
one and Mexican admiral Apple
I'm just gonna present evenly on the
bond with my skillet I'm cooking me
on 8 medium heat not be high and not to
let
I am using an all-clad still here but
you know what
i've seen many faiths Youth Parliament
months the skillet though I think any
skill that will really do
in fact a man I really feel it would be
great for the for the wall
RA my butter is all night and melted
right now I'm in the Apple just
beginning to relief from their
juices though now we're gonna sprinkle
n are brown sugar mine
so we've added her brown sugar its just
beginning to melt
on I'm going to add and mines
cinnamon
and I'm going at it in a little bit not
make one
came ends canister
to incorporate mine
these mall just incredible now this
butter and brown sugar
is going to make a really nice 60
that these apples will cry
in terrible modern it's going to take
about 15-20 minutes for the thing shot
but we'll come back from there all night
long RA
there were about halfway Kokinis Apple
you can see we have the
wonderful that there a break here so
while you're cooking just be sure to
star in every couple met him
you're gonna happen fabulous fried apple
so now you know how to make
Cracker Barrel pride Apple you know why
I thought what's more great recipes
online at copycat that cock and if
you're watching a video on youtube
be sure the Laker did the video some up
and let me know what recipe you'd like
to be met give her my Apple
and you can see miss a wonderful creamy
therapy and of it is all over the
thoughtful there might be
saw now in communities
just great premiums went to trial on
men boba my
I'm that mean the Amlin IQ ever wondered
how your favorite restaurant big head
bash like that for
I put together a ver 1500 rapid behave
just like they do in the abstract
copycat dot com and pine resin
from the Olive Garden Outback Steakhouse
the Cracker Barrel and
so much more that the hahaha mom and
have a recipe that that
the Olive Garden alfredo sauce olive
garden salad got me
abhorrence pride at all you tried in the
restaurant
now make it at home