thank you for joining me here on copycat
recipes today and to show you how to
make cracker barrel chicken tenders hero
really easy to make in the committees
just like you do in the restaurant
they have just four simple ingredients
and their let me tell you what's in them
we're gonna have chicken tenders in here
now if you don't have to contenders
you can use upon the skin of press to
cut it up
into stricter about one inch
why in those would be perfect
organi effect howling in drafting
any brand will tail ironically don't
spend a lot of math despite whatever and
say oh it's gonna be great
ralph opinions a little bit of honey
and a couple of line for a little bit of
features that
we're going to make that the marinate
printing marinated chicken tenders for
about an hour
they were going to cut them cannot be
perfect imitates just like they do in
the restaurant
they were really begin by making the
marinate and this is really really easy
to do
you are going to take
one-line and fight for it
immersed in a go-ahead it's clean the
line into our container
now i a m mixing my married and thinking
tenor
that i'm getting married chicken and
that way i can say that dash
to be on the lookout for a_b_c_'s just
in case if they come in
period at a table stand
a honey
then you need about half a bottle uh...
italian dressing though this is a
sixteen ounce bottle
three did not happen that's for the
merit
battalion jesse you can marinate
anything in it
vegetables stay
all kinds of fat
parents and again i think with all stars
and in the simply put my chicken in here
now i have an account of chicken here if
you have a little bit more that'll be
fine
doubt work in america checking out
marinade only works for the first time
dot after we finished cooking the
chicken you need to discard the married
and don't use it again
tyranny of the cyclical shake put this
in the french democratic comeback in an
hour
richard you that
great article is the mayor knitting for
just about an hour and a friend and i
think a kit
not just in a regular fillets in nine
wired on spell it
optimistic a little bit of oil in the
bottom of the pan
indian olive oil taxable oil that really
doesn't matter
about meanwhile episcopal more
and remember verbally come simplistic
and urinate don't use it again it's for
a one time only
you see it smells of really good rate
now he will begin cooking it
just a second
okay thirty million cooking the chicken
are tentative hotmail
that you're just gonna shake off
the myriad here
it just drop it in the pan
you're gonna need to put these on a
needy m
medium-high heat for a couple of minutes
on each side
k_k_k_ anytime it off
right now that i am you put all the
chicken and it can be democratic money
give it a little bit of faith
that took place in the evening late
featured discarded
the poor kitty is going to marry it and
get another one
we don't want to prom
significant anything out something for
for here
music again to take that to three
minutes and each side and we have
perfectly cooked
cracker barrel chicken tenders
dig in and out of the chicken is very
different
youth a new look on the friday that the
ticking of fee that it's starting to
turn white
tupelohall you know that the chicken
actually cooking
no one likes rocks again
so go ahead and and make sure your
tickets booked thoroughly
the mexican not yet ready to turn over
just yet from the put it back down
and wait another minute i fell in
phoenix in brown
into cigarettes just starting a
brand-new safely go ahead and flatbed
okay you can see the sick and is
wonderfully browns now
freely go ahead and take it out of the
ten years
if that is a great on fallon is my tooth
went ahead and make them off
threat on a plate with a couple vessels
and have dinner
it didn't take
too long at all
u_k_ marybeth before you leave from
margaret and then i put forth a little
extra flavor
your ego an art form wonderful
background to contender
the weekend made a cracker barrel role
to contender and really you think that
for agreement
so please be sure to subscribe to this
channel and breaks this video and
comment in the box below
and think what you'd like to think that