this is Stephanie manly with copycat dot
com
I'm gonna show you how you can make at
baked potato that's just like the
Outback Steakhouse
without a wonderful salty crust on the
outside I'm
from let's get started and solve this
mystery we're gonna start out with baked
potatoes
now use as many as you like now I'm
using some that are roughly the size of
my hand I'm guessing that's about a
half-pound
you're going to need some kosher salt
which you can buy it a regular grocery
store
I'm he haven't read it is a great
ingredient
on to use for salt them what the flavor
and for good news a vegetable oil
it doesn't matter you can you lose
just vegetable oil sunflower safflower
arm
corn oil I would stay away from olive
oil in peanut oil
simply because they think they can add a
little extra flavor
that I'm not quite looking for here they
don't need the pure sure baked potato
with the four
or in ninety for anything you're just
going to
arm Dept a paper towel
into a small container and as rob the
hall potato down
with oil you and number two in this
those so the salt crust will stick on it
arm in this does another thing as well
he keeps patino nice in light in fluffy
in the inside because we're not losing
any arm other potatoes National Water
so would really works out well so by now
you preheat your oven about 350 degrees
in its heating away and getting ready
for us
and the next thing gonna do use words
can sprinkle on some salt
now we're not corrupt isn't Boyle
because this could knock off a little
bit at the Salt
arm so that's it we're just gonna
sprinkle it was thought they were gonna
pop it in a 350 degree oven
I'm going to bake these until they're
done
in for me that takes about an hour so
probably close to an hour for you as
well
to go ahead put these in the oven and
then take them back out
let him cool for a little bit armpit you
can see
the salty crossed has remade in these
are wonderful
light and fluffy on the inside so I
wanna show you what the folks up
like a little bit closer how fabulous is
that
that perfect and um I love
the underside because the brown just a
little bit a little bit crispy on the
bottom
I don't think there's a anything much
better than that um
so here we go here's our paper tale I'm
gonna go ahead
and cut the soap and you can see again
this fall
stays right on the top to make it so
delicious
now i dnt go ahead and prepare this big
potato
now of course it still screaming hot so
use it how these something other than
your fingers at this point because
burning your stop for dinner is never
never find so what comes next well
of course we're going to topper pay
potato with the
favorite ingredients for choice home and
the butter and sour cream kinda girl
home but as you can see these are really
really easy to do you just need 8 big
potato
you need um alleged
oil again your choice is fine in some
kosher salt that's than
you know like the potato the
non-negotiable ingredient and
arm we can debate the easy take about an
hour in 3 MPT decree Evan
and that's it how wonderful is that so
here we go
were tapping our paper tale with a
little bit o
butter am sour cream in China's
in math how you can make a baked potato
just like they do at the Outback
Steakhouse
you you
don't forget to subscribe to the you can
also
you can see more copycat recipe if