[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="1" title="Breakfast Enchiladas! |  Hilah Cooking " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oFUG9ESBhr0" mode="non-automatic">
Hey, dudes.<s>
I'm Hilah, and today on Hilah Cooking, we're making <entity type="Recipe">breakfast enchiladas</entity> filled with <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo</entity>, topped with fried <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> with a homemade <entity type="Ingredient">chili sauce</entity>.<s>
These are going to go great with all of your breakfast margaritas.<s>
Alright.<s>
Numero uno.<s>
That means number one in Spanish.<s>
We're going to make our <entity type="Ingredient">chili sauce</entity>.<s>
So, I've got here <entity type="Amount">a couple</entity> of dried <entity type="Ingredient">pasilla chilies</entity>.<s>
They're pretty sweet and tasty and delicious.<s>
I'm just going to break the stems off.<s>
I've already given them a little rinse, just to get any dust or pesticide residue or anything like that off of them, since they're not organic.<s>
Sorry, Jesus.<s>
I'm going to add about <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> or maybe a little more.<s>
All we're going to do is bring this to a boil.<s>
When it boils, I'm going to turn the heat off and just let it sit for about ten minutes to get reconstituted.<s>
So, I'm actually going to move this to this back burner while that happens.<s>
Do a little magic switcharoo here and work on numero two.<s>
This totally looks like a number two here.<s>
Alright.<s>
What this is is not a turd.<s>
It's some <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo sausage</entity>, some fresh Mexican <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo sausage</entity>.<s>
I'm just going to cook this over sort of a medium-high heat, until it's cooked through and in really fine crumbles.<s>
You could totally leave this out.<s>
I've made these vegetarian before, and they're just delicious.<s>
But I had some <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo</entity>, so I'm going to add it.<s>
[music].<s>
Once most of the fat has released, you can be pretty sure that it's almost cooked.<s>
So, I'm going to add some diced <entity type="Ingredient">onion</entity>.<s>
We just want to soften this a little bit.<s>
I still want to keep some of the crunch integrity of the <entity type="Ingredient">onion</entity>, but maybe not like fully raw <entity type="Ingredient">onions</entity>.<s>
Although, you totally could.<s>
It's also fine that way.<s>
This is a very flexible recipe, as long as you have the <entity type="Ingredient">chili sauce</entity> and the <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity>, and even, you could totally just buy <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">can</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">enchilada sauce</entity> and make <entity type="Recipe">enchiladas</entity> and serve them for breakfast with <entity type="Amount">an</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">egg</entity> on top.<s>
I don't give two shits.<s>
Okay.<s>
So, our <entity type="Amount">water</entity> on the chilies is boiling.<s>
That's great.<s>
I'm going to drop in <entity type="Amount">a couple</entity> <entity type="Unit">cloves</entity> of raw <entity type="Ingredient">garlic</entity>, just like that.<s>
Bloop.<s>
Put the lid back on it.<s>
Turn it off and just let it sit there for ten minutes to get softened up.<s>
Okay.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Onions</entity> are getting just barely translucent.<s>
Go ahead and turn the heat off.<s>
I've got <entity type="Amount">two</entity> red <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity> here that I boiled a couple days ago, and then peeled and just cut into pretty big cubes.<s>
And then, I'm also going to add some <entity type="Ingredient">baby spinach</entity>.<s>
Tear it up a little bit.<s>
Ew.<s>
Gross.<s>
I want my money back.<s>
But like I said, yeah, this is totally still a hearty meal if you leave the <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo</entity> out.<s>
The meat is not integral.<s>
I don't know.<s>
Take it out.<s>
It's not necessary for the recipe to work.<s>
Just a little extra bonus, because <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo</entity> is the new bacon, y'all.<s>
I just declared that for 2014.<s>
Pass it on.<s>
Just going to mash up those <entity type="Ingredient">potato</entity> chunks a little bit to help this filling stick together.<s>
That's just going to make it easier to roll up.<s>
Okay.<s>
Them the last thing I'm going to add to the filling is some crumbled up <entity type="Ingredient">cotija cheese</entity>.<s>
This is a Mexican cheese.<s>
It's very firm and salty, kind of reminds me of a merman's dick because it's firm and salty.<s>
Okay.<s>
Anyway, I'm just imagining that merman have perpetual boners.<s>
But anyway, just <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of this, maybe <entity type="Amount">an</entity> <entity type="Unit">ounce</entity> or so.<s>
Just add a nice saltiness.<s>
So, we're not adding any other salt to this because between the <entity type="Ingredient">chorizo</entity> and the <entity type="Ingredient">cotija</entity>, we've got it made.<s>
But if you were leaving either one of those out, you probably want to add <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity>.<s>
Mix that around.<s>
And this is not a melting cheese.<s>
It stays in chunks, and they just kind of get soft.<s>
So, it adds a nice little textural bite in there, a little chewy cheese curd kind of feel.<s>
You could use other types of <entity type="Ingredient">cheese</entity> too.<s>
Just going to pull them out by the tips.<s>
Pull it out by the tip and let all the seeds drop out.<s>
You could leave them in if you wanted a really spicy sauce, but I don't know.<s>
To me, this doesn't really need to be like super hot.<s>
These <entity type="Ingredient">peppers</entity> have a really nice fruity flavor.<s>
And the little <entity type="Ingredient">garlic cloves</entity> that I dropped in.<s>
So, they'll still have a little bit of a rawness to them, but they're not going to be so sharp and spicy.<s>
So, I'm going to add, to start with, about <entity type="Amount">a half</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of this soaking liquid.<s>
That's why I rinsed these <entity type="Ingredient">peppers</entity> off first, because you want to be able to use this liquid, but not if it's full of weird gross shit, just jizz it around.<s>
Important safety note.<s>
When you're blending hot things in a blender, pressure builds up, and the lid can blow off.<s>
So, make sure that you allow it to like vent, just by sort of leaving a little thing like that.<s>
Or if you don't have like a little cap, you can just cover the blender with like a towel or something, doubled up, so you don't splatter your hand with hot liquid.<s>
Okay.<s>
Safety lesson over.<s>
Whoa, guys.<s>
That was loud.<s>
Okay.<s>
I'm going to check the consistency.<s>
Alright, that looks pretty good.<s>
Smells delicioso.<s>
I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity>, maybe <entity type="Amount">a quarter</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> or so.<s>
That's it.<s>
Our sauce is done.<s>
So, we can get rid of this.<s>
Magically, it goes over there.<s>
And then, for the <entity type="Recipe">enchilada</entity> part, I've got some <entity type="Ingredient">corn tortillas</entity>.<s>
Typically, or traditionally, they're sort of like warmed up and softened in some warm <entity type="Ingredient">oil</entity> before you roll the <entity type="Recipe">enchiladas</entity>.<s>
I have a cheer white girl method, and I'm just going to actually spray them with <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">spray oil</entity>.<s>
Boop.<s>
Boop.<s>
Boop.<s>
Boop.<s>
Boop.<s>
Boop.<s>
Then, stick them in the microwave for about 30 seconds, and you will see how beautifully pliable they become.<s>
Okay.<s>
See?<s>
These are nice and hot and soft.<s>
Your mileage may vary.<s>
You might need to put them in for a little bit longer, 60 seconds or so.<s>
But, looks good to me.<s>
So, we're going to put a little bit of our sauce down here.<s>
And then, you just want to dredge each <entity type="Ingredient">tortilla</entity> in a little bit of this sauce.<s>
It's going to be a little bit messy.<s>
Don't wear your best shirt.<s>
<entity type="Amount">Couple</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity> of your filling.<s>
And then, shove it on back.<s>
A lot of times when I'm just making these for Chris and I, I'll just do like a half batch, and I won't even bother heating up in the oven.<s>
I'll just do it on a plate and like, microwave them or something.<s>
So, this last one, you've got to do a little maneuvering, a little Houdini-ing to get it covered, but you can do it.<s>
I promise you'll manage.<s>
Alright.<s>
Muy bien.<s>
Now, I'm just going to pour the rest of the sauce over the top.<s>
Well, maybe save a little bit back because it looks really pretty when you top it with <entity type="Ingredient">egg</entity>.<s>
You can add a little bit more sauce on top of the egg too.<s>
Okay.<s>
Gorgeous.<s>
Alright.<s>
I'm going to put this in the oven, really just until I have some <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> fried or poached or however you want to do them.<s>
Bonus video recipe tip.<s>
How to fry an <entity type="Ingredient">egg</entity> in a cast iron skillet.<s>
You have to use <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity>.<s>
Do not screw around with <entity type="Ingredient">oil</entity> and frying <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> in a cast iron skillet.<s>
I have no idea why it doesn't work, but it doesn't work.<s>
You have to use <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity>.<s>
I'm sure I'm going to get a million comments telling me I'm totally wrong, but in my kitchen, I have to use <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity>, or the <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> just stick, and they make a huge mess.<s>
I'm heating this up over pretty high heat.<s>
I'm going to let this <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity> kind of -- It'll get a little foamy, and then the foam will subside.<s>
Don't let me down, <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity>.<s>
Do what I said that you'll do.<s>
Okay.<s>
I think that's hot enough.<s>
It's sort of popping and stuff.<s>
It's maybe almost about to turn brown.<s>
That's good.<s>
So, if you put it in, and it starts popping like that, that's good.<s>
It means you're probably not going to have your <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> stick to the pan.<s>
It also means you're probably going to get some little crusty brown bits, which I personally like.<s>
But if you don't, then you might want to try poaching your <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> or not using a cast iron skillet.<s>
Just kind of shimmy it.<s>
The handle will get hot, eventually, if you're frying <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">bunch</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity>.<s>
So, don't have to be like me and be all stupid.<s>
Turn the heat down if it's popping too much.<s>
So, it looks good.<s>
The bottom's all set, white.<s>
Get it moving like this, and then boop, like that.<s>
Turn the heat off immediately, because that residual heat is going to keep cooking it.<s>
So, it's not like totally done while I get my <entity type="Recipe">enchiladas</entity> out of the oven.<s>
Alright.<s>
<entity type="Recipe">Enchiladas</entity> are done.<s>
Oops.<s>
I scrunched it, but that's OK.<s>
It's going to taste awesome.<s>
Then, I'm going to cover it with a, hopefully, still runny <entity type="Ingredient">egg</entity>.<s>
Come on.<s>
I'll just do that.<s>
Perfect.<s>
Okay.<s>
There you go.<s>
<entity type="Recipe">Breakfast enchiladas.</entity><s>
I cannot wait to dig in.<s>
I have many other <entity type="Recipe">enchilada</entity> recipes on my website and videos.<s>
And also, check out my breakfast playlist, if you are so inclined.<s>
Let's just go ahead and see if the egg yolk is still runny.<s>
Hey.<s>
It's not runny, exactly, but it's moist.<s>
Why does that word gross everyone out so much?<s>
Okay.<s>
Get all this good stuff.<s>
I'm just going to take a big old honking bite.<s>
God damn it.<s>
If I can.<s>
Fork.<s>
My fork is traitor-ing me.<s>
That is what I'm talking about.<s>
This is what I want for breakfast if I ever come to stay at your house, like impromptu like bed and breakfast session.<s>
This is what I want you to make me.<s>
Okay?<s>
Thanks.<s>
Thanks for watching.<s>
Please subscribe if you haven't already.<s>
Check out Hilah Cooking for printable recipes, and I'll see you guys next time.<s>
Bye.<s>
Hey.<s>
What's a crab's favorite Mexican food?<s>
Pinch-a-lot-as.<s>
Get it?<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>