[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="15" title="Healthy Recipes- Easy 10 Minute Chicken Tacos " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DXSqkdBsm4o" mode="non-automatic">
[music] [music] Hi, I'm Christine Avanti, celebrity nutritionist and chef.<s>
Today I'm going to be teaching you how to make my world-famous <entity type="Recipe">10-minute tacos</entity>.<s>
But before I get started, I just want to give you a rundown on what the ingredients are.<s>
So very simple, we're starting out with <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">grilled chicken breast</entity>, okay?<s>
I'm going to be topping my <entity type="Recipe">tacos</entity> with <entity type="Amount">some</entity> shredded <entity type="Ingredient">lettuce</entity>, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salsa</entity>.<s>
I'm gonna use <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">black beans</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">low-fat shredded cheese</entity> and just as a side, I've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">brown rice</entity>, okay?<s>
We also are using <entity type="Ingredient">white corn tortillas</entity>.<s>
I love these guys.<s>
I'm gonna garnish with <entity type="Amount">some</entity> fresh <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity> and <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">cilantro</entity>.<s>
Mmm, so good, I love it.<s>
And <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity>, a right?<s>
Are you guys ready?<s>
I'm hungry so I'm gonna get started.<s>
All right, so we're gonna start with <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">olive oil</entity>, just <entity type="Amount">a</entity> teeny <entity type="Unit">bit</entity>, just for some cooking, get that <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> cooked up.<s>
I've got my pan on medium high.<s>
Just gonna let that heat up for a second.<s>
Every good chef loves to season with <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">pepper</entity>, and I know people are afraid of <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity> but I'm not afraid of <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity>.<s>
I eat healthy all the time.<s>
I exercise a lot so <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity> is not going to kill me or my clients.<s>
If you have high blood pressure, then that's a different story.<s>
So we've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity> in there always gonna go with the base, fresh-cracked <entity type="Ingredient">pepper</entity>.<s>
This <entity type="Ingredient">chicken breast</entity>--see, my husband seems to like this and guys really like this.<s>
This is pre-made, store-bought, cut up <entity type="Ingredient">chicken breast</entity>.<s>
I'm not the hugest fan of that but if you're in a hurry, it's good just to buy <entity type="Ingredient">chicken breast</entity> already cut up and made.<s>
You can buy it at the grocery store, Trader Joe's, wherever.<s>
So I'm gonna put my <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> in here.<s>
It's about <entity type="Amount">4</entity> <entity type="Unit">ounces</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">chicken breast</entity>.<s>
Okay.<s>
That's <entity type="Amount">4</entity> <entity type="Unit">ounces</entity>.<s>
Let me wash my hand really quick.<s>
I'm sorry, guys, but you can't cross contaminate.<s>
Sorry.<s>
So when you touch meat, you always want to wash your hands with hot, soapy water because cross contamination can be a problem in the kitchen.<s>
I'm gonna season.<s>
Instead of using the packet of taco seasoning that's high in sodium and preservatives, I'm gonna use some fresh spices, just <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">paprika</entity>, just sprinkling.<s>
You don't have to get out a measuring spoon.<s>
This is <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">chili powder</entity> and it's gonna start to smoke, which I love.<s>
<entity type="Amount">Some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">cayenne pepper</entity>, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> crushed <entity type="Ingredient">red pepper</entity> and <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cumin</entity>.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Cumin</entity> is a spice that you will see a lot in Spanish and Latin cooking.<s>
We're smoking, whoo, hoo, hoo.<s>
Okay.<s>
Literally because this is pre-made <entity type="Ingredient">chicken breast</entity>, I'm just gonna look it for just like a minute, just to get the spices on it.<s>
And also when you heat a spice, that lets the flavor release so kind of fun, kind of cool.<s>
Smells good.<s>
And I think that this <entity type="Ingredient">chicken breast</entity> looks prettier with the spices on it.<s>
All right, so I'm turning off my heat.<s>
I'm moving my pan over.<s>
Let that cool off.<s>
The spices are making me cough.<s>
I'm sorry.<s>
It's how it happens.<s>
Now, what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna get my <entity type="Ingredient">tortillas</entity> ready.<s>
Now if you have a gas range at home, you just turn on your heat, kind of to low, throw the <entity type="Ingredient">tortilla</entity> right over it.<s>
You don't spray, you don't do anything.<s>
Just put the <entity type="Ingredient">tortilla</entity> right over it.<s>
If you don't have a gas stove at home and you have an electric stove, that little like coil-looking thing, heating element, as they call it, you can put it on that too, medium high, just make sure that it's clean and it's not like coated with like sticky like Cream of Wheat from yesterday or something.<s>
And you just leave it on there and then I hope every healthy cook at home as a set of tongs because if you don't, you need to go by some.<s>
They're like a dollar at Target, okay?<s>
Go get yourself some tongs because you're gonna use those to flip over your <entity type="Ingredient">tortillas</entity>.<s>
You use them for a lot of things, but for this meal, it's for <entity type="Ingredient">tortillas</entity>.<s>
Just get some fire on the--look at how pretty that is.<s>
Just like a Martha Stewart photo at the end of the day when I'm done with these.<s>
We'll make them so pretty that Martha will be proud.<s>
Okay, they're almost done.<s>
And you know what?<s>
If you don't have--if you don't feel like heating them on your heating element, on your stove, on your gas range, you can always just microwave them.<s>
I'm not a big fan of the microwave but last case scenario--worst case scenario, go ahead and throw them on there.<s>
This one looks like it's literally on fire, which is fine.<s>
Okay, so I'm turning all the burners off.<s>
And I'm going to very quickly cut up my <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity> 'cause that's gonna go into my <entity type="Recipe">taco</entity>.<s>
And I just want to cut <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity> 'cause we want <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">lime juice</entity> once we're ready to build the <entity type="Recipe">taco</entity> here.<s>
And then I'm just gonna cut <entity type="Amount">a</entity> tiny <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cilantro</entity>.<s>
Chop it up real quick so we've got that.<s>
Now, these tacos, it's not super hot.<s>
I can hold it with my hand.<s>
It's no big deal.<s>
I'm gonna take my <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity>--look at this <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity>.<s>
It's gorgeous, a lot better-looking than that <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> I had before, right?<s>
Put it in there.<s>
Okay, it's a little hot.<s>
Ow.<s>
Okay, cool off, cool off, cool off.<s>
I'm gonna put <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of--I'll put <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">rice</entity> in here.<s>
I'm put <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">black beans</entity>.<s>
It's kind of hot.<s>
Hold on, you guys.<s>
Wow.<s>
I think I might have grabbed it too soon.<s>
Okay, so mental note, don't grab the <entity type="Ingredient">tortillas</entity> straight off of the stove, give it a second to cool off.<s>
I mean I'm not completely burning to where I need to go to the emergency room but I'm burnt.<s>
It hurts.<s>
Okay, so there I'm gonna put <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of fresh <entity type="Ingredient">lettuce</entity>.<s>
I'm gonna put <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of fresh <entity type="Ingredient">cheese</entity>.<s>
How pretty is that?<s>
There's one <entity type="Recipe">taco</entity>.<s>
I wasn't lying when I said 10 minutes, kids.<s>
Ten minutes.<s>
Okay, put this bad boy on here.<s>
More of my--hey, Mr. <entity type="Ingredient">Avocado</entity>, I know you wanted to go for a ride, but I'll use you in a minute.<s>
Okay, more chicken.<s>
Again, look at this <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> compared to straight from the store, okay?<s>
We got some quick here.<s>
We kicked it up a notch.<s>
Thanks, Emeril.<s>
Okay, and I just touched <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity>.<s>
All right, sorry.<s>
Washing my hands.<s>
Okay, <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">rice</entity>, <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">black beans</entity>.<s>
It's not a ton, but, you know, it's enough.<s>
Some people like their <entity type="Ingredient">cheese</entity> right up against the warm parts.<s>
We can do it this one like that, put the <entity type="Ingredient">cheese</entity> right there, <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">lettuce</entity>, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity> slices.<s>
And I've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salsa</entity> as well so we can put <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salsa</entity> on there when we're done.<s>
Give it <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cilantro</entity>, little squeeze of <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity>.<s>
Simple.<s>
We'll make our last taco.<s>
This <entity type="Ingredient">tortilla</entity> was really hot so I was giving it a few minutes to cool off.<s>
I think we're there.<s>
It feels good to me.<s>
Last little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity>.<s>
If you guys don't have spices at your house, like cumin, cayenne pepper, paprika, chili powder, you should go get some because it really makes food taste good, okay?<s>
It makes food taste phenomenal and I think that we--not only do we like good-tasting food but, as humans, we eat with our eyes so we want the food to look pretty as well.<s>
And just because it's healthy, does not mean it has to look bland and not fun, okay?<s>
Little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cilantro</entity>.<s>
I'll do my <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity> again, yummy, yummy, yummy.<s>
Who wouldn't want to eat these?<s>
That's what I want to know.<s>
I'm gonna eat them.<s>
So we've got three <entity type="Recipe">tacos</entity>, little <entity type="Recipe">tacos</entity>.<s>
I mean these <entity type="Ingredient">tortillas</entity> were pretty small.<s>
They weren't that big.<s>
You get <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of extra <entity type="Ingredient">brown rice</entity> on the side for a little bit more carb.<s>
These tacos are only about 10 to 12 grams of carbohydrate per <entity type="Ingredient">tortilla</entity>, so that's why we're adding a little bit more <entity type="Ingredient">black beans</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">brown rice</entity> to it.<s>
You can put your <entity type="Ingredient">salsa</entity> there on the plate for just prettiness.<s>
And did we already give it <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity>?<s>
I'm gonna give it a little bit more <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity>.<s>
We love <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity>.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Lime</entity> definitely helps the flavor and we're gonna put some more <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity>.<s>
Here's the great thing about this meal, <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity> is loaded with what we call mono and saturated fatty acids.<s>
These mono and saturated fatty acids are good fats.<s>
They've been clinically shown in several studies, one particular a Yale study, that actually helped reduce belly fat by 33% in people who were dieting.<s>
Another study showed that mono and saturated fatty acids that come from avocado, our dear friend the avocado right there, were actually people who were eating the more of these good fats from avocado were losing more weight than other dieters that were eating the same amount of calories.<s>
So it's not only about calories in versus calories out.<s>
It's about what are your calories?<s>
Are you eating good fats?<s>
Are you eating lean proteins?<s>
Are you eating processed food?<s>
If you're gonna eat a processed meal that's 400 calories versus a meal made of real food that's 400 calories.<s>
Trust me, the real food meal is gonna help your body get filter and leaner faster than anything else.<s>
So I'm putting all my <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity> on here.<s>
Put a little bit on our <entity type="Ingredient">rice</entity>.<s>
Who says you can't have <entity type="Ingredient">avocado</entity> on <entity type="Ingredient">rice</entity>, right?<s>
Little bit more <entity type="Ingredient">black beans</entity>.<s>
I like to mix up my <entity type="Ingredient">black beans</entity> with my <entity type="Ingredient">rice</entity>.<s>
I just think it's more exciting and more fun.<s>
And here you go.<s>
You've got my <entity type="Recipe">10-minute tacos</entity>, 377 calories for this entire plate, 20 grams of protein, 50 grams of carbs.<s>
You're good to go.<s>
All right, I'm Christine Avanti.<s>
Thanks for watching me teach you how to cook and for more fun recipes and videos, check out bodybuilding.com.<s>
CC by Aberdeen Captioning 1-800-688-6621 www.abercap.com<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>