[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="17" title="Healthy Recipes- Grilled Thai Beef Salad - Bodybuilding.com " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Z2gj2cvrMk" mode="non-automatic">
Hi guys, Jillian Beck here.<s>
Welcome to my kitchen.<s>
Today I will be showing you my <entity type="Recipe">Thai beef salad</entity>.<s>
It takes about, probably 20 minute to assemble.<s>
It's super easy.<s>
It's great for summer.<s>
It's getting warmer out and I kind of tend to go with salads around this time of year, grilled proteins are excellent, the fresher, the better.<s>
So this <entity type="Recipe">Thai salad</entity> is amazing because it's got tons of herbs, a lot of favors, some grilled steak, which is always a winner in my book, and then a lot of great flavors that are very typical of Thai dishes.<s>
As you may know, I do like Asian food and flavors if you've followed any of my other recipes.<s>
I just think it's a really good way to add flavor without adding a ton of calories and fat and all that other junk that comes with like a lot of sauces and condiments that some other recipes call for.<s>
So I've kind of pre-made things here so it goes by a little quicker for you guys.<s>
I'll kind of show you what you're going to need for this recipe.<s>
First and foremost, you need <entity type="Amount">a</entity> lean <entity type="Ingredient">steak</entity>.<s>
I typically go with <entity type="Ingredient">sirloin</entity>.<s>
I'll trim the fat away from it or I'll go with <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">flank steak</entity>.<s>
So we've grilled that on the Foreman here.<s>
If you have an outdoor grill, by all means use that.<s>
In my apartment, we don't have a grill yet so I either go to my friends house to, you know, grill on the barbecue or use the Foreman.<s>
So I've gone ahead and I've grilled it to my liking, which is about medium rare.<s>
So grill it to the temperature that you prefer.<s>
And I've sliced it so about 4 ounces sliced for one salad.<s>
We've got our mixed greens here, some mixed <entity type="Ingredient">red lettuces</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">green lettuces</entity> and then we have our fresh herbs.<s>
We've got <entity type="Ingredient">basil</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">mint</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">green onion</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">cilantro</entity>.<s>
So those are the components of the salad and I'm gonna show you how to make the dressing and then we'll put it all together.<s>
So for the dressing what you're going to need is fresh <entity type="Ingredient">lime juice</entity>, which I've already gone ahead and squeezed.<s>
So we have <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity> of fresh <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity>.<s>
We're going to add <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">low-sodium soy sauce</entity>.<s>
So I'll go ahead and add that right now.<s>
Here we go.<s>
And then we're going to use <entity type="Ingredient">fish sauce</entity> and it's just a typical Asian flavor.<s>
You can find it in the Asian market in most of your grocery stores and if you can't, maybe go to like your local Asian market to find it, but it's a pretty strong flavor but it's good.<s>
It's just a little goes a long ways.<s>
So we're gonna put 2--yeah, <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoons</entity> in here along with the <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">soy</entity> and then the <entity type="Ingredient">lime juice</entity>.<s>
And then we're gonna go ahead and add <entity type="Ingredient">lemongrass</entity>.<s>
Now you can get fresh <entity type="Ingredient">lemongrass</entity> from the produce aisle and slice it and add it to the salad along with all the other herbs.<s>
My grocer didn't have that so I went ahead and got the <entity type="Ingredient">lemongrass paste</entity>.<s>
So I'll go ahead and add that as well and we'll just do about <entity type="Amount">half</entity> a <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity>, just a really small squeeze of that.<s>
And usually with Asian dressings and what not, they--you need to add like <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">sugar</entity> or <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity> or <entity type="Ingredient">agave</entity> for like the sweetness to round all the flavors out.<s>
Typically I have been using <entity type="Ingredient">Stevia</entity> in the raw so that's what I'm gonna use here today but feel free to use whatever sweetener you choose, if that's <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>, if that's <entity type="Ingredient">agave</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity>, whatever it is that you want, go ahead and add that to the dressing.<s>
For me, I like I said, I just need it a tad bit sweet and so I've been using <entity type="Ingredient">Stevia</entity> in the raw.<s>
So I'll just do like <entity type="Amount">half</entity> a <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of that as well.<s>
And then I'm gonna mix all those ingredients up for our dressing and let the <entity type="Ingredient">lemongrass</entity> dissolve a little bit.<s>
And I'm also gonna add the <entity type="Ingredient">green onions</entity> to the dressing as well to kind of soak up the flavors of that.<s>
It smells really good, really fresh.<s>
Okay, so we'll go ahead and start to plate.<s>
We'll just put the sliced <entity type="Ingredient">steak</entity> on top of the salad here.<s>
Just lay it on there.<s>
And you can actually garnish it with all these fresh herbs before you put the <entity type="Ingredient">steak</entity>, but I kind of messed that one up but it doesn't really matter 'cause you're gonna mix it all together anyways.<s>
So I'll put the <entity type="Ingredient">mint</entity> and the <entity type="Ingredient">basil</entity> and you've got your <entity type="Ingredient">steak</entity> there.<s>
And we'll go ahead and top it with the dressing.<s>
Pour it all over.<s>
And if you want a little more spice, feel free to add like <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">red chili flakes</entity> would be really good.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Chili paste</entity> would be good if you wanted to add that as well.<s>
And then we're gonna garnish it with <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cilantro</entity> on top.<s>
So there you have it.<s>
Really simple, really fresh and easy but a ton of flavor.<s>
And there you have it, my <entity type="Recipe">Thai beef steak salad</entity>.<s>
There you go.<s>
I hope you guys enjoy.<s>
Thank you so much.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>