[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="18" title="Healthy Recipes- Honey Almond Protein Crisps - Bars " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0gMPVegmz8E" mode="non-automatic">
[music] Hi, I'm Jamie Eason, and I'm in the bodybuilding.com kitchen today, and I'm excited 'cause I'm gonna show you how to make my <entity type="Recipe">Honey Almond Protein Crisps</entity>.<s>
I've showed you guys how to make chocolate protein bars, lemon protein bars, carrot cake.<s>
They're all kind of, like, cakey, so I wanted something with a little bit of crunch, and this is super, super simple and tastes really, really good.<s>
So let's get started.<s>
For this recipe we're gonna need <entity type="Amount">3</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">crispy brown rice</entity>.<s>
We're gonna need <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">whole oats</entity>.<s>
We're gonna also need <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">vanilla protein</entity>, whichever kind you like.<s>
We'll also need <entity type="Amount">a fourth</entity> of a <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of chopped <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity>.<s>
You can either just use whole <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity> and break 'em up yourself, or you can buy the chopped <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity> at the store.<s>
And then for our wet ingredients, we're gonna do <entity type="Ingredient">almond butter</entity>.<s>
We're gonna have <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>, and this isn't actually wet, but it's gonna go in the wet ingredients.<s>
That's our <entity type="Ingredient">xylitol brown sugar blend</entity>.<s>
This recipe is super easy, and it comes together really, really quickly.<s>
All you're gonna need is basically a large bowl so you can dump all the ingredients in, and we need a smaller bowl so that we can actually just microwave to heat it up just a little bit, so that it's easier to actually mix into our dry ingredients.<s>
And once you do that, it's pretty much done, and we stick it in the freezer.<s>
No baking at all, and you can eat it in about 30 minutes.<s>
To begin with, we've added already <entity type="Amount">3</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of the <entity type="Ingredient">crispy brown rice</entity>.<s>
Now, you can hopefully find this at one of your local grocery stores.<s>
I've seen it at Whole Foods almost every time.<s>
The reason I like this, it's gluten free.<s>
It's really got very few ingredients.<s>
It does have some natural sugar in it, but it's from evaporated cane juice and it's organic molasses.<s>
So it's only got 2 grams of sugar per serving, which is 3/4ths of a cup, and we've got <entity type="Amount">3</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> in here, so you're looking at less than 5 grams of sugar for the entire batch, and you're not supposed to eat the entire batch.<s>
So <entity type="Amount">3</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> go in the bowl, and then we've got <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">whole oats</entity>...<s>
So we're gonna dump that on top.<s>
And then we're gonna add <entity type="Amount">a fourth</entity> of a <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity> of crushed <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity>.<s>
So you can actually do your own if you'd like and just use your trusty rolling pin and, you know, beat 'em down that way.<s>
Or you can buy 'em already chopped at the store, which is what we have...<s>
So I'm gonna add <entity type="Amount">a fourth</entity> of a <entity type="Unit">cup</entity>.<s>
And I kind of sprinkle it around, because we don't want to actually mix it up too much until we have the rest of our ingredients ready.<s>
And the last ingredient for our dry ingredients is <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">protein</entity>...<s>
So I'm putting that in.<s>
And a lot of you guys always ask me, "What kind of <entity type="Ingredient">protein</entity> do I use?<s>
" Whatever kind of <entity type="Ingredient">protein</entity> you like.<s>
I just like something that's got a good vanilla flavor 'cause it's usually a good base for everything.<s>
And I always look for the fewer ingredients, the better, but whichever one you like.<s>
Some people like it with added <entity type="Ingredient">aminos</entity>, and all kinds of extra little things so that they can get, you know, added nutrition in <entity type="Amount">one</entity> little easy <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity>, so all right.<s>
I'm just gonna give it a gentle shake.<s>
Don't mix it up yet, because it'll all settle to the bottom.<s>
Set that aside.<s>
And now I'm gonna start with my wet ingredients.<s>
So we are gonna start with <entity type="Ingredient">almond butter</entity>.<s>
Now, when you buy this stuff at the store, make sure that you're getting the one that is just <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity>, or just <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity>.<s>
Don't get anything that has, like, added oils.<s>
As you can see, there's a ton of oil already on top.<s>
I like to pour off just a little bit.<s>
Don't pour it all off, though, because you'll have a really hard time mixing it up all the way to the bottom.<s>
So I'm gonna mix it up just a little bit... and once I get that going, we are gonna need three-fourths of a cup of this.<s>
So I like to use my one-fourth scoop.<s>
I feel like it's a little bit more manageable, so I'll just pour that in... and we'll do that three times.<s>
So I'll get that going.<s>
I have my little rubber spatula to get it out...<s>
I need three.<s>
And now you can--one of the best parts of this recipe is that it's really whatever you want to put in it, so if you wanted to use, you know, <entity type="Ingredient">peanut butter</entity> or <entity type="Ingredient">tahini</entity>, which is crushed sesame seeds, or any kind of nut butters that you like, really.<s>
You can use anything, and that goes for the nuts that you choose as well.<s>
You can choose whatever you wanted.<s>
So one more.<s>
And as you can see, this is a lot of healthy fats.<s>
You're forewarned at this point that this is not something you need every single day, but it's a great snack.<s>
And we have actually an event tomorrow where we'll be running and burning a lot of calories, so this would be great for that, because it's great for energy.<s>
All right.<s>
And it's being a little stubborn, but I think we got it all.<s>
Okay.<s>
So that goes in.<s>
So we've got our <entity type="Amount">three-fourths</entity> of a <entity type="Unit">cup</entity>.<s>
And then we're gonna need <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
And <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>, of course, will still spike your blood sugar, but <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity> is so good for you.<s>
It's loaded with antioxidants.<s>
There's all sorts of benefits to it...so we're gonna add that in.<s>
Again, this isn't for everyday consumption, but it's gonna be an awesome treat.<s>
It tastes unbelievable, actually, for so few ingredients.<s>
So we'll get that in, and one more...<s>
There we go.<s>
And actually, <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity> is kind of fun, too, because at the store, you'll find, like, all different kinds of varieties.<s>
You might find one that's, like, lavender flavored.<s>
I got one that was rose flavored once.<s>
Not so much.<s>
I really felt like I was chewing on the lawn or something.<s>
Not good, so all right.<s>
We got that.<s>
And then to this, I'm gonna add a half a cup of <entity type="Ingredient">xylitol brown sugar blend</entity>.<s>
You don't have to use this if you don't want to, because you're fine with that amount of <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
This will kind of kick up the intensity a little bit and make it a little sweeter.<s>
I think it really adds a lot to it.<s>
And it does add some calories, but unlike sugar, which is like 3.7 or something like that for sugar, this is only 2-point-something.<s>
So it's less, and actually, it's approved for diabetics, because it spikes your blood sugar less.<s>
So we're gonna throw that in there...but I do want to show you this one other alternative.<s>
Some of you may or may not be familiar with <entity type="Ingredient">sucanat</entity>.<s>
It's actually a brown sugar substitute as well.<s>
If you taste it, it's really granular, but it does have a little bit of a hint of a molasses flavor added to it without extra sugar or anything.<s>
So this is definitely an option for you.<s>
So once we've put this in the bowl, I'm gonna put it in the microwave... [beeping sound] And we're just gonna do 30-second intervals is all we need.<s>
And I'm gonna move this back over here, 'cause we're gonna need it to start mixing this together.<s>
[beeping sound] Sometimes it just takes one.<s>
Sometimes it takes a little longer.<s>
I'm gonna actually go to the bigger spatula now.<s>
Actually, that heated it up pretty well...<s>
Mix it all together... and you really, you're just heating it just enough just so that it'll spread easily inside here.<s>
I think that's actually pretty good.<s>
If you needed to, you could do another 30 seconds in the microwave.<s>
So I'm gonna go ahead and pour that in.<s>
You want to kind of spread it out a little bit and get all of it out.<s>
It's gonna seem like there's really not enough to kind of go around at first, but you just kind of have to really work it in.<s>
So now I can start working it together.<s>
I like to kind of use this little fold-over technique... so it doesn't stick to my spatula...All right.<s>
So then you kind of start chopping into it.<s>
Now, you could actually add <entity type="Ingredient">dried fruits</entity> if you wanted to, if this was for your kids.<s>
You know, I know a lot of us stay away from dried fruits, but you could do all kinds of <entity type="Ingredient">nuts</entity>, actually.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Walnuts</entity>.<s>
You could do <entity type="Ingredient">peanuts</entity>, whatever you'd like.<s>
All right.<s>
I think we're looking pretty good.<s>
I see a few dry spots, but I think I can fix that when it put it into the bowl.<s>
So I want to use a 9 x 13 Pyrex dish.<s>
You can use whichever dish you'd like.<s>
I just find that works well because I don't need to spray it or anything.<s>
There's enough healthy fats in here that you don't have to add any nonstick sprays or anything like that.<s>
All right.<s>
I'm gonna grab my dish and pour this in... All right.<s>
And you kind of get it started--I'll move that so you can see.<s>
Kind of get it started with your spatula... and then I like to finish it with my fingers.<s>
I think it's easier to really get it pushed down in there.<s>
So wet your fingers just a little bit...so it doesn't stick, and just start really pushing it down...<s>
I could put the towel down underneath this.<s>
It wouldn't be so noisy.<s>
So I'm just really pushing it in good...and that's it.<s>
And just so you know, one of my favorite things, actually, is you can use the same technique and actually use cookie cutters, which is kind of fun, and make like little shapes and stuff for the kids.<s>
And now I'm just gonna put this in the freezer and then in about an hour to check on it... All right.<s>
It's been about an hour, so I'm gonna go ahead and get the <entity type="Recipe">Honey Almond Protein Crisps</entity> out of the freezer.<s>
All right.<s>
It is definitely cold.<s>
It's pretty hard.<s>
So you can either at this point cut it into squares and sometimes, I don't even like to go to all that trouble, so I just break pieces off.<s>
I recommend you store it actually in the freezer, because it'll keep the texture nice and hard, and it doesn't get too hard to bite into.<s>
But if you cut it into 18 squares, each one is about 154 calories, about 8 grams, all of good fat, 21 grams of carbs, and about 4 grams of protein.<s>
So I guarantee you will like this.<s>
It's really good stuff, and I hope you will come back next time whenever I'm making something new.<s>
For more content like this, check out bodybuilding.com.<s>
[music]<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>