[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="21" title="Healthy Recipes- Quick & Easy Turkey Meatloaf Muffins " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cSSZB3jSL4M" mode="non-automatic">
[music] Hi I'm Jamie Eason and I'm in the bodybuilding.com kitchen today to show you how I make my <entity type="Recipe">Turkey Meatloaf Muffins</entity>.<s>
[music] You're gonna need a large bowl for this, because we've got a lot to mix up, okay, but the nice thing is is just one big bowl for everything.<s>
Okay.<s>
The first ingredient we're gonna need is <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">quick-cooking oats</entity>.<s>
So we're gonna dump those in.<s>
Then you've got all these ingredients that we're gonna mix in with it.<s>
We've got <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">garlic</entity>.<s>
Now, you can either use the powdered version, or you can use the minced version.<s>
I'll show you what--I've got it over here.<s>
Here's the minced <entity type="Ingredient">garlic</entity>.<s>
Now, this one seems to be okay.<s>
If you read the ingredients, it says, "Garlic, water.<s>
" It says, "Phosphoric acid," and no preservatives.<s>
So this one's okay.<s>
You could probably use this as an option, but some of them, be really careful.<s>
Read the label.<s>
They actually have oil in them.<s>
It won't be real prominent.<s>
It won't say it on the top.<s>
So you've gotta really check out those ingredients.<s>
This one's actually rare to be just in water.<s>
So that's an option, too, but we're gonna use the powder 'cause it's just as good that way.<s>
Okay, then we've got <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity>.<s>
We've got <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoons</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">pepper</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">black pepper</entity>.<s>
We've also got <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoons</entity> of a <entity type="Ingredient">dry mustard</entity>... just <entity type="Ingredient">dry, yellow mustard</entity>.<s>
And sometimes if you're looking for <entity type="Ingredient">dry yellow mustard</entity>, some people will not be able to find it in your standard jar, kind of like this one... You'll have to find it in sort of a box.<s>
It looks a little bit more like the <entity type="Ingredient">pepper</entity>, but it's in a darker box.<s>
So I've noticed it's hard to find sometimes, and that's why.<s>
And then we've got a <entity type="Amount">half</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cumin</entity>.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Cumin</entity> is a really smoky spice.<s>
It's really good for you.<s>
A lot of these spices are antioxidants so they're really good for you.<s>
If you're not using a lot of spices in your food, you should start doing so.<s>
And then we also have a <entity type="Amount">half</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">thyme</entity>.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Thyme</entity> is used a lot in poultry dishes, whether you're making chicken, turkey, or anything.<s>
And then our last ingredient is the one that makes the whole dish, so this is not the easiest to find, so this might take you a little while, but it's very well worth it.<s>
It is <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoons</entity> of a <entity type="Ingredient">chipotle pepper seasoning</entity>.<s>
Here's--let's see if I can find it.<s>
Here's what it looks like... so hopefully you'll be able to find that.<s>
It does add some heat, so be careful.<s>
If you're not big on hot things, then maybe only add <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> and <entity type="Amount">a half</entity> or something like that.<s>
But I really think without it, they're a little more bland, so you definitely want the heat in there.<s>
So that's it.<s>
So I'm just gonna use my fingers and kind of get it all incorporated and mixed up...<s>
This whole recipe is pretty much about using your hands, so all right.<s>
That looks pretty good.<s>
Oh, and before I really get messy, I'm gonna take this off...<s>
So put that to the side.<s>
All right.<s>
The next thing we're gonna need is going to be chopped <entity type="Ingredient">onions</entity> and chopped <entity type="Ingredient">celery</entity>.<s>
Now, this is pretty convenient 'cause it just comes in the package in your produce section.<s>
I'm all about quick and easy, and this is what I'm gonna do.<s>
I hate chopping <entity type="Ingredient">onions</entity>, so we'll open that up... and if you were to chop it, you're gonna want to do a cup of everything, so quite a bit.<s>
You know, you really can't overdo the vegetables, and if you're not a fan of celery, you can use <entity type="Ingredient">red peppers</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">green peppers</entity>, anything you want.<s>
But <entity type="Ingredient">celery</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">onion</entity> seem to work really well for this.<s>
But the more veggies you add, the more moisture there's gonna be in your dish, so overdo the veggies instead of under.<s>
Put that to the side.<s>
All right.<s>
The next thing we're gonna need is <entity type="Ingredient">meat</entity>.<s>
Grab these over here.<s>
For this recipe, you can either use <entity type="Ingredient">extra-lean ground turkey</entity>, or you can use <entity type="Ingredient">extra-lean ground chicken breast</entity>.<s>
Either one will work really well, and actually, even <entity type="Ingredient">beef</entity> will work, too, so get that open...<s>
Dump it in.<s>
And I'm using probably--I would say this is about probably about <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">pounds</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">meat</entity>.<s>
So dump that in, and it doesn't have to be exact.<s>
That's the great thing about this recipe is you kind of do it all to taste.<s>
You just dump it all in and see what you get.<s>
Then the next thing we're gonna need to add some moisture is gonna be <entity type="Amount">3</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">egg whites</entity>.<s>
If you're not concerned about adding any added fat, you can actually do a whole <entity type="Ingredient">egg</entity> in there, but for this purpose, we're just gonna use the <entity type="Ingredient">egg whites</entity>.<s>
There's one...<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Egg</entity> number two... and <entity type="Ingredient">egg</entity> number three.<s>
Now, before I really get my hands in there and get dirty, I'm gonna make sure first that I have my muffin pan prepped, and I've already set the oven to 375 degrees, so make sure you preheat it and that it's ready to go before you put them in.<s>
Rinse my hands off.<s>
All right, so we're gonna prep this, because I don't want to have to stop it the middle with goopy fingers and do it.<s>
So I'm gonna use my <entity type="Ingredient">canola oil</entity> or <entity type="Ingredient">olive oil spray</entity>, and that is 12 muffin tins.<s>
It should make about 12.<s>
Sometimes it goes a little over.<s>
It just depends on how big or small you make them.<s>
Okay.<s>
You want to spray 'em pretty good just to make sure they don't stick.<s>
And to save my pan, 'cause I hate when they get gross, I always, always, always wipe the excess off the top, 'cause they will get pretty grodey if you start making these a lot, which is what I do, because I always have these on hand and in my refrigerator, just ready to go.<s>
You can actually keep this recipe completely frozen in your freezer and just take them out one at a time and microwave them if you want.<s>
All right.<s>
So that's ready to go.<s>
I'm gonna set that to the side.<s>
Bring this back and get busy.<s>
So take any jewelry off.<s>
This is pretty cold...So all right.<s>
Starting to look pretty grodey, which is exactly what we want.<s>
You don't want to over-mix meat too, too much.<s>
You do want to make sure you get all the spices incorporated and lift it up and get all that stuff out of there.<s>
If you over-mix meat, though, it tends to get a little more tough, so don't go crazy.<s>
Just get it all in there.<s>
Now, the nice thing about this dish, too, is that the muffin tins are what keep it in its serving size.<s>
So it's all nice and portable that way, and it's got your carb and your protein all mixed in one.<s>
Now, it is a low amount of carbs, so you could still eat them in a <entity type="Ingredient">pita</entity>.<s>
You could add <entity type="Amount">a few</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">rice cakes</entity> or something to them.<s>
Every time I flip it, I'm still seeing spices, so I'm making sure.<s>
All right.<s>
Don't want to over-mix, so I'll stop there.<s>
All right.<s>
Now we're gonna put them in our muffin tin, and I'd say do about a racquetball size.<s>
Let's see.<s>
That might be a little larger than a racquetball size, but not too bad.<s>
We'll see how that looks.<s>
Sometimes you'll get all the way through and have to steal a little from the other one to kind of make 'em even out.<s>
There we go.<s>
You don't have to be perfect, but... Another thing is that the fact that they're in a muffin tin, this is essentially just a meatloaf.<s>
The difference is most meatloafs have, like, a ketchup base kind of in them, whether it's ketchup or tomato sauce or something inside of 'em.<s>
We've kind of left that out and just put the <entity type="Ingredient">eggs</entity> and a lot of <entity type="Ingredient">veggies</entity> in there, so they're not quite as moist.<s>
You can, if you want to, you can actually do what I call a thumbprint.<s>
Push it down in the middle and put like a <entity type="Ingredient">ketchup</entity> or a <entity type="Ingredient">barbecue sauce</entity> or something in them if you want to.<s>
They get a little slimy and a little bit messy to take with you, so only do that when you plan to eat 'em at home, I think.<s>
Okay, we're doing good.<s>
Not looking like I'm overdoing it yet.<s>
Oh, the beauty of having them in a muffin tin, not only is that it's the right portion, but the moisture from the <entity type="Ingredient">veggies</entity> stays confined in the little tins, so it tends to keep the meat from getting overly dry.<s>
Because, you know, <entity type="Ingredient">extra-lean ground turkey</entity> has no fat really, so really kind of just gets overcooked pretty easily.<s>
There we go.<s>
Exciting stuff watching me do this, I'm sure.<s>
Okay, it looks like I actually maybe have--I can make them a little bit bigger, so make the last one and then we'll add a little bit to a few of 'em.<s>
Now, if you were to cook these and measure them out, they would usually be about 2 and a half ounces each, so that will come to, you know, a pretty good serving size.<s>
Like, a male might eat maybe three or four of these, where a female would only eat two would be your serving.<s>
And each one of these, depending on how large you make it, is gonna be like about 78 to 80 calories, or you know, maybe a little more if you do too large of ones.<s>
These might be more like 80, 'cause I'm making 'em pretty big.<s>
I think those packages, I didn't check the exact weight of them.<s>
May have been a little bit more than 2 pounds, but that's good.<s>
I'd rather have more than less, and these are really lean, so they'll be good for us.<s>
So that looks pretty good.<s>
Rinse it off.<s>
And so to continue with the macros, about 80 calories.<s>
Maybe like 2 grams of fat.<s>
You're looking at 4 carbs and about 11 grams of protein, and that's for one muffin.<s>
So you can get 22 grams of protein for 2 muffins.<s>
All right.<s>
These are ready to go, looking pretty good.<s>
Stick them in the middle rack, and we want to cook these for quite a while.<s>
You never want uncooked turkey, and so depending on how hot your oven gets, I'm gonna put mine at about 40.<s>
But you might have to play with that.<s>
Go a little over, go a little under, and just check them as you go.<s>
All right.<s>
So we've got 40 minutes to wait, so go watch a sitcom or something and we'll come back and check 'em.<s>
All right.<s>
I think these are about done, so check 'em out.<s>
They're looking good.<s>
Let's pull 'em out.<s>
They smell good.<s>
I'll put down my potholder so that I don't burn the counter.<s>
So they look pretty good.<s>
All right.<s>
Now we just need to give 'em time to cool.<s>
I suggest that you take them out a little bit before they're completely cool and put 'em on a paper towel.<s>
I just fold it up on the counter and I put 'em on there and allow the juices that have kind of accumulated in the bottom to get a little bit dry, so that I can put 'em in a Ziploc baggie, keep 'em in the fridge for any time that I just need to grab something to go, or just looking for something good to eat.<s>
So hopefully you like the <entity type="Recipe">Turkey Meatloaf Muffin</entity>, and hopefully you'll come back to bodybuilding.com and check out more recipes with me.<s>
[music]<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>