[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="3" title="Cookie Dough Ice Cream Recipe - Laura Vitale - Laura in the Kitchen Episode 781 " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-dmW7QynDTY" mode="non-automatic">
Hi guys, I'm Laura Vitale and today, upon your requests, we are making Cookie Dough Ice Cream!<s>
I've had so many people ask for this recipe, it's insane!<s>
And, it's actually really really simple.<s>
I've also had some people ask me if cookie dough ice cream is just simply crushed up chocolate chip cookies in <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient>.<s>
It's not, so today we are going to make the real thing.<s>
It's so, so easy, and <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient> is something that I really only make in the Summertime, so I'm always looking forward to sharing a new recipe with you.<s>
The recipe to make the <B-Ingredient>custard</B-Ingredient> is pretty simple and basic.<s>
You're going to need <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>whole</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>heavy</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolks</I-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>sugar</B-Ingredient>, I also have <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>pinch</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and either <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>bean</I-Ingredient>, or I've got <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>bean paste</I-Ingredient> here so it makes my life a little bit easier.<s>
This is really easy.<s>
Now, we are going to make the custard now, and then I'll show you later how to make the cookie dough and then when we combine everything together it is going to be money!<s>
Okay, let's get started - so simple!<s>
I've got a large sauce pan here, and in here I'm going to add my cream and <B-Ingredient>milk</B-Ingredient>, add them both at the same time - makes me feel fancy like that.<s>
And then we're going to add in a good <B-Unit>spoonful</B-Unit> of the <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>paste</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You would need one <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>bean</I-Ingredient> that you would scrape down and get rid of - you know, take all the seeds out and put it in here - the <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>beans</I-Ingredient>.<s>
But, I'm using <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>paste</I-Ingredient> so, a nice healthy spoonful of that should do the trick.<s>
So, I'm just going to take this off.<s>
I'm going to put this on my stove top, and let this come to temperature to a simmer over about medium-low heat.<s>
Now, while my milk mixture is coming to a simmer, I'm going to just take my <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolks</I-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>sugar</B-Ingredient> with <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>pinch</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>, and I"m going to whisk these together until the mixture becomes really nice, thick and pale in color.<s>
I'll show you what it looks like when it gets there.<s>
Basically - essentially what we are making right now is kind of like a zabaglione, zabaglione is nothing but - which I'll show you in a different recipe - is just <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolks</I-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>sugar</B-Ingredient>, <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of booze, and you are good to go!<s>
But this needs to be whisked until it's really light and pale, and about doubled in volume.<s>
I'll show you what it looks like when it's there.<s>
Keep an eye out on your milk mixture, you do not want it to come to a boil, because if it does, it will split and then you're going to have to start all over and waste all that <B-Ingredient>milk</B-Ingredient> and cream and vanilla.<s>
So, keep an eye on that it should take just a coupe of minutes and you should be done with the <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolk</I-Ingredient> mixture as well - and you're getting an awesome arm workout while you're at it!<s>
My <B-Ingredient>milk</B-Ingredient> is at the right temperature, you can see there are little bubbles starting to form around the edge of the pot, which is when I know that it's at a perfect simmer.<s>
My <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolk</I-Ingredient>, as you can see, i'll show you the texture - the consistency - see it kind of falls down on a ribbon, oh that's perfect!<s>
I'm going to temper the <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolks</I-Ingredient> by just taking a little bit of my <B-Ingredient>milk</B-Ingredient> mixture, just about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <I-Amount>half</I-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> or so, and this is all it's doing is tempering the <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolks</I-Ingredient> so that they don't get shocked when you pour them into the pan with the hot liquid.<s>
That's all you need to do.<s>
I'm going to now pour my <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolk</I-Ingredient> mixture into my pan, very simple, just making an easy, easy and very classic <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream custard</I-Ingredient> base.<s>
Now I'm going to - look at the color of that!<s>
Look at that color!It just makes me so happy, you have no idea!<s>
Okay, I am going to just switch back to my wooden spoon, and I'm going to cook this over about low heat until it thickens really nicely and it coats the back of my spoon, and I will show you what it looks like when it's there.<s>
Just make sure you keep this at a low heat and take your time and be gentle, because if this comes to a boil, or it gets too hot, it will split.<s>
And once it splits, again, you will know when it splits, and there is no going back, so just take your time.<s>
Stir it in a figure eight motion, kind of like I am doing right now.<s>
And then just be patient and when it gets nice and thick, you will be able to notice it immediately.<s>
My custard is ready, it has been cooking for about six minutes and you can see it is coating the back of a spoon and if I run my finger down and the <B-Ingredient>custard</B-Ingredient> stays separated, you know it's thick enough!<s>
Doesn't really get any easier than that!<s>
I'm going to pass this through a sieve just in case there are any egg shells remaining or anything curdled, or whatever.<s>
It stays back, and doesn't get into your final mixture.<s>
As you can see, this is smooth sailing all the way.<s>
That's how I like it!<s>
That's how I like it!<s>
Nice and smooth, there's really nothing - maybe a little, little tiny <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of something remaining, but for the most part everything is really nice and smooth.<s>
Okay, now, you need to wrap this with plastic wrap, and you want to make sure that the plastic is actually touching the surface of the custard, because otherwise it just forms a really weird looking skin that you don't want and it's definitely not going to be smooth and delightful once you go ahead and freeze this.<s>
So I'm going to pop this into the fridge - it needs to be in the fridge for about four to six hours or best, overnight.<s>
That's even better.<s>
If you can put this in the fridge overnight, it's even better.<s>
I'm going to leave this in, it's pretty early in the day so I'll get to finish this this afternoon and I'll show you what it looks like once this is chilled.<s>
We'll get going on making our cookie dough and we'll pull the whole thing off together!<s>
While the <B-Ingredient>custard</B-Ingredient> is chilling, we're going to get going on making the cookie dough batter.<s>
Now we're actually making a chocolate chip cookie dough batter here, and now, if that - chocolate chip cookie dough - if that bothers you because none of this is going to be cooked, so you're kind of eating raw cookie dough, which I love and I know everyone eats raw cookie dough at some point in their lives - now if this bothers you, then you might want to skip this ice cream in its entirety.<s>
You can make my <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>ice cream</I-Ingredient>, you can make my <B-Ingredient>strawberry</B-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>mint</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chocolate</I-Ingredient> chip, vanilla whatever you want - I've got a ton of recipes on my website.<s>
But, most of the time, cookie dough ice cream has actual cookie dough in it, and that's what makes it so delicious.<s>
So, we're going to make it like we would make <B-Recipe>chocolate</B-Recipe> <I-Recipe>chip cookies</I-Recipe>, but really easy - and to do that, you'll need <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>all</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>purpose flour</I-Ingredient>, I've got <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>pinch</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and I've got <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>instant</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>espresso powder</I-Ingredient> here, just a small little pinch, <B-Ingredient>brown</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sugar</I-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>granulated</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sugar</I-Ingredient>, some softened <B-Ingredient>unsalted</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>butter</I-Ingredient>, <B-Amount>an</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient>, <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>extract</I-Ingredient>, and what I have here are <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chips</I-Ingredient> that I've pulsed in my food processor so you can see that I've got little rubbles, I've got some that are bigger.<s>
I've got some that are kind of whole, and I think the thing that I love about cookie dough ice cream is that you actually get bits and pieces of <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chips</I-Ingredient> or <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> throughout the entire <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And I think that just by pulsing it a few times, and breaking the pieces up a bit just gives it a little more interest, and I think these itty bitty, almost dust-like pieces of the <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> is what makes this so divine, in my opinion.<s>
So if you want to skip doing that part, by all means, do that, but I think that it's kind of crucial.<s>
I also have a nine by thirteen inch baking pan here, and I have a big piece of parchment paper because you want to make sure you can lift it up.<s>
That's sitting aside, so let's get going, I'm going to just cream together my <B-Ingredient>butter</B-Ingredient>, and both kinds of <B-Ingredient>sugar</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I'm going to do this in just a little bowl because I don't feel like getting my mixer out for just a small batch, so I'm just going to mix these two together until combined.<s>
That's looking good enough, I'm going to add in my <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Again, you want to make sure that whoever you're making this for will eat raw cookie dough.<s>
Just want to make sure you don't have anyone that can't eat raw <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> or whatnot, just give them a heads up.<s>
I'm going to switch to my whisk briefly, just to mix everything together a little bit better.<s>
Just mixing together the coffee and <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Now I'm not adding any leavening agents to this - no baking soda - you don't need to, I mean you're not baking it so it's not going to make a difference.<s>
I'm going to put my <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> mixture in here, normally I would put the dry into my wet, but I switched bowls for some reason and the <B-Ingredient>flour</B-Ingredient> was in the bigger bowl and I just wanted to have plenty of room to mix this together.<s>
And that's basically all I'm doing, I'm just going to combine this until it forms into a dough, and then I can add in - I can actually add in my <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> now because it's almost there so I might as well because I don't want to overwork this anyway.<s>
Add in my <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> chip mixture, you can also add - take <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>bar</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> and chop that up if you wanted to, that would be lovely, instead of adding chocolate chips, or you can add <B-Ingredient>mini</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chocolate chips</I-Ingredient>.<s>
But, you see what I mean when I say that I think that this is so much better because that way you're really getting <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> throughout every little teeny tiny bite of the cookie dough.<s>
Otherwise, you just get <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chips</I-Ingredient> here, chocolate chips there, but I want <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> completely infused throughout the entire cookie dough, so that's why I like to pulse it, and it's those kinds of little things that really make a difference, otherwise you know I would skip it.<s>
Okay, now I'm going to put this closer to me, get my cookie dough out of here.<s>
Oops!<s>
We'll fix that in a minute, do not panic!<s>
Talking to myself, by the way.<s>
Now, all I'm doing - and this can be a little bit tricky, I'm trying to get this into a pretty thin layer because when we freeze this and I pull this out of the freezer, we're going to need to chop it into small pieces.<s>
But clearly, you can see that I'm not too worried about getting it perfect, and I don't want you to be that worried about it either.<s>
And it doesn't have to be all on one layer, I'm just doing it this way because it's easier to cut it once it's frozen.<s>
So, just going to do that, and then I'm going to pop this into my freezer, probably for several hours or however long it takes for the custard to chill.<s>
The more frozen, the better.<s>
The easier it's going to be for us to chop it up.<s>
So I'm going to pop this in, looks odd now, but trust me when I tell you, it works wonders.<s>
Popping this in, waiting for my custard to get nice and cool, and then we'll go on and put it all in the little machine and get that much closer to eating cookie dough ice cream!<s>
My custard was in the fridge overnight, I was going to leave it in there for a few hours, but then we had my aunt over, and maybe a cocktail or two, and we decided to wait until tomorrow to have ice cream - which is good because it's the weekend - perfect time for entertaining and having ice cream!<s>
Now, I have my <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient> machine here, you want to make sure that the insert of your <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient> machine, which is this right here, that's going to basically freeze your <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient> for you, is frozen.<s>
Now, you want to always check your manufacturer's instructions because every ice cream machine is different from others, so mine says to put it in there overnight, so that's what I do, and it's really nice and frozen solid which is really important, so make sure that you read your instructions because some might just need a couple of hours, but most of the time they'll take overnight.<s>
Now I have my really cold custard, which is absolutely fantastic, I mean look at that!<s>
This would be good on it's own, as-is over top of maybe <B-Ingredient>berries</B-Ingredient> or whatnot.<s>
I'm going to pour that in there.<s>
Get it all out.<s>
Okay, and now I'm just going to turn this on, now again, check your manufacturer's instructions because the time is going to vary.<s>
Mine takes a good twenty-five to thirty minutes to freeze the <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient>, but they're all so different.<s>
So, I'm going to wait for this to be pretty much - pretty much fully frozen, and then we'll get going on adding our cookie dough!<s>
Alright, my <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient> is exactly where I want it.<s>
It's been about twenty five minutes, now I'm going to take my cookie dough that was in the freezer overnight as well, which is what we want.<s>
And this is why I do it on parchment because it's so easy!<s>
And now, I just take a sharp knife, and in no particular way, I just - I'm just going to chop this up into bite sized pieces, that is it.<s>
You can - you really can do this a couple of different ways.<s>
Instead of doing it the way I am doing it, you can take little <B-Unit>teaspoons</B-Unit> of the batter - you know, once you make it and then put it on a baking sheet lined with parchment and freeze it that way and then you can just put them right into your ice cream machine.<s>
I tend to do it this way, I don't know why, I just think it's easier, and gets the job done a lot faster, and you can also leave certain pieces bigger or smaller, like that's perfect.<s>
Now I'm just going to go across, and just rough chop-age on everything until you've got about bite sized pieces.<s>
That's it!<s>
And I did want to mention that it sounds like this is really hard, but it's not, it just sounds hard because we're cutting through <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I just wanted to mention that because as I was doing this, I'm thinking - you know you can hear the crunch, but the crunch is just because we are chopping up the <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient>, so anyway, figured I would let you guys know that.<s>
And now I'm just going to take these - and you can cut these as big or as small as you want.<s>
And you can add as much or as little as you want to your cookie dough batter, it's up to you.<s>
I'm going to add most of it, but most likely not all of it because it's a lot, and then we can also add some for people to serve, you know, sprinkle on top.<s>
Then just let them mix in as this is running.<s>
Yeah buddy!<s>
Now I only added about <B-Amount>half</B-Amount> of the chocolate cookie dough mixture in here because I didn't want to add too, too much because then you can also have a hard time with your machine being able to handle all that.<s>
But look at this!<s>
I mean, are you seeing what I'm seeing?!<s>
And also, are you seeing how those little rubbles of <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> kind of spread all throughout the batter?And that's from when I took the <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chips</I-Ingredient> and put them through the food processor, because that's what I personally like.<s>
Obviously, you want big <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chips</I-Ingredient> here and there, but why have a little bit when you can have <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> throughout?<s>
Ah, look at that, if you get up close you can see that it's really creamy, it has those big chunks of cookie dough.<s>
I'm just going to make myself a little <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Okay?<s>
Just a scoop.<s>
Just a scoop, on a cone because I'm deserving.<s>
Look!<s>
Whoooaa!<s>
Look at that!<s>
Look at all the pieces!<s>
Mmm.<s>
You'll love this!<s>
I promise you will love this.<s>
It's so easy, tastes so much better than store bought, I cannot stress it enough.<s>
It's insanely easy to do, doesn't take a lot of time, it doesn't take any fancy ingredients.<s>
It's very basic but it's done the right way, and you can see - I mean, it's just - it's phenomenal.<s>
Look at the <B-Ingredient>chocolate</B-Ingredient> pieces in there!<s>
[humming] I was trying to sing in my head, but... LauraintheKitchen.com will have the recipe written for you, let me know what <B-Ingredient>ice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cream</I-Ingredient> you want to see next.<s>
Hope you've enjoyed spending time with me and I'll see you next time!<s>
Bye bye!<s></transcript></transcripts>