[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="30" title="Rotel Cheese Dip " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aR9xELaq9UE" mode="non-automatic">
This is Stephanie Manley with copykat.com.<s>
Today I am going to show you how you can make <entity type="Recipe">Ro-Tel Cheese Dip</entity> in two different ways.<s>
This is one of my favorite party foods to make.<s>
It is easy and tastes great.<s>
Again, I said this is easy.<s>
This only has two ingredients; the first being <entity type="Ingredient">Velveeta cheese</entity> and the next being <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">can</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">Ro-Tel tomatoes</entity>.<s>
Now the ratio is easy, easy to remember, it's <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Unit">pound</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">Velveeta cheese</entity> to <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Unit">can</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">Ro-Tel tomatoes</entity>.<s>
Now I like to heat mine up on the stove, just because I think it's easier than pulling it in and out of the microwave, and stirring it and trying to make sure it's all perfectly melted.<s>
This takes only about three to five minutes, and you will have some perfectly made <entity type="Recipe">Ro-Tel dip</entity>.<s>
So again, there it was.<s>
That took me about three to five minutes to make, and now I'm going to spoon this up and put it in a dish and get it ready.<s>
So but you know what?<s>
While this is really good, we can make this <entity type="Recipe">Ro-Tel Cheese Dip</entity> better.<s>
So I'm going to show you how you can jazz up your <entity type="Recipe">Ro-Tel cheese dip</entity>; <entity type="Ingredient">sausage</entity>.<s>
You're going to brown <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">pound</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">sausage</entity>, so go ahead, and cook that thoroughly, because we are going to put this into our cheese sauce, so you want to make sure it is completely browned all the way through.<s>
So again, I'm starting out with that same pot of <entity type="Recipe">Ro-Tel dip</entity> and that is <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Unit">pound</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">Velveeta</entity> to <entity type="Amount">two</entity> <entity type="Unit">cans</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">Ro-Tel</entity>.<s>
I'm adding in <entity type="Ingredient">sour cream</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">cream cheese</entity> and the next ingredient I am going to add in is that <entity type="Ingredient">sausage</entity>.<s>
That cooked <entity type="Ingredient">sausage</entity> is going to go in here, as well.<s>
Now for the exact ingredients and recipe, please go to my website.<s>
It's there I list it for you.<s>
<entity type="Amount">A</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">garlic powder</entity>, and then I'm going to go ahead and stir this together a little bit, before I put in my <entity type="Ingredient">pickled jalapeno slices</entity>.<s>
I like to use the pickled ones, simply because they're not as raw-tasting, and I think the heat's a little bit more consistent.<s>
So if you like your <entity type="Recipe">cheese dip</entity> a little spicier, hey, add some more or even add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> of that <entity type="Ingredient">jalapeno pickle juice</entity>.<s>
You can see how that's rich and creamy and full of goodies, so hey, there's <entity type="Recipe">Ro-Tel Cheese Dip</entity> two different ways.<s>
And for more great recipes, go to copykat.com.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>