[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="6" title="Egg Rolls Recipe |  Hilah Cooking " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cud-ZTvCxx0" mode="non-automatic">
Hey, dudes.<s>
I'm Hilah, and today on Hilah Cooking, I'm making Chinese egg rolls, which might more appropriately be called Chinese-American egg rolls because they're a complete bastardization of original Chinese spring rolls, I'm sure.<s>
But anyway, these are great for snacks, appetizers, or even Easter because they're called egg rolls.<s>
Get it?<s>
That'll really throw your guests for a loop.<s>
They'll be like, 'What the f-- is Chinese food doing here with the ham?<s>
' Okay.<s>
The first thing we're going to do is make our filling.<s>
So, these have a precooked filling that you will cook it, and then cool it before we fill the <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>rolls</I-Ingredient>.<s>
I'm going to add <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of oil to my pan and start sauteing.<s>
I've got some super, very, very finely minced <B-Ingredient>celery</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>onion</B-Ingredient> here.<s>
So, while that's going, I've got also here about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <I-Amount>half</I-Amount> a <B-Unit>pound</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>ground</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pork</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use <B-Ingredient>ground</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>turkey</I-Ingredient>, or you can leave out the meat completely and add some more vegetables if you want to also.<s>
I'm going to add to this -- This bowl, I've got <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>brown</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sugar</I-Ingredient>, <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>corn</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>starch</I-Ingredient>, and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> minced <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>ginger</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So, when you add <B-Ingredient>corn</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>starch</I-Ingredient> to ground meat like this, it kind of helps lock in the moisture.<s>
So the meat doesn't dry out, and it helps it sort of bind together.<s>
So, it's serving two purposes.<s>
I'm just going to mix this in with the ground meat here.<s>
Also going to add about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>soy</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sauce</I-Ingredient> to this and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>pepper</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I'm going to use <B-Ingredient>white</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient>, but you can use <B-Ingredient>black</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient> or <B-Ingredient>red</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient> if you want it a little bit spicier, and <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> also.<s>
I'm going to add <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> to these vegetables too, to draw some of that moisture out, to sweat them a little bit.<s>
They'll soften up a little quicker.<s>
And then, just get our meat mixed up and add that to the skillet also.<s>
Then, we just want to stir it around, break the meat up as much as you can, and eventually, it'll sort of come into really, really tiny little crumbles.<s>
So, keep an eye on that and have a brew while you're waiting, because nothing goes with <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>rolls</I-Ingredient> like <B-Ingredient>beer</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Right?<s>
You could also have water, but hey.<s>
Look.<s>
Tecate Light.<s>
I'm saving calories on my beer so that I can have more fried egg rolls later.<s>
Beautiful.<s>
Okay.<s>
Just a few minutes later, it looks like this.<s>
I'm going to turn the heat off.<s>
You just want to make sure that any big chunks of meat are sort of broken up.<s>
You want, really, a very fine filling for these egg rolls.<s>
Then, transfer it to a plate.<s>
You can use a baking sheet or something.<s>
We just want to spread it out so that it cools off faster.<s>
If there's any oil left in the bottom of your pan, you can try to keep that behind.<s>
We'll use that to cook the <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient> also.<s>
Okay.<s>
We'll set that aside.<s>
Then, back in the same skillet.<s>
I'm going to add a tiny bit more oil, and we'll add the <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So, this is shredded Napa <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I just sliced it really, really finely.<s>
You can use regular old <B-Ingredient>green</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cabbage</I-Ingredient> too.<s>
That'll give you more sort of texture inside your <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>roll</I-Ingredient>, and that's more common in restaurants.<s>
I don't know.<s>
I had Napa <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So, I'm using <B-Ingredient>Napa</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cabbage</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Either one is fine.<s>
You can also add <B-Ingredient>bean</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sprouts</I-Ingredient> and things like that.<s>
So, we're just going to saute this until the <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient> is wilted.<s>
It shouldn't take very long at all.<s>
Okay.<s>
So, <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient> getting nice and wilted.<s>
We don't want to get it too soft because you want to keep a little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of texture, and it'll still continue to cook, even after you've turned the heat off.<s>
So, this looks pretty good.<s>
The leafy parts are nice and soft, but the stemmy parts are still a little crispy.<s>
So, I'm going to turn that off, and I'm going to add <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>water</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chestnuts</I-Ingredient>.<s>
These is just like -- These is just like-- A can of <B-Ingredient>water</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chestnuts</I-Ingredient> that I drained and minced finely.<s>
And then, I'm also going to add <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>mushrooms</B-Ingredient>.<s>
These are <B-Ingredient>dried</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>Shiitake mushrooms</I-Ingredient> that I've just had soaking in water for about an hour.<s>
Wood ear mushrooms are, like those black ones that are really firm, are also commonly used in <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>rolls</I-Ingredient>.<s>
These are a little bit easier to find, usually.<s>
So, squeeze the <B-Ingredient>water</B-Ingredient> out.<s>
Then, I'm just going to mince up these mushrooms too.<s>
And then, finally to this, I'm going to add <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit> of regular, <B-Ingredient>all</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>purpose flour</I-Ingredient> and mix that in.<s>
That's just going to help the filling stay kind of firm.<s>
As it cools, it'll thicken it up.<s>
So, it'll sort of make a mass that you can form into little <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>rolls</I-Ingredient>.<s>
I'm going to spread this out on top of the meat mix.<s>
Then, we'll just put this whole thing in the fridge and let it get super chilled.<s>
You can make the filling a day ahead of time, even two days ahead of time, which is muy excelente when you've had a lot of brews.<s>
Okay.<s>
Time to roll these mofos.<s>
This is just about half the mixture.<s>
It's cooled off totally.<s>
These are my <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>roll wrappers</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can find these in the frozen section, usually, of pretty much any major grocery store.<s>
You just want to thaw them out, and then keep the rest of them covered while you're rolling them so they don't dry out.<s>
It dries out pretty quickly.<s>
So, there's two here.<s>
God damn it.<s>
They stick together.<s>
Stick together like a hand in glove.<s>
These <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>roll wrappers</I-Ingredient> are the best of friends.<s>
Okay.<s>
It's going on my album, guys.<s>
Stay tuned.<s>
Stay iTuned.<s>
Just kidding.<s>
Okay.<s>
So, you want to get a big spoonful, maybe like <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <I-Amount>quarter</I-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> or so of your mixture.<s>
Put it pretty much right in the center, maybe a little bit below the center, but pretty much just right on, bros. And then, roll the bottom up.<s>
What I like to do is kind of take it over, and then pull it back.<s>
Did you see how I did that?<s>
Did you see how I did that?<s>
So that it gets a nice little tight log.<s>
Fold this side over.<s>
Fold this side over.<s>
Then, in this little bowl, I've got just a mixture of <B-Ingredient>plain</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>flour</I-Ingredient> and water, about equal parts, maybe a little bit more water.<s>
It's not important really.<s>
Just use your finger to go.<s>
I like to sort of get these sides here, like the envelope sides, and then the little point also.<s>
This is going to kind of glue it together.<s>
Then, just roll it over like that.<s>
Just like that.<s>
Make sure that you have enough in that little tippy tip.<s>
There we go.<s>
So then, we want to set this aside, seam side down on a plate.<s>
You can make these and let them sit for maybe, like, ten or 15 minutes tops.<s>
But eventually, and pretty quickly, the filling, the liquid in the filling and the <B-Ingredient>oil</B-Ingredient> in the filling is going to kind of soak through the wrapper.<s>
So, you can't really make them really ahead of time.<s>
But like I said, you can make the filling ahead of time.<s>
Then, just roll up a few.<s>
Then, as you're frying the first batch, you or someone else, ideally you have a little helper, a little kitchen elf, will be rolling the next batch.<s>
So, it's kind of a fun thing to do if you have friends that like to cook, to have them over, and let's all make egg rolls together.<s>
You can make some different fillings.<s>
You can put <B-Ingredient>shrimp</B-Ingredient> in them, or you could make vegetarian ones.<s>
You could put <B-Ingredient>carrots</B-Ingredient> in them.<s>
You could put whatever in them.<s>
Good.<s>
So, I'm going to roll up about six of these while I start heating up my <B-Ingredient>oil</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I've got <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>peanut</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> in the skillet, just three-quarters of an inch or so, to about 365 degrees Fahrenheit.<s>
Catch you on the flip side.<s>
Wait.<s>
There we go.<s>
Cowabunga.<s>
Once your oil is around 365, you want to carefully fry your egg rolls in small batches for one to two minutes on each side, until golden brown.<s>
Now, we're talking.<s>
Be careful not to fry too many at once because the temperature will drop, and you'll end up with greasy <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>rolls</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You'll also run the risk of over boiling your oil.<s>
Drain your <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>rolls</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Then, I like to put them in a bowl that's lined with a paper towel, sort of upright, so that the excess oil can drip off.<s>
They actually stay pretty warm this way.<s>
Egg rolls are done.<s>
What time is it?<s>
It's egg roll time.<s>
What time is it?<s>
It's time for egg rolls.<s>
Those don't rhyme.<s>
So, I've got here some oriental hot <B-Ingredient>mustard</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can find this in spice areas.<s>
Daisy, quit being such a bitch.<s>
You just mix up the powder with water to the desired consistency.<s>
I like mine a little bit thin so that it's good for dipping.<s>
Then, I've also got <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>sweet</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>chili sauce</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So, if you like this egg roll recipe, also check out my chimichangas for another delicious fried treat with a Mexican twist.<s>
I also did fresh spring rolls recipe a couple years ago that aren't fried, and they're way healthier and almost as delicious.<s>
With that said, let's give this a taste.<s>
I like this hot <B-Ingredient>mustard</B-Ingredient>.<s>
It's going to clear out my allergies.<s>
It's a fine crunchy <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>roll</I-Ingredient>.<s>
There you go.<s>
I hope you like this egg roll recipe.<s>
I hope you give it a shot.<s>
If you want printable recipes, they're always available at Hilahcooking.com.<s>
That's also the best place to reach me if you have an important question about a recipe, because I will be sure to see those questions.<s>
Visit me on Twitter, Facebook, Instagram.<s>
I'm all over the place y'all.<s>
I own the Internet.<s>
I'm inside the Internet.<s>
Bye.<s>
Baby, do you want <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>roll</I-Ingredient>?<s>
You like crunchies?<s>
Good catch, girl.<s>
Daisy's really good at catching stuff.<s>
You're so smart and clever.<s>
I love you.<s>
That's probably enough fried things.<s></transcript></transcripts>