[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="8" title="Fish Tacos Recipe |  Tacos De Pescado " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-LjKf4YxMk4" mode="non-automatic">
Hey dudes, I'm Hilah and today I'm Hilah cooking and remaking the second recipe video I ever did.<s>
That is Fish Tacos.<s>
Can you believe it's been that long since I ate some Fish Tacos?<s>
I mean, come on.<s>
So, this is a great summertime recipe.<s>
It comes together in a cinch.<s>
It's nice.<s>
It's refreshing.<s>
It's light so that you can keep your beach body figure.<s>
It's totally working on me.<s>
So I'm really excited to share it with you, especially because that old video, the sound was totally f'ed up, dudes.<s>
Time to get hoppin' on the Fish Taco toppin'.<s>
Taco Toppin' was actually the old Aztec name for this.<s>
So I'm going to update my slaw a little bit.<s>
I've got some <B-Ingredient>green</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cabbage</I-Ingredient> that I shredded up, <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>white</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>onion</I-Ingredient> that sliced, and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>jicama</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So this is a root.<s>
It's starchy.<s>
It has a texture like a raw potato, but it's sweet like an apple and mild.<s>
So it adds a nice little flavor to the slaw.<s>
I've got that in there.<s>
And then I'm going to add <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
This is a super duper simple coleslaw recipe.<s>
All we're going to use is <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>juice</I-Ingredient> to get it softened up to get that <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient> releasing <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>water</B-Ingredient>, and get it nice and tender so we can eat it raw.<s>
Everyone's on this raw diet thing.<s>
Whatever.<s>
But some raw vegetables obviously are good for you.<s>
Like salad.<s>
Like <B-Ingredient>celery</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sticks</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Like <B-Ingredient>carrot</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sticks</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So that's about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I'll get that tossed around with my tongs.<s>
You could use your hands also, nature's tongs.<s>
Use a bigger bowl than I did so you don't have to worry about it flopping out everywhere.<s>
So salt's coating everything.<s>
Now we're just going to squeeze in <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>juice</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And if you are be stricken by horribly high <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient> prices, you can use <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>lemon</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>juice</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Just don't tell anyone.<s>
I really expected more juice from that <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient>, since I paid 33 cents for it.<s>
Hopefully that was close to two tablespoons.<s>
We'll get that tossed around.<s>
Toss that salad.<s>
And then I'm going to add <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>cilantro</B-Ingredient>, or fresh coriander, if you are British.<s>
And I don't bother pulling off the stems for <B-Ingredient>cilantro</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I just chop it up really really fine because there's a lot of flavor in the stems actually.<s>
So I can see with my little eyes that the <B-Ingredient>cabbage</B-Ingredient> has already started to soften up just with that little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of motion in the ocean, so I'm just going to set this aside and work on some other stuff and just leave it at room temperature, and I'll show you what it looks like when we're done.<s>
You'll be amazed.<s>
You'll be like wow, you're a genius.<s>
For the <B-Ingredient>mayonnaise</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sauce</I-Ingredient>, this is an update, I've got <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>mayonnaise</B-Ingredient> here.<s>
I'm going to add some minced <B-Ingredient>chipotle</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>peppers</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So chipotle and adobo, they come in a little can, it's a dollar, and it's the adobo sauce that's sweet and slightly vinegary, but mostly sweet.<s>
And hot.<s>
There's smoked <B-Ingredient>jalapeno</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>peppers</I-Ingredient>, and then they're put in this <B-Ingredient>adobo</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sauce</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So whenever I get a jar home, I like to transfer it into a jar and keep it in the fridge, and then they'll stay like that forever.<s>
So they're pretty spicy.<s>
I'm going to start with <B-Amount>half</B-Amount> of one and just mince it up, and it pretty much just turns into a paste as you're mincing it.<s>
I'm just going to put all of it in there.<s>
I like it spicy.<s>
All minced up, it's about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>chipotle</B-Ingredient> in adobo.<s>
Plop that in with <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>mayonnaise</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Lick your finger, because who cares.<s>
I'm only cooking for myself and this guy, and he doesn't give a sh**.<s>
I'm going to add <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>juice</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit> of that.<s>
And I'm going to add <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>malt</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>vinegar</I-Ingredient>, which is really really good on fried fish.<s>
It smells vinegary, but it's nutty and sweet.<s>
Anyway, if you can't find this, then you can just add some more <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>juice</I-Ingredient>.<s>
It's just going to add some more tartness.<s>
But also it's nice because of the whole fish connection.<s>
Then we're going to mix this up.<s>
So the sourness of the <B-Ingredient>vinegar</B-Ingredient> and the <B-Ingredient>lime</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>juice</I-Ingredient> should balance out the heat of the chipotle pretty well, but if it's a little bit too spicy for you, I would recommend that you add <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>honey</B-Ingredient> or <B-Ingredient>sugar</B-Ingredient> to temper that heat a little bit.<s>
But this tastes pretty good to me.<s>
Thumbs up.<s>
So we'll just set this aside and start working on the fish.<s>
So, I haven't changed anything from the original recipe as far as the seasoning and the spices that I'm putting on it.<s>
So the two main things here are <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>cumin</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>seeds</I-Ingredient> and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>anise</B-Ingredient>.<s>
This is not star anise.<s>
It's just <B-Ingredient>anise</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>seed</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And it has a licoricey fennely flavor.<s>
If you can't find it you can leave it out, but it goes really really nicely with fish.<s>
And then whole <B-Ingredient>cumin</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>seed</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So those two.<s>
And <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>chili</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And when I say <B-Ingredient>chili</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>, me, personally, I just mean ground up ancho chilies, or <B-Ingredient>ground</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>up New Mexico chilies</I-Ingredient>.<s>
I don't mean commercial brand of <B-Ingredient>chili</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient> that has <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>salt</I-Ingredient> and all that stuff mixed into it, although if that's what you can find, and that's what you have in your pantry, that is totally totally fine.<s>
Please don't worry about it.<s>
A little mortar and pestle.<s>
You can use pre-ground spices if you want, but you know me, I like to make things hard on myself.<s>
So put our whole spices in and crush them up.<s>
Good.<s>
And then I'm going to add my <B-Ingredient>chili</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>.<s>
It's already ground.<s>
And <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>pepper</B-Ingredient>.<s>
What's life without <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>pepper</B-Ingredient>.<s>
You wouldn't have that song, Push It, for one thing.<s>
Mixed up.<s>
Now for the breading part, I'm just using some cornmeal.<s>
If you are in another country that's not the best country in the world, America.<s>
If you are in another country and you don't have cornmeal, you can use fine <B-Ingredient>polenta</B-Ingredient>.<s>
It's basically the same thing.<s>
We're going to add this to that, and mix it around.<s>
It's combined.<s>
Now we're going to do the fish.<s>
So, I do the fish last so I don't have to wash my cutting board between.<s>
I'm not getting raw fish juice on things.<s>
I'm using some wild snapper, but you can use pretty much any lightish fish.<s>
You could probably use <B-Ingredient>salmon</B-Ingredient> or something like that too.<s>
Any old kind of fish that you like.<s>
And I asked the fish monger if he could skin it for me, so these are skinless and boneless.<s>
So, I'm just going to cut them into pieces, maybe an inch wide by however long it is, so that usually ends up being about the right size to go into a taco.<s>
So you got your fish chunks.<s>
Now we're just going to toss them around in this cornmeal mixture just to coat it.<s>
We don't really need anything to help adhere the cornmeal, just the moisture from the fish will keep it on there.<s>
And you can do this fish coating part ahead of time too and just cover them and leave them in the fridge up to a couple hours and then it'll help the coating stick on better too.<s>
But you can leave them sit for awhile.<s>
So the fish is all coated.<s>
I'm just going to let it sit here in my little dish for just as long as it takes to heat up a skillet with <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>oil</B-Ingredient> in it and then we'll get to fry in the fish.<s>
Fish fry party.<s>
So you want to heat your pan up over medium, or medium high heat, and then add maybe <B-Amount>two</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoons</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>canola</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> or <B-Ingredient>corn</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> or <B-Ingredient>peanut</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient>, something neutral, with a high smoke point.<s>
Swirl it around like a lava lamp.<s>
Don't get all high and get distracted.<s>
And then you want to cook your fish in two batches.<s>
Cook the smaller pieces with the smaller pieces and the bigger ones with the bigger ones.<s>
And when you lay it in the hot oil, lay it away from you, just in case, so you don't splatter hot <B-Ingredient>oil</B-Ingredient> on your beautiful face and make Jesus very sad.<s>
So they'll probably just take about two to three minutes on each side depending on the size.<s>
And with thicker filets like this snapper, you might need to do more than just two sides and go ahead and get the sides, sides cooked as well.<s>
Once they're nice and brown on every side we can take them out.<s>
And when you break one open the inside should be flaky, like that.<s>
And these are super duper hot right now so you want to let them cool off for a few minutes, and while that's happening we can heat up our <B-Ingredient>tortillas</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Put some of that on there.<s>
Some of our <B-Ingredient>chipotle</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>mayo sauce</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So if you're interested, be sure to check out the original Fish Taco video for some really hilarious Fish Taco jokes.<s>
And also make sure to check out HilahCooking.com for this printable recipe and all of my recipes.<s>
And if you make this, please tag me on Instagram or Twitter and send me a picture, because I'd love to see that.<s>
Look at that.<s>
It's so gorgeous.<s>
So colorful.<s>
I did it again.<s>
You're welcome.<s>
Thank you for watching.<s>
Have a great day.<s>
Bye.<s></transcript></transcripts>