[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="9" title="Greek Pasta Salad  + Tour of My New House! " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jFs5PSdZ7u0" mode="non-automatic">
Hey Dudes I'm Hilah and today on Hilah Cooking, look, I'm in a brand new kitchen.<s>
So long orange countertops.<s>
Hello, a brand new house with white cabinets and lots of natural light and looks like rich people live here.<s>
So, I'm going to make some <entity type="Recipe">Greek Pasta Salad</entity> today.<s>
This is a great thing for all your summer time potlucks.<s>
Fathers Day is coming up might be a nice thing to take out for that and then after we make the recipe, I'm going to give you a tour of our new house and tell you a little bit about this watermelon that I ate.<s>
The first thing for the <entity type="Recipe">pasta salad</entity> is we need to cook <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> and now, one thing I've been meaning to talk to you all about, I've got about <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">quart</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> almost to a boil here.<s>
You really don't need to use like six quarts of water when you're making pasta.<s>
I wrote a big thing about water conservation on my website.<s>
If you want to go read some tips about how to save water because it's our most precious natural resource.<s>
I said that sarcastically but I mean it so, anyway, you need about <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">quart</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> to cook <entity type="Amount">two</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> or <entity type="Amount">1/2</entity> a <entity type="Unit">pound</entity> which is what we're going to do now.<s>
The reason that people tell you to use a whole sh** ton of <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> like that is so that the <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> doesn't stick together but as long as you're kind of standing here for the first minute or so while the <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> goes in and you can kind of stir it around a little bit and then it's not going to stick together.<s>
So I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity> to my <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity>.<s>
So, you basically just want to stir until it comes back to a boil which will take 30 seconds to a minute so you can put the lid back on for maybe 10 or 15 seconds to help it come back to a boil faster but don't walk off because it will boil over if you do that.<s>
So, once it's boiling and you want to set the timer.<s>
My <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> package said 9 to 11 minutes.<s>
I'm going to split the difference which is ten and then subtract two, so I'm going to set it for eight minutes.<s>
I did it.<s>
So, I've got my <entity type="Ingredient">green beans</entity> while that's boiling, I'm going to go ahead... you want to snap the little stem ends off these and I don't bother like snapping off the little string ends because I think they're kind of cute.<s>
So, once you've got all your <entity type="Ingredient">green beans</entity> snapped.<s>
Just chop them all into about one inch lengths.<s>
I'm going to set them in this little bowl.<s>
Get them the hell out of my way.<s>
Once our time goes off which is just in about two minutes, I'm going to add the <entity type="Ingredient">green beans</entity> and then let the <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">green beans</entity> boil together for the last two minutes.<s>
That's going to sort of blanch the <entity type="Ingredient">green beans</entity> and let the <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> finish cooking.<s>
Then you just want to drain the <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity> and the <entity type="Ingredient">green beans</entity> and give them a quick rinse with <entity type="Amount">some</entity> cold <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> You're not really trying to cool them off so much as you are trying to rinse off some excess starch so that they don't stick together.<s>
We're just going to leave those draining in the sink while I get the other stuff prepped up so I've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> fresh <entity type="Ingredient">parsley</entity>.<s>
I'm not going to be too anal about like not leaving any stems behind.<s>
No stem left behind.<s>
Just sort of pull off the big leaves and we're going to give it a rough chop.<s>
So, just sort of wad it up into a little ball and don't cut your fingers, and then I've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">Kalamata olives</entity> and I've already chopped up <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">sweet peppers</entity> and <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">tomatoes</entity> here, as you can see, You can buy presliced <entity type="Ingredient">Kalamata olives</entity> but I find that they get a little bit mushy so I like to buy the ones that are just pitted and whole and then I'm just going to cut them in half.<s>
Yeah, let's just cut them in half.<s>
That's easier for everyone.<s>
So then, we're going to work on the dressing so that's going to require <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">clove</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">garlic</entity>.<s>
Just get it minced up then in a bowl here I'm going to put this <entity type="Ingredient">garlic</entity>.<s>
See if I can do this.<s>
This is stupid.<s>
Ta-da.<s>
So I've got my <entity type="Ingredient">garlic</entity> in a large bowl, I'm going to add <entity type="Ingredient">olive oi</entity>l.<s>
About <entity type="Amount">two</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity> of that and then I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">white wine vinegar</entity>.<s>
You can use <entity type="Ingredient">red wine vinegar</entity>.<s>
You can use <entity type="Ingredient">cider vinegar</entity>.<s>
So I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">a couple</entity> of <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity> to this and traditional vinaigrette is three parts oil to one part acid like vinegar or lemon juice.<s>
I like mine a little bit more forceful.<s>
I like my vinaigrette to really take control so I'm going to do one to one ratio but feel free to adjust it a little bit according to your taste.<s>
Get that kind of mixed up then <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">black pepper</entity> of course and <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity> and the real kicker here, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">oregano</entity> and that's what makes it Greek.<s>
I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">a</entity> whole <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity>.<s>
Get that mixed up.<s>
Now let me go grab the <entity type="Ingredient">pasta</entity>, just dump that on in.<s>
I'm going to use a wooden spoon so I don't hurt you're delicate ears.<s>
Sweet viewers.<s>
So I toss this all around then we can add our other vegetables and whatever else you want to add to this.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Cucumbers</entity> may be good too.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Red onion</entity>, whatever.<s>
Have a pasta party.<s>
So this is why too, when you're making pasta for <entity type="Recipe">pasta salad</entity> you want to undercook it just a tiny bit, take it off the heat just moments before it would be tender enough to serve hot because then once you cool it off and mix it with your vinaigrette it's going to absorb some of that vinaigrette and it makes it way delicious if it has some room to absorb some of that.<s>
Also, it would be really soggy if you cooked it completely before you did that.<s>
So then once everything is mixed up together, cooled off, then we're going to add the last ingredient which you can totally omit if you are a vegan or you are <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">parmesan cheese</entity> instead too and that's <entity type="Amount">some</entity> crumbled <entity type="Ingredient">feta cheese</entity>.<s>
Just <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity>, <entity type="Amount">couple</entity> of <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity> there we have it.<s>
We're done.<s>
So, you could serve this right now at room temperature or you could refrigerate.<s>
It lasts in the fridge for couple of days.<s>
Let me get a fork because I'm going to eat it.<s>
So if you like this recipe I also did a potato salad last year so that's also really great.<s>
I did coleslaw, like a vinaigrette coleslaw that's also good because it doesn't have mayonnaise so like if it's sitting out in the sun, it's not going to get all poisonous on you, kill your children.<s>
Da**it, that is good.<s>
Good as hell and I hope you try it.<s>
Okay, than there you go.<s>
Thank you so much for watching.<s>
Printable Recipes are always at hilahcooking.com.<s>
But, hey, guess what, remember what I told you?<s>
House tour time.<s>
I'm going to take this pasta and show you around the house.<s>
Let's go.<s>
Here's the kitchen pretty much saw that already.<s>
Okay then after the kitchen there is this sort of nook, we've got our bar, some booze in it, some random sh** that we haven't figured out what to do with and then all of my cookbook collection.<s>
You want to see my favorite cookbook?<s>
It's this one.<s>
It's the one I wrote.<s>
Okay, then here's the living room.<s>
More books, some other artwork we don't know what to do with and then look.<s>
World's largest dog bed.<s>
The dogs really enjoy this couch.<s>
Chris and I usually just end up sitting on the floor because they are such space hogs.<s>
Just kidding.<s>
We all cuddle together and it's really cute.<s>
Okay and here we went from about 1700 square feet to about 1200 square feet which is a way more manageable number, I think.<s>
Bathroom, so we're selling our old place and we're just renting this place.<s>
This is the baby room.<s>
Guess what, guys?<s>
I lied, I did not eat a watermelon.<s>
I'm having a baby because I had sex.<s>
Okay, so having sex makes you have a baby.<s>
So kids, listen up.<s>
We're having a boy.<s>
Fortunately, the room was already painted this nice turquoise color and had these window treatments that totally matched our Pee Wee Herman poster.<s>
Oh, also, the landlady left the crib for us.<s>
So we were like, "Dude, free crib.<s>
" We have to get this place.<s>
And, oh, prenatal yoga bolsters.<s>
We're going to be doing so prenatal yoga that.<s>
Okay, this is where the magic happens.<s>
This is where the baby got made.<s>
Not in this room but on this bed This is also where Daisy can often be found and this is why, got wooden floors and we had to get rug over here so that Daisy could get some traction so she could jump up on the bed in the morning and wake us up.<s>
She was just slipping and sliding.<s>
It was so sad and cute.<s>
Okay, so let's go look at the back yard and see if we can see the dogs doing something cute.<s>
Look how big my butt's getting.<s>
Guys.<s>
"Boom, boom, boom.<s>
" Looks like a Godzilla butt.<s>
Well, that rug is slippery.<s>
Be careful.<s>
Oh yeah, so it's got a big old deck.<s>
Hey guys and it came with a swing set.<s>
Guys go be cute for the camera.<s>
Go run around and play.<s>
So yeah, basically, there's our new house.<s>
We moved because we're having a baby and I wanted a nicer neighborhood that we could like walk around in so this is really good.<s>
We're still in Austin but its way more central and there's like parks and little shops we can walk to, so I don't have to load up the car every time I want to take the baby somewhere and it came with a swing set and a crib.<s>
So how can we say, no.<s>
Okay, that's it.<s>
New house new kitchen baby stuff.<s>
If you want to follow along on my maternal journey.<s>
My "ma-journey.<s>
" You can go subscribe to Hilahtalking.<s>
I'll, post some updates over there and thanks so much for watching I'll see you guys later hope you try the pasta salad.<s>
I know the dogs like it.<s>
I do too.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>