[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="14" title="Healthy Recipes- Death By Garlic Roasted Asparagus " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sngFbBW01q8" mode="non-automatic">
[music] I'm Natalie Hodson, and I'm here in the bodybuilding.com kitchen today, showing you how to make one of my favorite side dish recipes and I call it Death-by-Garlic Roasted Asparagus.<s>
And it's a really good side dish to go with <B-Ingredient>chicken</B-Ingredient> or tilapia and it even works great as leftovers.<s>
I put it in a Ziploc bag and use it the next day.<s>
For today's recipe, this is a pretty simple recipe though we only use a few ingredients and I have everything here.<s>
We are going to use fresh <B-Ingredient>asparagus</B-Ingredient> and use about <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Unit>pound</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>asparagus</B-Ingredient>.<s>
They usually come in bundles like this.<s>
And <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>asparagus</B-Ingredient> is a little bit more thin and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>asparagus</B-Ingredient> is a little bit thicker and it doesn't really matter, you can use either.<s>
We're gonna use fresh <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> does come pre-minced but I prefer the fresh <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I think it makes the recipe taste a little bit better so we're gonna just buy the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>clove</I-Ingredient> like this.<s>
And then we are going to use <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient> and just make sure that you get the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient> and not the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>salt</I-Ingredient>.<s>
They look real similar.<s>
They come in the same size of container but the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>salt</I-Ingredient> has quite <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> added to it and the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient> is just straight <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And then we are going to use extra virgin <B-Ingredient>olive</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> and we're just gonna use <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit> of this, so just a little bit.<s>
And then <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>pepper</B-Ingredient> and I have fresh <B-Ingredient>ground</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient> but you could--if you don't have the fresh ground, just regular <B-Ingredient>black</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient> will work as well.<s>
And then we're gonna bake everything on a cookie sheet and line it with aluminum foil and I already went ahead and pre-heated my oven to 400 degrees.<s>
So the first thing we're gonna do is line a cookie sheet with aluminum foil.<s>
And this just makes for easier cleanup so that way, when you're done, all you have to do is take your aluminum foil out, throw it in the trash and it's really easy to clean up.<s>
Okay.<s>
So then we're just gonna set this aside.<s>
First, we just take our bunch of asparagus, take off the rubber bands and then just rinse this, make sure that gets nice and rinsed and then what I do is I like to keep the asparagus still in the bunch formation and you want to cut off the bottom about inch of the stalk and--because the bottom of the stalk is really tough and it doesn't taste good, it's not fun to chew.<s>
So what I do is I just take a kitchen knife and I just cut it all at once so it's really fast and easy.<s>
And you just cut off the bottom of the asparagus and then what you're gonna do is evenly distribute the asparagus over the cookie sheet.<s>
The next step is mincing the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>, when it comes in a clove, has an outer shell kind of like an <B-Ingredient>onion</B-Ingredient> and so what I usually do is just cut the end off just so it's easier to peel and then there's some stuff, I just throw that away and then there's--if you can see inside, there's a lot of little what are called <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cloves</I-Ingredient>, so you just take out--this recipe calls for anywhere from four to six <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cloves</I-Ingredient> and it just depends on how much <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> you like.<s>
I usually--I like a lot of <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> so I err on the side of six but if you don't like <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> as much or as strong, then you could just do four.<s>
And another thing too, if you don't like <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>, you could actually make this recipe even without the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> and just use <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>pepper</B-Ingredient> and it would still taste pretty good.<s>
All right.<s>
So I'm just gonna set this aside and we have <B-Amount>six</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>cloves</I-Ingredient> here.<s>
Now these still have kind of an outer papery shell on them.<s>
And so you need to take that off.<s>
So what you do is you just put the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> clove flat on your cutting board, take a knife that has kind of a wider flat edge and you just go like this and you just hit it and what it does is it kind of crushes your <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> so it makes it really easy to pull but it actually, I found out, this one has two cloves inside of it so I'm gonna do that again.<s>
And then it makes it really easy just to peel off the outer shell.<s>
So I'm just gonna do this for all six.<s>
I really like--I eat asparagus a lot.<s>
I really like eating asparagus and one thing that a lot of people don't know is that asparagus is actually really high in folate and a lot of pregnant women are recommended to take folic acid which is the supplemental form of folate and so asparagus is really good for pregnant women too.<s>
And asparagus is also a natural diuretic so if you feel like you're holding on to some water weight or if you're feeling kind of bloated, sometimes eating some asparagus can help your body rid itself of some of that <B-Ingredient>water</B-Ingredient>.<s>
All right.<s>
So your hands are gonna feel kind of sticky when you're doing this.<s>
That's okay, that's normal.<s>
One, two, three, four, five.<s>
All right.<s>
So since that original clove actually was two cloves inside of it, I'm gonna set one of them to the side.<s>
And then I just throw all the paper stuff away.<s>
Sometimes it sticks to your hand a little bit.<s>
I just rinse my fingers.<s>
All right.<s>
So we're gonna mince the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> really finely and I'm just gonna do that with a knife.<s>
We already took the outer shell off, the papery part, and I just put my hand on the top and I kind of bunch it together and then I just mince it like this and I just keep pressure on the top of the knife and I just kind of keep going back and forth and then what I do is bunch it back together and just keep mincing, just like this.<s>
And you just want it really pretty finely minced because you don't want anybody to take a big old chunk of <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>.<s>
They might not appreciate you for that.<s>
So this is looking pretty good.<s>
I would say that's about as finely minced as you want.<s>
So I'm going to rinse my hands.<s>
And then I'm gonna set this aside for a second.<s>
And then what we're gonna do is put the <B-Ingredient>olive</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> on.<s>
So I just use <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>olive</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Now this recipe makes four servings and so each serving is gonna have less than <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>olive</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So I do--I like to measure it out because sometimes I have a tendency to use too much <B-Ingredient>olive</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> so I just like to measure it out that way and know I'm just using a tablespoon.<s>
And I just slowly drizzle it over.<s>
Just like this.<s>
And then what I'll do is I'll take either a spatula or even just the measuring spoon and I'll just sort of go like this just to make sure that the <B-Ingredient>olive</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oil</I-Ingredient> doesn't get wasted on the bottom of the cookie sheet and that it gets over all the asparagus.<s>
So then what we're gonna do is we're gonna take the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient> so if you have thicker stalks you might not need quite as much <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>, but if you have more stalks, you might need a little bit more, if you have thinner stalks.<s>
So I just sprinkle--this is <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> and that didn't even cover half of it so I'm gonna do it again, <B-Amount>3</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoons</B-Unit> equals <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Unit>tablespoon</B-Unit>.<s>
So just gonna keep sprinkling and it looks like I'm gonna use the whole tablespoon for this recipe 'cause remember this is called Death-by-Garlic Asparagus so it's gonna be pretty heavy on the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And if you don't like <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient>, again, you can use lighter <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> or even no <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> and just use <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>pepper</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And then I'm gonna use some fresh <B-Ingredient>ground</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient> and this, I just kind of eyeball it.<s>
You could probably use about <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit>, maybe <B-Amount>2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoons</B-Unit> and if you don't have the fresh ground, just regular <B-Ingredient>black</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>pepper</I-Ingredient> will work.<s>
And if you wanted to add <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>, you can, but I usually just don't add extra <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And then what I'm going to do is take my knife and kind of scoop the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> onto the knife and then just evenly distribute this over the asparagus.<s>
So I just take my finger and I just go like this.<s>
Now if you were to eat a raw <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> clove, your eyes would probably water up and your mouth would probably start to burn because it's really spicy but when you roast it like we're gonna do on 400 degrees, it kind of takes some of the spiciness out of the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> and it makes it have more of the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> flavor that we're used to.<s>
So that's it.<s>
All I'm gonna do is rinse my hands and then stick this in the oven at 400 degrees and I'm gonna cook it for 15 to 20 minutes.<s>
So what I'm going to do is put this in the oven, set the timer for 10 minutes.<s>
At 10 minutes, I'm gonna take a spatula and just kind of rotate the asparagus a little bit to make sure that one side doesn't get burnt or crispy and then I'm gonna put it back in the oven anywhere from 5 to 10 minutes.<s>
And if it starts to look too brown, then I'll pull it out at 5 minutes.<s>
Usually I cook it for the full 20 minutes.<s>
All right.<s>
So we just took the asparagus out of the oven.<s>
At 10 minutes, we checked the asparagus, just rotate it, make sure it wasn't burning and then at 15 minutes we checked it again and what I like to look for is to make sure that the <B-Ingredient>garlic</B-Ingredient> starts to kind of turn brown a little bit and actually at 15 minutes ours looked good so you can cook it 15 and up to 20 minutes but we took ours out at 15 minutes.<s>
And then what I do is I just use my spatula and put the asparagus onto a plate.<s>
Just like that.<s>
And this asparagus is a little bit thinner which is probably why we were able to take it out at 15 minutes too.<s>
If your asparagus is a little bit thicker, you'll probably want to go closer towards the 20-minute mark.<s>
And this looks really good.<s>
I'm gonna clean up this super easy.<s>
All I do is fold up the aluminum foil, throw it in the trash and this looks really good so I'm gonna try it.<s>
And you can serve this warm or you can serve it chilled as well.<s>
Tastes really good.<s>
You can find this full recipe on the page below and for more recipes and nutritional tips, keep checking out bodybuilding.com.<s>
[music]<s></transcript></transcripts>