[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="20" title="Healthy Recipes- Pumpkin Protein Bars " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BfLDYuVmb84" mode="non-automatic">
Hi.<s>
I'm Jamie Eason.<s>
Welcome to the bodybuilding.com kitchen.<s>
Today I'm gonna make my Pumpkin Protein Bars.<s>
I know I've been making a whole lot of different types of protein bars, but I don't want you to get burned out so I've got this brand new one.<s>
This one actually makes a larger portion than the 8x8 we've been using so we're gonna get a bigger Pyrex dish this time.<s>
I've prepped this by spraying non-stick spray.<s>
It's a 9x13, and I've also preheated the oven to 350 degrees.<s>
So this one's easy because it's all in one large bowl.<s>
See, first we've got <B-Amount>2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cups</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>oat</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>flour</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Again, <B-Ingredient>oat</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>flour</I-Ingredient> is just ground up oatmeal, and you can buy it at the store in the healthy section.<s>
You can make your own by grinding it in a coffee grinder or in a blender.<s>
So I'm just gonna put that in.<s>
Two cups.<s>
And then I've got <B-Amount>2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>scoops</B-Unit> of a <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whey protein</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use any flavor that you like.<s>
For me, I just look for the fewer ingredients the better 'cause then it's healthier and usually it tastes a little better too.<s>
So <B-Amount>2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>scoops</B-Unit> of that.<s>
And then I'm gonna start putting in all of the flavoring ingredients.<s>
I've got <B-Amount>2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoons</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>cinnamon</B-Ingredient>, <B-Amount>1 1/2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoons</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>ground</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>ginger</I-Ingredient>, <B-Amount>1/2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>cloves</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Cloves are pretty strong, but I think that's really what gives this its flavor.<s>
So then we've got <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>baking</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>soda</I-Ingredient> and <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>baking</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient> and then <B-Amount>1/2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
For my sweetener, I'm actually adding 1/2 cup of <B-Ingredient>Xylitol</B-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use the <B-Ingredient>brown</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sugar</I-Ingredient> blend.<s>
You can use the regular.<s>
I actually like the brown sugar blend for this recipe a lot, but you can't always find it.<s>
This one is just the regular half cup of <B-Ingredient>Xylitol</B-Ingredient> so put that in.<s>
I'm gonna mix up these dry ingredients really well.<s>
Okay.<s>
And then to this I'm gonna start adding the wet ingredients.<s>
You can mix these in separate bowls if you like, but it's really not necessary so I'm just gonna put it all right in the same bowl.<s>
First thing, I'm gonna start with <B-Amount>four</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use the liquid <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient> if you like.<s>
I used regular, real <B-Ingredient>eggs</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I kinda like those better for baking, but it's up to you.<s>
Then I'm gonna add <B-Amount>1/2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>almond</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use whatever kind you want.<s>
You can do regular <B-Ingredient>milk</B-Ingredient>.<s>
You can do <B-Ingredient>rice</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Whatever you'd like, but I like the <B-Ingredient>almond</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient> so 1/2 <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of that.<s>
And then to that I'm gonna add one <B-Amount>4</B-Amount> <B-Unit>ounce</B-Unit> of the <B-Ingredient>baby</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>food applesauce</I-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use regular <B-Ingredient>unsweetened</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>applesauce</I-Ingredient> at home if you have that.<s>
Put that in there.<s>
It comes out to probably about 1/4 cup if you're gonna us the jar at home.<s>
To that I'm gonna add my pumpkin.<s>
I've used a whole <B-Amount>15</B-Amount> <B-Unit>ounce can</B-Unit> of pumpkin for this so you can use as little or as much as you want.<s>
I really like mine really pumpkiny so I use the whole entire can.<s>
Make sure, too, that you pick the raw pumpkin and not the pumpkin pie mix that's loaded with <B-Ingredient>sugar</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So put that in.<s>
Then my final wet ingredient is just <B-Amount>2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoons</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient>.<s>
So I've got all of those in.<s>
You can use the whisk if you like, but I don't wanna make a mess so I'm just gonna fold it all in with my spatula.<s>
Okay.<s>
Starting to come together.<s>
And for this recipe, you can use nuts or you can do it without nuts.<s>
I'm gonna put some walnuts in it.<s>
I really like pumpkin and walnut together.<s>
So I've got it all mixed up.<s>
I've already put 1/2 cup of <B-Ingredient>walnuts</B-Ingredient> in a little baggie.<s>
So the reason I've done this is because I didn't buy the crushed up kind.<s>
I'm gonna actually crush these myself.<s>
So I like to buy the ones from the bin.<s>
Usually they're a little bit more fresh than the ones that have been sitting on the shelf for a while.<s>
So I just put them in a bag.<s>
You can grab anything you like.<s>
I like my little rolling pin.<s>
Just sort of crush them a little bit.<s>
If you're worried about adding too much fat to your dessert, you actually don't have to mix them in.<s>
You can put it all together and just maybe sprinkle half on one side or just lightly sprinkle them on top.<s>
I like to mix mine in because I like there to be nuts in every bite, but it's totally up to you.<s>
That's pretty good.<s>
Getting there.<s>
Maybe a little smaller.<s>
Alright.<s>
Now I'll just dump these in.<s>
Now the difference though--if you make it with or without nuts--with nuts, you're looking at probably about 67, 68 calories.<s>
Without nuts, you're looking at under 50.<s>
It's about 47 calories.<s>
So it's totally up to you, but the fat isn't that different and the amount of protein really isn't that different.<s>
It's like about 4 grams of protein a bar.<s>
This makes 24 bars, by the way.<s>
So I've got that all mixed in.<s>
And I'm gonna get my dish ready and just pour it in the pan.<s>
Okay.<s>
I'll get it all spread out.<s>
Now this one you wanna bake it for about 30 minutes I would say, but it's totally up to you.<s>
Some people like the bars a little bit more soft, and some people like them a little more cooked through.<s>
I suggest that if you're traveling with these, definitely keep them in the oven a little bit longer 'cause you want them to hold up.<s>
Put these in the oven.<s>
Bake it for about 30 minutes.<s>
Think that's right.<s>
And then we'll check it in about 30 minutes.<s>
Always make sure when you're baking that your oven rack is like usually in the middle.<s>
If it's too close to the heating element on the bottom, it'll burn.<s>
And if it's too high up, it'll take forever to cook so we will check on it in about 30 minutes.<s>
Alright.<s>
The timer went off.<s>
Let's check our bars.<s>
Alright.<s>
They look good.<s>
I'm pretty sure these are done, but if you wanna make sure you can stick a toothpick in it.<s>
If it comes out dry with no wetness or anything, it's pretty much ready.<s>
So I'm gonna let these cool and then we'll come back, cut them, and I'll show you how to wrap them up.<s>
Okay.<s>
Our Pumpkin Protein Bars are fully cooled so I'm gonna cut them up.<s>
Let's see.<s>
We've got--it's gonna make 24 squares so I'm gonna make 3 cuts lengthwise and 5 this way.<s>
Alright.<s>
Scoop a few of these out.<s>
They look really good.<s>
You can see some of the <B-Ingredient>nuts</B-Ingredient> in there.<s>
And then I'm gonna wrap up the rest.<s>
Show you how I wrap them when I travel.<s>
Be sure to store these in a cool place like the frigerator because if you leave them just out on the counter or not in your cooler, they'll actually spoil.<s>
There's no preservatives or anything in these.<s>
I do them by twos.<s>
I just place two on the saran wrap, fold over the one end, and roll it over, and then fold in the edges and--it's pretty simple.<s>
Okay.<s>
I'm gonna finish up wrapping up the rest of these.<s>
For this recipe, you can check out the link below.<s>
And if you wanna check out other recipes and articles, just visit bodybuilding.com.<s></transcript></transcripts>