[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="25" title="How to Make Watermelon Cookies " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1wzOj6YUpHE" mode="non-automatic">
Hi, I'm Eugenie.<s>
Today I'm making watermelon cookies.<s>
Those cookies are really easier than you think and it takes only several everyday ingredients.<s>
It's basically a French biscuit sable recipe which is a slightly modified version of my French coffee sables.<s>
First, in a mixing bowl, I will add in <B-Amount>½</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of softened <B-Ingredient>unsalted</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>butter</I-Ingredient>  and <B-Amount>1/3</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>granulated</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sugar</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And whisk until light and fluffy.<s>
And add in <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolk</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Remaining <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>white</I-Ingredient> will be used later.<s>
And add in <B-Amount>½</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of pure <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>extract</I-Ingredient> and <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <I-Amount>generous</I-Amount> <B-Unit>pinch</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And whisk until homogenous.<s>
Now sift in 1 and <B-Amount>¼</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cups</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>all-purpose</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>flour</I-Ingredient> and fold until combined.<s>
Now divide the batter into half.<s>
First I will make red dough by adding some red food color and kneading.<s>
This method is called 'fraiser' and you can mix without making the dough too tough with this method.<s>
And make a 2 inch diameter cylinder and cover with plastic wrap and store in the refrigerator.<s>
Then take out half of the remaining vanilla dough and cover with plastic wrap.<s>
Then roll out.<s>
And chill in the refrigerator.<s>
And with the remaining dough make a green dough.<s>
Today I'm using both matcha, Japanese green <B-Ingredient>tea</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>, and green food color.<s>
And again I will knead until homogenous and cover with plastic wrap.<s>
Then roll out.<s>
And chill in the refrigerator.<s>
Now bring red dough and <B-Ingredient>vanilla</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>dough</I-Ingredient> to working surface.<s>
Measure the size of the red cylinder and cut out the sides of the vanilla dough  and roll out to lengthen it.<s>
And place the red cylinder over it and carefully roll up like a yoga mat.<s>
Now cut off the surplus vanilla dough.<s>
Repeat with the green.<s>
By the way the cookie dough should be cooled a little before rolling, otherwise the dough will be too soft and won't hold the shape well.<s>
Now cover the dough with plastic wrap and rest in the refrigerator for about 2 hours.<s>
Now make a colored sugar.<s>
In a plastic bag, add in <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of green food color and spread with fingers to avoid any green color lumps.<s>
And add in sugar and mix well until homogenous.<s>
This is a simple way to make colored sugar at home.<s>
And make a sugar bed.<s>
Then break <B-Amount>one</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>white</I-Ingredient> and brush on the cookie dough.<s>
And roll the dough over sugar bed.<s>
French sable cookies need sugar decoration.<s>
And slice the dough half inch thick.<s>
And arrange the disks on a cookie pan.<s>
And decorate with toasted <B-Ingredient>black</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>sesame seeds</I-Ingredient>.<s>
I love the mixed flavor of <B-Ingredient>green</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>tea</I-Ingredient> and sesame seeds.<s>
But if you don't have sesame seeds, use mini chocolate chips.<s>
Again I will chill the pan in the refrigerator for about 20 minutes  and then bake in the oven preheated to 350 degrees F. (175 C) for about 10-12 minutes.<s>
Out of oven immediately cut the cookies in half and let cool for 5 minutes.<s>
Then transfer to a wire rack.<s>
Voila!<s>
Watermelon cookies.<s>
They are so so cute!<s>
I love them.<s>
It's French sable cookie style, so there are little cracks.<s>
Bon appetit.<s>
My dad really like sable cookies and I also love those crumbly biscuit sables!<s>
You can find all the cookie recipes in my playlist.<s>
And don't forget to check out my summer giveaways: Nespresso Espresso Maker video contest and a blender for ice blending Twitter giveaway.<s>
The links are in description box below.<s>
Thank you for watching.<s>
Bye for now.<s></transcript></transcripts>