on
1880 kicked in hi
I'm using me do you need rain both today
and making remain below thank you I key
it's totally healthy
and very yummy unique theory cake tried
a
for this recipe you'll need
good pitcher grain rice prices the maker
optional
for me season Miami can the tuna
sold sugar
I'm here pepper bed a bell pepper Carol
World Bank Oconee and
where the cap each first in a mixing
bowl
and adding he found himself during peak
and the tuna one people's canal
finely chop the onion and to be able to
consult my on me
and needs to combine pieces for my
keep getting and don't forget the season
8 papar
you can use scrappers famine Fallon
if you're a big scary and hop on will
come Oni
in three people spend up by 15 acre
and 1 tablespoon of sugar and 1 teaspoon
of salt
and stir to combine can prolly
into them put the short grain rice
temple to me
be careful not to break mine I
cool 2 cups now rice to be and p1 now me
clean too was the first thing he said
be great then he could be bi airlines in
fine and
and one vegetable each ball 3
tablespoons up
finely chopped red bell pepper three
cables been so finely chopped carrots
crumbles I with three Boyle at new
york's
three candles burned up finely chopped
broccoli
and 3 tablespoons up finely chopped the
red cabbage
I used to play into the broccoli carrot
& Metcalf be cheaper
batter peace thank you can and color and
to that now for the curious how on
yellow bell pepper were yellow people
who read each for yellow mines
any other ideas hun leave a comment
below
but then for our Rainbow cops
make a rainbow in a class first the
violent and
allele add tuna salad pick in that
year's then green
yellow personally don't like this plan
to make it fun
our means and bad
and for sushi rice cake make another
mainly no comp
lined with plastic wrap this then I
started beating a bad
and the repeat the process
fun on healthy brain Bocock
and when both were here I skate
on D beautiful the collar sought the
species so even by Dean
on FB and love it
also lead to how be domain leveraged
through FL not fearing
so make sure to use your favorite the
lesions
billion you can find the recipe down in
the Description box
and please give me two thumbs up you
want to see more
favorite he he is and this week I have
Facebook giveaway the price the Sun
already any
my China peak is number one best-selling
Amazon that come
an bubble tea cops to enter these people
wait just like
that people we post at feet some people
can find the much at usually
and it can be pretty expensive for such
a small amount
and these giveaways perfect for Mike
Green keep property no
so don't forget to find me
at beefed-up okay that's it for today
thank you for watching bye for now
them in them