pitted am Highland and how it looking
like I'm in a brand new kitchen so long
orange carrot top
hello friend house with white cabinets
and
not natural light and looks like rich
people in here
so I'm gonna make some Greek pasta salad
today this is a great thing for our
summertime potlucks
father's Day is coming out maybe nothing
to take out for that and then
after we make the recipe and I give you
act or our new house
and tell you a little bit about this one
around the eight
way
that
thinker hosokawa doesn't need to cook
sound pasta
now one thing I've been in touch about
am
I've got about a quart of water almost
to a boil here you really don't need to
use like
six quarts water when you're making
pasta Arabic thing about water
conservation
online website if you want to go reading
tips now has a wire because it's our
most precious natural resource
an I said that sarcastically but I mean
it so anyway
me about a quart of water to cook two
cups the past hour half a pound
which is what we're gonna do now them
reason that people tell you to use
whole shit on water like that is so that
the positive thing together
but as long as your class standing here
for the first minute or so
while the pasta goes then you can stir
it around a little bit
then it's not gonna stick together some
absence of my water
so basically just last yr
until it comes back to well it'll take
30 seconds to a minute
you can put the lid back on for maybe 10
or 15 seconds to help it
come back to work faster but don't walk
off because it will while or if you do
that
so want well I want to set the timer my
pasta package said nine to 11 minutes
spot the difference which is 10 and then
subtract two to set it for
eight-minute edit
guess I've got my dreams while that's
boiling
comes gonna go ahead and when a snap to
but also demands of the is
I don't bother like snapping of the
little string and because I think
they're kinda cute
so once you've got all year green beans
snapped
just travel all India about one-inch
link now
said Amanda Salam Paul getting the hell
outta my way
once our timer goes off which is just in
about two minutes man and the
green beans and then let the pasta and a
green beans boiled together
for the last two minutes that's gonna
sorta blanche to green beans and let the
pasta
finish cooking then you just wanna drain
the pasta and green beans and give them
a quick grounds for some cold water
not return a call of so much as you are
just trying to rinse off the excess
starch they'll stick together
miners leave those training and think
why did this other stuff
kinda propped up said got some fresh
parsley
I'm not gonna be to an all about like
not leaving any stands behind no stomach
when I'm
to serve pull off two big leaves we're
gonna give it a
rough chops just sorta wat up into a
little ball
and don't put your fingers and then I've
got some kalamata olives and already
chopped up some
sweet peppers and some tomatoes here as
you can see you
you can buy a pre sliced kalamata olives
but I find that they get a little bit
mushy
so I like to buy the ones that are just
petted and Hall and then was gonna
cut in half yeah let's just cut in half
that's easier for everyone still
me I'm you work aren't that dressing so
that's
gonna require clove garlic this
commitment up then
in a all here gonna her
this Carla see if I can do this and
to got my girl
in a large bowl of Madea olive oil
about 2 tablespoons that nah nah nah son
white wine vinegar you can use red wine
vinegar you can use
cider vinegar someone at a couple to
listen to this
and traditional vinaigrette is
three-part well to one part accent like
vinegar and lemon juice
I like mine a little bit more forceful
like me then a great to really take
control so I'm gonna do
one to one ratio but feel for you in
just a little bit according to your
taste
attack next to her and some
black pepper port salts
and the real kicker here
some haranguing now and that's what
makes the creek
nada whole teaspoon get that next start
now let me to grab the have to
just down that on i Mees wouldn't spend
China hurt your delegate years sweet
viewers to and talk with all around
19 at are other vegetables and
you know whatever else you want to add
to this cucumbers many
here red onion whatever
have a pasta party so this is why to
when you making pasta for pasta salad
you wanna under could get just
a tiny tiny bit take out he just moments
before it would be tender enough to
serve hot
because they want to call it off annex
you're gonna credits can absorb sound
that
vinaigrette and a makes it way too much
as it has some room to absorb some that
also it would be
release on the issue could it completely
before you did that
so then once everything's mixed up
together it's cooled off
organ and the last thing I want you to
limit you are being in or you can use
some parmesan cheese and sent to you
and that some crumbled fettuccine just a
little bit
couple table stand there we have it
weren't done
to get service right now at room
temperature or you can refrigerate it
and last in the fridge for a couple a
days metaphor
can only eat it actor if you like this
recipe also did a potato salad
and last year so that's also a really
great and
call larger than a great cole slaw
that's also good because I am an answer
sitting out front row out time and again
I like poisonous on you know
kill your children, mmm-hmm mmm-hmm
demand as good as good as hell and I
hope you try it
okay nader things went rushing print for
us these our own at Highland looking dot
com
but hey guess I can wait on you house
wartime
gonna take this pasta share on house let
up
could jump very much Saturday has an app
in a kitchen
there is this partner ok
Darbar anderson et some random shit that
we haven't figured out what to do if and
then all of my cookbook collection
USD my favorite Burke if this time on
Iran okay and injured 11 a.m.
after more black other
artwork we don't know what to do and
then like world's largest dog bed
the dogs really enjoy this capped
Christian Angelina just sitting on the
floor because there are
such space hugs asking me out
held together to make it okay here so we
went
pram about seventeen square feet about
1220 am which is away more manageable
number I think
and bath
home so we're selling our own place who
is renting this place
am my baby round
cath right diet I'll I had
I did not hear watermelon having a baby
okay
having sex makes you have a baby del cid
with a nap though we're having a boy
fortunately
room re-painted mister boys color and
and had these window treatments calling
Master P behind master
oh and also the landlady left the
compressed re-elected program
we have to get this place and prenatal
yoga bolsters
you can simply million does your with
agents and now keep an eye out back
okay best is with the magic happen
this is where the baby get made not in
this room but on this
bed this is also where Danny
can often be found and this is why says
that wooden floors
and we had to get around over here so
that he could get some traction
she generally then anything except
toward
used it let's go look at the back end
the week ended up doing something here
accompanied by left giving
guy bone bone bone bone
playing godzilla but well
on the slippery be careful yes I'm
standing on deck
hey I had and I can't think that
as good here for Kamran coram play
to get basically
they're running out and we moved because
we have a baby
and on a nicer neighborhood that when
they walk around and this is really good
mister not stand for it
when our central like parks animal
shop definitely want to sell you like
the Harvard me someone am an account
things at my crib
acronym okay that house kitchen
I'm maybe that if you want to follow
along
on my maternal journey I'm journey
you can't go subscribe to pilot talking
ok
hola post abdomen and and
thanks so much for watching I'll later
haven't read about talent know the dog
like it