Eugenie Kitchen
Hi, I am Eugenie.
Today I am going to make "Soufflé à la vanille",
vanilla Soufflé.
Soufflé, it puffs up in the oven
and it falls down so quickly.
So, there is a famous French saying,
“Le souffle n’attend pas,
on attend le soufflé.”
That means le soufflé doesn’t wait for
us,
we (the guests) wait for le soufflé.
But today we will not wait for le soufflé,
we will make
the soufflé.
For this recipe, you will need:
1 tablespoon of unsalted butter (14g),
1 tablespoon of all-purpose flour ( 10g),
1 /2 cup of milk (120 ml),
1/2 teaspoon of pure vanilla extract,
2 tablespoons of caster sugar (30g),
2 eggs, and a pinch of salt.
First,
with butter at room-temperature,
brush the ramekins.
Brush from bottom upwards.
This will make the soufflé to rise evenly.
Then, with caster sugar coat the ramekins.
And shake out any excess.
And set aside.
On medium heat,
add the butter in the sauce pan
and melt it.
Add in the flour
and with a wooden spoon
stir for about 1 minute.
In the microwave,
I made the milk hot.
Out of the heat,
gradually add hot milk,
and stir until smooth and combined.
Back to medium heat
stir constantly until it comes to a boil.
Remove from the heat.
The texture should be like this.
This is white sauce.
Now add in salt and vanilla extract
and stir until combined.
Separate the egg white and egg yolk.
Then add in the egg yolks one by one into
white sauce
and stir to combine.
The sauce pan is still warm,
so pour the sauce into a separate bowl
to prevent unwanted evaporation.
And set aside.
Now, whisk egg whites.
It is not mixing.
It is incorporating the air
like this.
Keep whisking until firm peaks form.
Add gradually sugar while slowly whisking.
Keep whisking until soft peaks form.
This is French meringue.
It takes about 20 minutes with hand.
Then, add about one third of the French meringue
into the white sauce
and whisk until homogeneous.
Then, pour all white sauce into meringue
and whisk until just combined.
Now, spoon the mixture into ramekin.
Run thumb around inside of the rim.
This will help the soufflé to rise straight.
Bake at 390 degrees F (200 C.) for 12 to 15
minutes
or until very well risen.
Immediately serve on a plate.
And dust with confectioners' sugar.
soufflé...
Risen straight and evenly.
And it has golden brown top and pale yellow
inside.
This is classic French soufflé.
It is very delicate and hot mousse.
Thank you for watching!
Bye for now.