many Italian island today on highly
cooking or making McDonald
knock-off full efficient watch this is
alway better than McDonalds range and
and I'm gonna tell you if the most are
the hot guy and then it and here's a
hint
have to do to Jesus pass
well home
that
way to start out
dour anything fish anything to Lafayette
try to get like as
big ever fully as you can anything said
sorta firm
will do well I caliber a cod and
we're just gonna try to cut it into
square ash shape so that it looks a
little bit like
down the nets and half way back saffir
this
little interesting shaped thing here
sorry kind of
starting to split their summers gonna go
ahead and cut it
diamono and then
trim of like the little pointy
and bet just cannot trust squared off a
lover
and you can still awake you know cook
these in in them
when I like fissionable or something but
and
they want gonna say much because they're
not perfect so then these lines are cut
in half these ones coming on
mommy so ashamed to have my language
there right now I'm
bad grammar so they're not exactly
square but they're
rectangular and thats a type a square
guys than others but the memorable here
all the little pieces same
army to tiny and then squeeze San
oranges
over awesome said skin like brighten up
the flavor a little bit we're just not
this marinated in lemon juice
for about 10 minutes in that time we can
make our
McDonald's Corp of tartar sauce to make
sure our little fishies get covered
you don't have one man you could use are
a little bit like white wine vinegar
something arson tarragon vinegar
would make it a fancy French
filet of fish Philip French not be
something else entirely okay I'm and get
set up
and will make aren't her shots while we
wait on us man
obviously tires are starts with a man is
based now if you would like
a more fancy time to turn it off I have
a recipe for
one with parsley and capers and Carl
Icahn
others other shit on a website if you
want to do that but this
is what I think is closest to
the McDonalds tartar sauce which really
just can t spectacles said is at a
little pinch of salt
man and a woman in white paper this is
my own fancy attach
sure it's not the real thing but it has
trended and then
to make it McDonald the this is just
some
diced up like hamburger dole fleiss's
just mentioned really tiny
in a adding a little bit of that pickle
juice in there champ
so down plaid and
down there and then some super
min step why and as well just like the
10-year
you can chop it better I'm a magician
with a knife
you could use a food processor if you
have bad skills
and with nixon something
that argument to the devil oh that
reminds me so the story
have the flatfish as the sky in Ohio
that had
franchise when McDonald's for stars
franchising he was making any money
during Lent
because his a really eighty-nine percent
catholic or something so he like all
that
wanna mcdonnell himself and he was like
looked on
sorry I mean rhyme I'm not making any
money over here in Ohio and make a fish
sandwich data for an abrupt
route I was like I don't think so buddy
then
he tasted it and he was like wow this is
the best
sandwich ever not better than my
hamburgers but you have my permission to
put it on your menu
and centers restaurant and then it went
nationwide like the next year
cell there you go time to read the
donuts
I mean the fish I mean don't okay so I
drained
the lemon juice of I've the fish fillets
and down
and some now because no alcohol
something and as your body good
just enough to cover too many wasted how
drink that later
my passion so just get them all
in a rather hang out time
and then for the breading part what I
dan is a mashed up some moisture
crackers here
until they're very very fine these ROIs
to crackers
they taste like saltines but they look
like or stirs I don't know either
con that but that's a good enough reason
I think I like to use these one
i'm reading stuff instead of saltines
because one there cheaper than saltines
by like
a few sense but I am NOT free will
beeotch and also they're already in tiny
pieces so they break up faster so I did
was
puts on them into this little
the tough baggy and Krishna
until they're fairly fine most of them
are powder ash and a min ago
but add a little bit of plain dry bread
crumbs to that to you
if you want to just use breadcrumbs
that's fine
but I felt like the crackers kinda gives
it and better
coming cell just like that together
and thus the crackers are you have salt
on into the night nanny salts and esters
it's enough not salt with just what's on
the crackers
10 hours new standard milk crackers not
crackers
plate the
there
okay ac if fishing areas and I want
their coated you want them in the fridge
for at least 10 minutes
up to two or three hour she can make you
had had a little bit
and that's going to help that cutting it
here said on Friday doesn't just like
fall off into that
trying well Easter so I'll see that
tenants
to fry the fish and got just under about
a half inch
peanut oil here you can use canola oil
and destroy whatever
enough stuff like that and got heated up
to about 350
if you don't have a thermometer you can
just throw in a little read crime like
this
just across and saw lights not not
peeing that sizzling sound
and will are fleas and and you remember
when I
I'm cut them out I ended up with two
that were a little bit thicker
and tuner little bit then are so the
thicker ones honest they're gonna take a
little bit longer Kirk
cell math come easier sometimes just to
do them
together to thank you once again there
and then if anyone's that basically we
just got cookies for
I met on the far side and Phil be nice
golden brown
what mother doing under two minutes or
so on a second time
until that's going around by then inside
should be
perfectly cooked and you to fall off and
flaky and mores
like a fish sandwich
here we go
cell
just check out the second plane usually
brown slower than the first sessy
still prepay of felt like them but maybe
another minute or so
if you wanted to make the lower-fat you
can also totally
thank them just to the breading ass
spray it with a little better you know
spray or something
and bake it on it like a tray with iraq
like this by many as the spring training
but you can just take it on here at 4:15
for about 15 minutes it's not going to
get like
as selectively golden brown ft youth but
it will be christie and
curt and I'll be much healthier then
this
for mcdonald's lavish now
shitty in a new cluster
let and easy to stand up straighter okay
they were getting our talc and and to
apply to them
to string it on a rack over here and
I'll go ahead and Friday my
other fish while others are calling on
my grey a couple of
hamburger buns to soften him up in can
nice and squishy like the ones at
McDonalds
okay okay I just finished which is the
first in a wheelchair
I've got a little fun here at like I
said I just economic way for literally
10 seconds
and it's nice employable on warm when a
top it with American cheese on
mcdonald's
their skimpy little bastards mail you
have a place that she is
what the hell's American about that so
we're gonna go ahead and do a whole
slice
thank you very much and then top with
the law dish
paddy let see this one month period and
at big big hefty blob have your tartar
sauce
they do like this match their I know cuz
I just a line the other day
and then there you go gorgeous
flair fish sandwich for you then of
course you and put the top on
unit if you like this recipe also check
out my chick-fil-a knock off if you like
fried meat
sandwiches and you don't want to watch
that one
then you can watch my chicken fried
steak video now
the United the same here somewhere
cracker crest
you can just see him graciousness
delicious right meets for the win right
people
okay humidity ok
room
that's what's supposed to happen at
little poop mmm-hmm
ship dress in the image yes
year United alright
may go prominent player fish way they're
going down
haven't read happy let please leave a
comment below and visit me at hello did
not come for printable recipe sing and
later thanks for watching by
contractors hope
a nap
well