Hilah: Hey dudes. I'm Hilah. Welcome to Hilah
Cooking. Today, I have a
very special guest who is the pizza expert
and he's going to
show you how to make homemade pizza at home.
All right, so
here's Brandon and him and his brother are
from Detroit.
Brandon: Yes.
Hilah: And you all just started a pizza trailer
called Via 313.
Brandon: Correct.
Hilah: Because 313 is Detroit's original area
code.
Brandon: That's so smart.
Hilah: Good. All right, so we're going to
make pizza today. You all
specialize in Detroit style, so tell me about
that.
Brandon: Well, Detroit style is made with
blue steel pans to make on a
Sicilian styled pie, but we put the sauce
on top, caramelized
cheese all the way around, and we get four
squares out of it.
Hilah: God, sounds yummy as hell.
Brandon: And it's so good.
Hilah: All right, but I don't have a pizza
pan. What do we do?
Brandon: We're just going to make it happen
with what we got in the
kitchen.
Hilah: Sweet! I love that. Awesome, let's
make some dough.
Brandon: All right.
Hilah: All right, so we got just a few ingredients
here. It's not like
it's that complicated it seems like.
Brandon: It's pretty easy.
Hilah: Okay, cool. So you all do use bread
flour.
Brandon: Yes.
Hilah: That's the key thing, right?
Brandon: Yeah, a lot better than all-purpose
flour. Most people buy all-
purpose flour and you don't get the same rise
out of the dough.
Hilah: Okay. And then we've got some dry yeast.
Now is this what you
all use in . . .
Brandon: In the trailer we use active dry
yeast, but at home instant dry
yeast is a little bit better. It's a little
user friendly.
Hilah: Okay, all right. So this recipe is
a little modified from what
they actually do so that we can make homemade
pizza at home.
Brandon: Yes.
Hilah: All right. So I've got my stand mixer
here and I've got a bread
hook on this so we can use this for kneading.
If people don't
have that, they can't just knead it by hand
I guess.
Brandon: Yeah, be old school like that.
Hilah: Where did I get muscles?
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: So we're just going to put all this
stuff in and turn on the
thingy.
Brandon: Yeah, that's pretty easy.
Hilah: Cool. So we got our yeast and we're
going to put it in with the
flour. Stop me when I hook up.
Brandon: I'll slap the shit out of you.
Hilah: Okay, cool. Salt and sugar. And then
. . .
Brandon: So far.
Hilah: So far, so good.
Hilah: Okay, cool. And then oil in there too?
Brandon: Yeah, did all right so far.
Hilah: Thanks professor. Okay, and then I'm
going to put this in here.
Okay, and then what is it?
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: And turn this on?
Brandon: Yes.
Hilah: Okay, so this . . . Well, now it'll
just go and it'll start to
kind of like . . .
Brandon: Yeah, it'll start to ball up and
you'll be able to tell once it
becomes one . . .
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: . . . etc. It's very loose right
now obviously.
Hilah: All right. So we'll just let it go
for a few minutes and then
we'll come back and take a look at it.
Brandon: Yeah, I would say five to six minutes
is pretty standard.
Hilah: Okay. Yeah, it's already changing,
cool. Okay. So it's been
like five minutes or something.
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: Look at that.
Brandon: Yeah, it should be nice on the hands.
It shouldn't stick to
your fingers too bad. If it does, just throw
some more flour in
there.
Hilah: Yeah, we added maybe a couple extra
teaspoons I guess.
Brandon: Yeah, just make it easy to handle
for yourself.
Hilah: Okay. Now we've got some flour on our
bitch as they call it in
the restaurant.
Brandon: Yes, bitch flour. Yes, that's the
fancy words for it.
Hilah: It's just flour on the counter top.
Brandon: This recipe should make enough for
five or six pizzas.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: You can cut it.
Brandon: Yeah, and [inaudible 00:03:36].
Hilah: Pizza party! So I'll do six.
Brandon: Make it four.
Hilah: Make it four, okay.
Brandon: So it'll be a little bit thicker.
Hilah: Okay. Wow, it cuts really nice.
Brandon: Yeah, it's got a nice feel to it.
Hilah: And then what do you just kind of . . .
Brandon: Well, you can ball it like this.
Pull it over like that. You
pull the sides and I'll pinch it at the bottom,
and then make
sure you cap it like that. That's what they
call it.
Hilah: Kind of like pinch it.
Brandon: Yeah, and then the other nice restaurant
ball.
Hilah: Ooh! Cutsie tootsie.
Brandon: You do another one. I'll do another
one.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: I think yours actually looks nicer
than mine.
Hilah: I'm a girl.
Brandon: That's what happens.
Hilah: So then we'll put these in the fridge
and that's an important
thing that you all make sure to let it kind
of rest over time.
Brandon: Yeah, I like to give it a good 12
or 24 hours to rest, gives it
a nice flavor.
Hilah: Okay, cool, so start this a day ahead
people.
Brandon: Yes, plan ahead.
Hilah: Okay. Well, this one's not quite as
pretty. Let's use this one.
It's the prettiest.
Brandon: Yeah, thank you. I did that.
Hilah: I noticed. And then I'll just kind
of, I guess, a little oil in
here.
Brandon: Yeah, throw a little oil in there
so it doesn't still too bad
and it'll be easier to handle tomorrow. It
won't . . .
Hilah: Stick to the . . .
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: Okay. And keep it from getting like
a dry out skin here.
Brandon: Yeah, obviously covering it so it
won't dry out too bad, but
Hilah: All right. So then we'll put this in
the fridge and then I'll
get you back here tomorrow.
Brandon: I'll meet you tomorrow.
Hilah: Okay, cool.
Brandon: Maybe, I don't know.
Hilah: Well, if you're not drunk. Okay, so
here we are again. Nice
outfit.
Brandon: Thank you.
Hilah: He did not spend the night here.
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: Okay. So we got our raised doughs.
Brandon: Yeah, and what you want to do is
kind of make love to it. Don't
go in there and bang it all out. Just the
more you mess it up
the harder it'll be.
Hilah: Am I messing it up?
Brandon: You're destroying it.
Hilah: Oh, God. I am. I'm sorry.
Brandon: There you go.
Hilah: Okay. Because we don't want to like
bust all the air out,
right?
Brandon: No, well again, the easier it is
to handle right here.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: So what you want to do is make a
little crust. So imagine a
pizza on your table.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: Come on, get with it.
Hilah: Okay. I was going to watch. I don't
make it.
Brandon: No, make a little crust.
Hilah: Okay. Flip it over.
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: And then . . .
Brandon: Keep doing it.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: Now, flip it over again. All right.
You can push out the gas in
the middle, but don't mess up the crust that
you started.
Hilah: Okay. Yours looks better than mine.
Brandon: Now use your knuckles to stretch
it. Just pull it apart and
then you can [inaudible 00:06:10] . . .
Hilah: Oh!
Brandon: Ah, geez!
Hilah: Party foul. Pizza party foul.
Brandon: Yes, you can stretch it about [inaudible
00:06:20] apart like
that. Put your hand back and stretch it. Put
your hand back,
just pull it apart with your knuckles like
that. There you go.
That ain't going to tear on you.
Hilah: Okay. This pretty cool.
Brandon: Yeah, I think this is the most intimidating
part that people
get a little freaked out about making pizza.
And if it does tear
on you, just pinch it together and there you
go.
Hilah: Okay. Just patch it?
Brandon: Yeah, just patch it together.
Hilah: You did that on purpose . . .
Brandon: I did that on . . .
Hilah: . . . to show us how to fix it.
Brandon: Yeah, exactly.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: That's what I tell people.
Hilah: Cool.
Brandon: Keep stretching with your knuckles
until you get about a 12
inch pie. I think yours is pretty good actually.
Hilah: Yeah, it's not [inaudible 00:06:56]
round.
Brandon: Let's destroy it, so we can be done
with it.
Hilah: It's the pizza expert, okay?
Brandon: Yeah, I'm done with it and so that's
good.
Hilah: Okay. We just don't need one anyway.
Brandon: That's good, yeah.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: Because I'm not hungry. All right.
We can use that.
Hilah: Okay. So now we put some toppings on.
Brandon: Yeah, so let's go ahead and put a
little flour on this. Most
people don't have these at home.
Hilah: Right.
Brandon: You can use just a cardboard box
and throw a little flour on
the cart. I'm not hungry.
Brandon: Geez! A fucking shit show over here.
So no matter what you do
it's going to lose its shape and form. So
once you get it on
your cardboard box or if you're fancy and
have a [inaudible
00:07:40] at home just pull it back out and
restructure it to a
nice round size. I won't keep saying pie because
most people
here in Texas don't call it a pie.
Hilah: Right. Yankee.
Brandon: There it is.
Hilah: Just kidding. Welcome Yankee.
Brandon: I don't have ten years underneath
from some [inaudible
00:07:57] Yankee.
Hilah: Okay. Wow!
Brandon: That's a good start right there.
Hilah: That looks awesome.
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: Okay. So we'll get some sauce and cheeses.
Brandon: Yeah, I don't know where it's at.
Hilah: Oh, you know what? I made sauce.
Brandon: Where is it? There it is. It's a
little easier if you put it in
the center.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: I put a pretty good mound in the
center all the time and just
kind of swirl it out into the crust. You should
be able to see
where your crust was.
Hilah: And I can see it on mine, yeah.
Brandon: Yeah, a little bit. If you have an
imagination just make it
happen.
Hilah: So we don't want to like saturate it.
Brandon: No, just give it a good . . . And
sometimes it's better to put
a little bit up at the top because it'll all
kind of bleed
through the center once it starts baking.
Hilah: Oh, okay. A little heavier on the edges.
Brandon: So I like to put a little . . . Yeah,
a little heavier on the
edges especially because the crust tends to
dry out a little
bit.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: And then just let it kind of bleed
through, through the center.
Hilah: Cool.
Brandon: So that's the beautiful saucing.
Hilah: Awesome. And then the cheesing happens
next.
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: All right. We got our moz.
Brandon: Yeah, we'll do it together.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: This is a whole milk mozzarella.
It bakes up a little bit
nicer. It's got a little bit higher fat content
than like a
Kraft, a little moister cheese that you'd
get at . . . you know?
Hilah: Like pre-shredded kind of stuff.
Brandon: Yeah, if you want to be cheap. It's
like a buck more a pound,
but you'll taste the quality. It's already
got a nice salt
content so it'll pull the mozzarella flavor
out of it.
Hilah: Yum.
Brandon: Again, kind of the same with the
sauce. With the cheese you
want to put a little bit more around the edges.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: Not hit the crust, but let it kind
of bleed through. It'll all
melt towards the center. That's pretty good
right there.
Hilah: Cool. So we got our moz, now we get
our pepps.
Brandon: Yes.
Hilah: Cool. And this is some kind of . . .
Brandon: These are natural casing pepperonis.
This is what we use back
in Michigan and we're trying to bring a little
flavor back to
Texas from Detroit. These will shrink up,
cup and charr. We call
them grease cups back at home.
Hilah: Mm! I love that kind.
Brandon: Yes, but you don't find it around
here too much though.
Hilah: Cool.
Brandon: Just whatever you want to do.
Hilah: Just get it on there.
Brandon: Who cares?
Hilah: Jesus.
Brandon: Whatever. There it is.
Hilah: Show is over.
Brandon: Here. Just put some so it's not on
the crust though. But for
real, these will melt, cook up nice, so whatever.
It doesn't
have to be pretty because they'll do their
own thing.
Hilah: All right. Let's put it in the oven.
Brandon: That's beautiful. So again, we're
using our fancy peel from the
restaurant or the trailer. We have a stone
in here. It's
preheated about 550 degrees. If you give it
a good shake, again,
if you're using a pizza box at home, you could
use a little bit
of flour on the box and just kind of give
it a good shaking on
there, make love to it, and let it do its
thing. It should take
about ten minutes and it should be ready to
go.
Hilah: Okay, cool. If people don't have a
pizza stone, what can they
use?
Brandon: A pizza stone, you can use just a
regular aluminum sheet pan.
This cooks up real nicely. You'll get a nice
crisp on the bottom
or as you said we could use a cast-iron upside
down, make a mini
personal pie.
Hilah: A smaller one.
Brandon: Yeah.
Hilah: Cool.
Brandon: But stone works the best. They're
only about 15 bucks.
Hilah: Awesome.
Brandon: And a local art shop.
Hilah: Voila! Awesome. Okay.
Brandon: Now you're cutting it now so go ahead.
Hilah: I have to cut it?
Brandon: Yeah, cut it in eighths, cut it in
half.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: Just, you know . . .
Hilah: My girl muscles are tiny.
Brandon: Put those mashed potatoes into it.
Don't do that. All right.
This is sad.
Brandon: Forget it. So we'll cut it in half.
Hilah: Let's have a man do it.
Brandon: Yes.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: I can't guarantee you get a . . .
Hilah: So not like back and forth and sawing
it.
Brandon: No, don't do that because you'll
have 18 different pieces out
of that.
Hilah: Okay.
Brandon: So this is what we have here.
Hilah: Cheers.
Brandon: Beautiful, cheers.
Hilah: Yay! Mm.
Brandon: Everything is good except for the
sauce. I don't know what
happened.
Hilah: Oh, my God. My mom did it. That was
weird.
Brandon: I don't really know what happened
with the sauce, but the
cheese, the pepperoni, the crust, perfect.
Hilah: Dude! This is awesome.
Brandon: The sauce is . . .
Hilah: Wow! Dude, pizza party!
Brandon: You guys can buy Ragu at the store
or whatever.
Hilah: He's funny. Anyway, I'm going to be
having a pizza party for my
New Years. What are you going to be doing?
Thanks for coming on
the show Brandon, pizza face.
Brandon: Thank you for having me and my beard.
Hilah: No problem. You should have a beard
net really. There's hair
all in my pizza.
Brandon: Yeah, this is a hairy pizza.
Hilah: All right. Bye! Thank you for watching.
Brandon: See you.
Hilah: See you.
Brandon: Warm up.
Man: That's great.
Brandon: All right. I'm ready.