yeah well now I'm picking today have a
very special guest here the pizza expect
ain't gonna show you
how to make money on hey
and I have read a from his right yes and
young
started and p2 trailer
yes car yet country correct just a
one-day and t20
a hats here so smart get yeah
weird make UK ya special-interest
tell me about that %uh short sales made
with her depends made in Detroit sales
then bloopers the a-bands
that sir make Amazon itself by but we
put a
the sauce into caramelized she's %uh
where around and a
via Foursquare yeah
so good
okay fan always hours gonna make it
happen
well yeah kissed lol thats how much
making them
our okay yeah just read it here
I like that happen thanks very easy okay
also be out to eat bread flour
yes keep right yet about an all-purpose
flour
you by all-purpose flour same raisa
okay and then went back dry yes
now I'm this way on we can ensure that
we use active dry yeast
but at home and some traces little bit
better
Salo user-friendly okay axle is asking a
lot higher
what the actual yet so that we can make
how many
yeah Afghanistan here and I friend
dumbass a week you back from eating
people have added
yes yeah Girls Aloud I'll
source gonna also and I'm
company yeah it's pretty easy saari
and other farm stop me when I'm
hahaha such a day okay cool
saucer tired
and him
the IRS number thanks Professor
Anna on okay this nara
okay
weren't yet hands-on
yes yeah
not just like here
at a soccer ball up to built our becomes
one so today
thank you and
back
yeah I would say fat chicks yet ready to
go
okay I finance or something
yet contact yes to be nice and shouldn't
state you're going to bed
yes some clower there yeah and collected
yet
masters make it easy to handle or so
okay now
get flower are fish is a columnist
lower yessir Betsy works for fire in
Harrah
this year should should make an effort
by a six pieces
okay I'll in kinda okay yet
and up
thank you or okay feel a bit better
okay petrocelli yes this is dennis
get less feel to it and but
you can ball like this pollen over
full-size intention about
and make share care
something college yeah and many have a
nice restaurant
in
thinkers actions lesson
I'm anchor anderson et
so than welcome represent an important
email
action let rest yeah like to give it
it to our site for hours to rest is a
nice flavor
okay calls today had people
yes plan ahead I S let you decide
KS there thank you editor and I was
happy
here they're a little oil on their side
and stick to bed
and easier to handle smile said
here keep again I need right now yen
Yemen I was the cover so mantra to
better
asthma French an army
I meet tomorrow okay maybe walking at
up yeah
makeup back and I
he did not tonight yeah okay yeah
they're
irate down yet which one it was kinda
make make love to her
go in there being a dallas more you were
Maceda are be see thanks here's
her I am okay
we don't like but I and I'm
China you know again easier to handle
right here
so whatcha gonna do star make a little
crushed
some Asian appeaser I'm here
detail meh
yeah I was just out hot sale made
Michael Cera's now
I to shut the gas in the mail but on
this the Krusty
started now using not cause a stretcher
his hola %uh geez I
special a whole a
a handbag fashion
men spar knuckles
and playing an attacking here
as I think this the most intimidating
higher people
developer it's a and if it does care
Anya
you know better together in okay a
passion yes at yeah
had except have to help people
construction
enough to speak about to expire fingers
not yeah
yeah I'm done
that so that's good okay we'll give you
money that's good
yeah okay as an honors it and
at user okay now a help them about yeah
sauce a.m. the flower nurse
most will have these home you can use
car or bus
okay and all of our K
funny show
sir
once no matter what you do it's colors
shape and form so
once you get it on your car for boxer if
you fancy him feel at home
just a letdown restructures to
a nice round size upkeep Sam
Packers people here check system right
yankee
there it is just kidding welcome yeah
ten years old and has been charged am
Saturday
that Ostara yeah okay
hit box kaya an hour
oh yeah there's laser
a center okay pretty good Center
scanner swell it out across
should be able to see way across
worse here love it
a few an imagination a.m. yeah
likes actually Nana's committed
and and sometimes better but a little
better to
at all currently through Center answer
a.m. okay
so here little yeah here on the edges
especially is Prestons and rather okay
site at least 30 percent
cool that's that's them beautiful sauce
house hey there
are my here all that together it's all
know
mozzarella picks up a little bit nicer
excalibur higher fat content and
like a craft long moisture cheese that
you get it to
in a like pressure yesterday gonna be
cheap but
just buying a 9 talk about more power
but
a taste for quality charting that nice
all contents and an apology
mozzarella player out of it a
again can same the sauce at the cheese 1
element more around the edges
okay that the crust but you know but
Kambli
through you know at all not towards a
senator
and that's pretty good right there
lawsuit am I not know that our pet
yes yes columnist kinda international
casing pepperonis movie news
second miscarriage and rail player back
to Texas from Detroit
these will shrink up Cup in Shire the
congress cups peck at home
mile-and-a-half yes those but you don't
find it around here too much so
well you know but everyone do just just
gonna get it on air
he hath other it is says over
air on has
you know but some so it's not dress a
for babies will not
a cook up nice so whatever it doesn't
have to be pretty cuz I'll
from are bank I love put another that's
beautiful
so again reason our attic PO restaurant
trailer be astonished here Trisha
of I 50 degrees to give it a good shake
again if using a pizza box at home his
little bit lower
on the box and I just can't can a good
shaken down there make love to it and a
but I do its thing should take about at
Ms
ash year ago okay caught people are
happy to start in the news
%uh peacetime I mean you can use just a
regular aluminum
she and this comes up real nice a good
nice Chris from the bottom
are or as you said we can use a cast I
am
upside down make a little bit are many
personal I hear
call but a stone like the best on about
15 bucks
I to local our shop
wallach
okay and you can announce yeah
yesterday's cut in half here
I me for those mashed potatoes into it
shunted a said Canada
a yeah and
yes i knt tonight back
or and now I'm tonight shell 18
pieces out there texas is what we have
here
cheers uggs
him mum
Andrews good example is awesome I am
don't look at all disaster
she have a running across for to you
pasta sauces Wow yeah I T
regular at the store whatever them
him funny and a man to be happy
for many years what are you doin
make Cheyenne be Bay
thank you for having me a beer no
problem yeah that was a reason
im II by you
yes but
home
on
warm-up think
right on right
do