I'm Natalie Hodson, here
today in the bodybuilding.com
kitchen showing you how to make
a recipe that I make a lot of
mornings, and it's my
Blueberry Protein Pancake.
This is a really good recipe.
If you're getting tired of the
same old egg whites and oats.
This uses the exact
same ingredients.
It just mixes them
into a different way.
I know there's a lot of protein
pancake recipes out there, but I
like this one because it uses
all whole foods and it tastes
really good.
These are all the ingredients
that we're gonna use for today's
recipe.
We're gonna use 6 egg whites,
and 1/2 cup of old
fashion oats.
I like the old fashion oats
better than the instant oats
just because they're a
little bit less processed.
The instant oats have actually
been cooked and dehydrated to
make them cook
faster, and these haven't.
They've just been rolled.
We have 1/4 cup of blueberries.
You can use fresh or frozen
or you can substitute it for
raspberries or strawberries.
We have 1/2 cup of
unsweetened vanilla almond milk.
And just make sure that when
you get the almond milk, you're
getting the
unsweetened vanilla kind.
I like the Almond Breeze brand.
It's 40 calories,
has no sugar in it.
Also, if you wanted, you
could substitute milk,
but I prefer the almond milk.
And then we have 1 teaspoon
of baking powder.
This is just to help the
pancakes rise a little bit.
Two packets of Truvia.
This is to make them
a little bit sweeter.
I have 1/2 cup of
unsweetened applesauce
and just a dash of cinnamon.
And those two items we're gonna
save 'til the end and use it as
a topping on top
of the pancakes.
So for today's recipe, I'm
actually gonna use a blender to
mix everything together.
And I'm gonna start with
my liquid ingredients.
Gonna pour in my almond milk,
and then I'm going to
do my egg whites.
And I'm just gonna crack
these right into the blender.
Now some people just throw their
yolks away into the trash can.
I actually like to put mine
in the garbage disposal, and I
found that out the hard way.
I used to just throw my yolks
into the trash can, and one day
I came home and my house smelled
really bad and I couldn't figure
out why.
And it's because I left the
yolks in the trash can for too
long, and so now what I do is
I'll just put them right into
the garbage disposal.
Some people like to feed the egg
yolks to their dog, and I guess
that helps with their coat and
makes it a little bit shinier.
And this is a really good
breakfast recipe if you have
kids.
I have a 2 year-old
and he loves this recipe.
We eat it a couple times a week.
And it's a really good way to
incorporate some whole grains
into their diet, and the
blueberries has some really good
antioxidants.
Another thing you can do is you
can make these in bulk on the
weekend, and then freeze them.
I think they taste a little bit
better fresh but you definitely
can freeze them.
And when I do that I just put
them in a Ziploc bag and then
when I wanna eat them, I
stick them in the microwave
for about a minute.
Alright.
So we have 6 egg whites.
Then I'm just gonna add my oats.
And I'm gonna save the
blueberries until we're actually
in the griddle.
I'm gonna add my baking powder.
I'm just gonna do
a dash of salt.
It's probably about
1/8 of a teaspoon
if you were to measure it.
And then two packets of Truvia.
If you want to eat the pancakes
without any applesauce on top,
you could add a
third pack of Truvia.
It would make your pancakes
sweet so you wouldn't need to
add the applesauce on top.
And then I'm just gonna
blend this really fast.
Alright.
I'm quickly gonna turn my
skillet on to about medium-high
heat.
Then I'm just gonna spray it
with a little bit of non-stick
cooking spray.
And then I'm just gonna take my
batter and--this recipe makes
two pancakes.
Two pancakes is one serving so
usually just kinda eyeball it.
And put about half of the batter
in the skillet, and then I'm
gonna take half of my
blueberries and just drop them
in the top.
You can blend these, the
blueberries, in too if you want.
I've done that before, but I
think it tastes a little better
this way.
Makes them a little bit juicier.
So we're just
gonna let this cook.
Usually you can tell they're
ready to flip when there's
bubbles in the
center of the pancake.
So I went ahead and
flipped the pancake.
We've been cooking it about
1 to 2 minutes on each side.
And sometimes the first pancake
doesn't flip quite as well as
the second pancake, and it's
because sometimes in the blender
the egg whites tend to kinda
stay at the top and the oats
fall to the bottom, but this
one turned out pretty good.
So I'm just gonna take the
pancake and put it on my plate.
I'll flip it I guess.
That side's not quite as pretty.
And then I'm gonna go ahead
and put my second pancake in.
I'm just gonna blend it for
just a second to get everything
shaken up.
Gonna spray my
pan with the spray.
Then I'm just gonna pour
the rest of my batter in.
Make sure to get
all those oats out.
And I'm gonna add the
rest of my blueberries.
And we're just gonna let it cook
about 1 to 2 minutes per side.
You know it's ready to flip
once the edges look like they're
cooked all the way through and
there's bubbles starting to form
in the center of the pancake.
Alright.
So we are done
cooking our second pancake.
I'm gonna go ahead and
put it on the plate.
Oops.
As you can see,
this is a lot of food.
This is another reason I
like this recipe is 'cause it's
really great way to start the
day with a nice hearty meal.
And then--the pancakes are
really sweet on their own I
think, and so a lot of times
I'll actually eat these even
without any applesauce on top.
You can use sugar free syrup if
you want, but I prefer to stay
away from that just because it
has a lot of preservatives in
it.
So sometimes if I want a little
extra something on top, I'll use
some unsweetened applesauce.
Just make sure you get the
applesauce that says no sugar
added or unsweetened or if you
read the ingredient list, the
only ingredients are apples,
water, and maybe ascorbic acid
which helps keep the coloring.
So I'm just gonna go with this
half of a cup of applesauce.
I'm just gonna pour it on top.
Sometimes I like to put
a little bit underneath.
And then I like cinnamon so I'm
gonna put a dash of cinnamon on
top.
You don't have to do that
if you don't like cinnamon.
Sprinkle a little cinnamon
on top and there you go.
You have a really
good breakfast.
One serving is 2 pancakes, and
each serving has 6 egg whites,
and 1/2 a cup of oats,
some blueberries,
and some almond milk.
So to get this Blueberry Protein
Pancake recipe, you can check
out the link on the page
below, and continue to go to
bodybuilding.com to find all
of my other recipes as well as
nutritional information, workout
programs, and motivation.