[music]
Hi, I'm Jamie Eason and today
I'm in the BODYBUILDING.COM
kitchen and I'm showing you
how to make my
chocolate peanut butter
protein crisps.
In a previous video I showed you
how to make my honey, almond,
protein crisps.
But now we're gonna use two of
my other favorite ingredients:
chocolate and peanut butter.
So, let's get started.
The ingredients for our
chocolate, peanut butter,
protein crisps are three
cups of a crispy brown rice,
we've got 1 cup of whole oats,
a scoop of a vanilla whey
protein powder, we've got
some crushed almonds,
some peanut butter
right here, some cocoa,
and some brown sugar,
and somewhere around here
I've got my honey.
That's all you're gonna
need, so let's get started.
To start I've put 3 cups
of the crispy brown rice.
And just so you see.
You can have a reference.
This is the crispy
brown rice I used.
It's gluten-free, organic.
It's got very few
ingredients in it.
It does have a
little bit of sugar.
It's natural sugar.
It's got organic molasses
and evaporated cane juice.
But it's 2 grams per serving.
There's 3/4 of a
cup in a serving,
so you've got less than 5 grams
of natural sugar in the whole
entire recipe, so not bad.
It makes 18 servings.
So, we've started with
that, put that in.
And then I've got my
cup of whole oats.
I'm gonna put that on top.
And then I'm gonna add
1/4 cup of crushed almonds.
So, if you don't
have crushed almonds,
you can actually just take
your own almonds, you know,
scoop out 1/4 of a cup of
those and just beat them
with a rolling pin.
You can use the back of
a pot, whatever you have.
And then, on top of that I'm
gonna add 1 scoop of
vanilla whey protein powder.
I kind of sprinkle that on
top, spread it around a bit.
Now, do not mix this up.
We don't want to make all of
the protein powder settle
to the bottom.
So, I just give it a gentle
shake and then I'm gonna set it
to the side.
So, now I'm gonna switch out
to a smaller bowl and in this
bowl--now make sure
you use a glass bowl.
That's important because we're
gonna need to put it
in the microwave.
So, we're gonna start out
with our main ingredient,
which is an all natural,
unsalted creamy peanut butter.
You can use chunky if you like,
but the chunky actually doesn't
seem to mix up quite as well.
But I have made it and it
tastes really good too.
So, it's just your preference.
There's a lot of natural oil
that comes up from the peanuts,
so we're gonna pour a
little bit of that off.
Don't pour it all out though,
because you'll really have
a hard time mixing it up.
So, I'm gonna go
ahead and mix it--see,
it's already kind of hard.
Let's see.
I have to get the
muscle in there.
Mix it up a bit.
Alright.
And so, we're gonna actually
take 3/4 of a cup of a creamy,
all natural peanut butter
and add that to the bowl.
So, I like to use my
little smaller scoop.
I think it's more manageable,
but you can use a measuring cup
and just measure to 3/4.
So, I'm going to scoop it
out and put it in there.
This one looks slightly
chunky, slightly smooth,
so I think I needed to maybe
stir it up a little longer.
Sometimes I've been known to
heat it up a little bit in
the microwave just to get it
going, but--let's see.
So, we've got our 1/4 going.
Do some more.
And you don't have to be
super, super careful with
the measurements in
this actual recipe.
You can add a little, take
away a little if you want.
I've actually figured out the
ratios just to have just enough
so you don't have to--they
don't end up too dry,
'cause we want them to
stick together a bit.
We're trying to make that crispy
rice and everything kind of all
come together, so that
when we freeze it,
it actually makes this crunchy,
crispy, kind of granola.
I've almost got it all out.
This one's more challenging
that the almond butter.
Now, with that said, you could
use the almond butter
if you'd like.
And you can actually
add extracts.
So, if you wanted to make say
chocolate with like a little bit
of orange--hint of orange or
something or there's
coconut extracts.
There's bananas--maybe
chocolate, peanut butter,
banana might be pretty good.
You could actually use little
pieces of banana
if you'd like too.
But they will get a little mushy
and that'll make it not stick
together as well.
So, use that sparingly
or do the dried bananas.
But, again, that's added sugar,
so just be careful about how
much you're using, 'cause we're
already using quite a bit of
natural sugar.
Next thing I'm gonna add
is gonna be my honey.
So, we're gonna do
1/2 cup of honey.
So, since this is my 1/4
measuring scoop I'm gonna do
2 of these.
So, we've got one.
Need my little spatula.
Now, honey is really,
really, really good for you.
I'm often asked about honey
versus agave and if agave
is better.
I personally prefer honey.
I think there's so many
health benefits to it with
the antioxidants.
And it's good for your skin.
It's a good antibacterial.
There's just so many great
things about it that I'd prefer
to use it, 'cause agave in truth
it'll still spike your
blood sugar.
So, be careful because a lot of
times some of those labels can
be misleading and make you think
that that's a better choice,
but it actually still pretty
much does the same thing.
So, alright, we've got those two
ingredients in the bowl and now
I'm gonna add 1/2 cup actually
of xylitol brown sugar blend.
Xylitol is a sweetener.
It comes from like
raspberries, plums.
It's a natural
fructose sweetener.
And it's actually
a sugar alcohol.
It does not have quite as many
calories as regular sugar,
but it still will have a
slight insulin spike.
It's just a little
bit better for you.
It is organic.
It is natural.
They actually use it in
toothpaste 'cause it's good
for our teeth.
So, I'm gonna dump that in.
and the brown sugar part adds a
little bit of molasses flavor
to what we're making.
If you really prefer, you can
look for something like
organic sucanat, which it has
15 calories per teaspoon.
So you're adding some calories,
but it's less sweetness as far
as like less grams of sugar,
but it also tastes less sweet.
So, you might end up
having to use more.
So, for me I just like to use
this and just kind of eat it
sparingly, so.
Alright.
Into that I want to add--let's
see we've got vanilla.
I'm gonna do a
teaspoon of vanilla.
And then I'm going
to add my chocolate.
Now, the chocolate the
preference is up to you.
You can add a
couple tablespoons.
You can add a lot
of tablespoons.
You can use dark chocolate,
Hershey's chocolate,
whatever kind
you'd like to use.
Some people like cacao.
You could use
anything you'd like.
So, I'm gonna open that up.
Let's do 3 of those.
I prefer for the recipe
to use dark chocolate.
So, if you can find
the unsweetened dark chocolate,
I think that's
probably your best bet.
So, I'm gonna stir this up just
a little bit just to get
the dry stuff incorporated
a little.
And then we want to stick this
in the microwave for just about
30 seconds just to
kind of soften it up.
So, I can stir it all together.
Alright, let's stir
this together a bit.
You want to get all of the dry
ingredients incorporated into
the wet, so it's
doing pretty well.
You might have to stick it
in there for maybe another
30 seconds to really
get it pliable.
I think I'm gonna do that
with--when you add all of
the cocoa and everything it's
not quite as liquefied as one of
the other recipes that we made
like the honey, almond,
protein crisps.
So, let me stick that back
in for 30 more seconds.
Don't do the minute all at once,
because you could burn
your chocolate and we
definitely don't want that.
Alright.
Let's stir this together a bit.
Yeah, that's much
easier to stir.
So, now that I've
got it all out,
I'm gonna go ahead and pour that
on top of our dry ingredients.
There we go.
Now it's pouring.
It smells really good.
I could probably just eat the
chocolate and peanut butter,
but--let's see.
This one I don't
share with my dog,
'cause she can't have chocolate.
So, I'm gonna fold the dry
ingredients over the top.
I like to do the little
folding technique,
'cause it keeps my spatula
from getting too sticky
right off the bat.
Alright.
And it doesn't look like much.
You have to really work it
to start getting all
the wet ingredients
incorporated into the dry.
So, it might take a little bit
of work, a little bit of muscle.
So, I think I've
almost got it all done.
If you can see the protein
powder still in there,
you've got to probably
keep stirring, which I can.
So, I'm gonna keep
going a second.
It might look a bit dry
and you don't want to add
a lot of liquid though,
because if you do,
it'll end up getting
too soft and fall apart.
So, I think it
looks pretty good.
Now, we end up putting this in
the freezer so it can get hard,
but do know that after a while
if you take it out of the
freezer, it's gonna get softer
and softer and it still
tastes awesome.
It's just not quite
the same texture,
because of course the peanut
butter and everything softens up
a little bit.
So, I think we're good.
And I'm gonna show you first and
foremost how I make like
one of the shapes.
I brought just a little circle,
'cause that's a pretty easy one
to demonstrate with.
And I brought a pan.
You don't need to prep
your pan or do anything.
You can just use
your little circle.
And then you just really you
take a little bit in your
fingers, push it down in there.
It takes a little bit of time,
but it's really pretty simple.
And then you just want to
firmly pack it in there.
And as you push it all in then
just gently kind of take
the little loop off.
You can see how it turns out. Turns out like that.
And when it hardens
up, it stays that way.
And it's really nice
you can pack them up.
You can stack them together
and wrap them up if you'd like.
So, let me do
another one of those.
You could maybe
alternate flavors.
Do one kind of crisp and then
do a different kind
of flavored crisp.
Alright, so I packed
that in there.
Wiggle it a little
bit and there we go.
So, I would fill up the rest of
the tray and then stick that
in the freezer.
And I'm gonna finish
working on these.
Whatever I have left I'm gonna
put in here and then
I'll come right back.
[music]
Okay, the chocolate,
peanut butter,
protein crisp has been in
the freezer for about an hour,
so we're gonna go take that out.
They look great.
I took out the ones
that we cut into shapes.
So, now they're nice and
frozen and solid, so.
If you are making this and
you actually keep it in
one big dish, it makes about
a serving of eighteen.
For a single serving of these
you're looking at 153 calories,
about 7 grams of fat,
21.5 grams of carbohydrates,
and about 5.6 grams of protein.
So, I hope you like them.
I hope you get creative and have
a little bit of fun with it.
And please come back and visit
BODYBUILDING.COM
for more information
and content like this.
[music]