the
that
%uh
mom
the
%uh how I'm saying he said in today and
in the body lean back on teaching an
enemy
maintain textiles including burgers I'm
I've already started
by putting my head then and setting it
on broil you want to set it on high
there's high and low settings
make she put on high and I've missed a
rack to the top about two inches from
the heating element
well at all so I degrade my sicky me
I'm using to pound turkey and for every
pound turkey
I've created to use it teenies so we've
got
quite a busy teeny and
makes a lot of issues but we want that
because turkey tends to be really dry
so that's why we're put music in there
in the first place at all add some
moisture
so I want all the liquid as much as I
can get
try to bounce at sample
right
and then after that is you can AM I had
all my spices
this is a really easy easy are recipe
it's got
one measuring spoon which is a teaspoon
so have got a teaspoon pepper here
1 teaspoon of garlic
27 assault
1 teaspoon oregano
an entity spends a penny in powder
and 2 teaspoons it pays off
that's it its last green staff
and Emma had the turkey
and this is where you get your hands
dirty meet its reach in and start
mission at
never wanna
overwork protein because they can tend
to get a little bit tough
so just really can ask questions pick it
up unfolded over into you get all
incorporated
you can make this
same recipe with really any sort of me
whether it's the four maybe ground
chicken breast
actually prefer lean ground chicken
breasts but actually it's really hard to
find and not every but you make senator
every grocery store offers it
looking pretty good
now I've already prepped my can I
covered it in foil because this can get
pretty messy
and dizzy he had a lot of liquid so
sometimes it's a little rainy
you can make these on the grill if you
prefer but for me the broilers just easy
cleanups that's why i like it now I just
need an
for knees into patties I get about a
palm full
nune aim for maybe about an 45 counts is
this whole recipe makes about
and ninety tenders this is actually a
really great
I low carb options says you can ease are
a car but
there's very few carbs and I'm
distressed he's also really versatile
instead have burgers you can make them
into meatballs and put them on
spaghetti squash and there's another low
carb option
for me spaghetti squash is a lifesaver
whenever I'm started in that low carb
phase
and something like this makes me think
that makes me feel like a man and
spaghetti
also using the greater to create a few
vegetables and things like that not only
does add moisture to your needs
but adds more volume so even a it seems
like
me be Rand like for instance it here
having a party or something you've got
to make a dollar stretch
you can add lots of grated vegetables to
things now actually create more suited
to the more you kenya Red a great at the
family had to come to Turkey
it actually might make more patties so
second an average my hands of
cannot just got a dip in and
with a broiler you're actually getting
treated just like a gorilla and
this one I usually like to do about
seven to eight minutes on each side
depending on how hot your add an S
I miss at mine for seven minutes and the
mall open it for the mother and 27
minutes more
okay we flip the burgers and
it's been seven minutes on one side and
now seven minutes on the other
let's get a map
Kelly
K say always wanna make sure it's done
switches can and poke into one see know
clinton sad they really to see
its good sign and I guess I'll just put
one together you can you can buy
themselves region a low carb thing
or another option is to use Ezekiel then
or and in a bread you really want that
for for these
at the are only made from sprouted
grains
so if you look at the ingredients there
there's nothing artificial and you can
only find in the freezer section
he's our fans teaser at an English
lesson which is another
options and then you've also got stuck
bread so-so different ones have
different carrier caps
think I'm gonna go for an English muffin
you can test a
you can even soft whatever you'd like
remain soft
staff government ban many
miss I sipped media
and cheese slices a little bit less
and then whatever condiments you want to
put on this and
kachuck where or add mustard might work
I like to catch it this is the reduced
sugar variety just make sure you get one
that doesn't have high fructose corn
syrup and
Sandusky something that on there I like
quite a bit
get patty that arm
and there's
hamburger it looks pretty good I am
taking
rights effingham out on in case come
from alright
for this recipe just check the link
below
known if you want more recipes or
articles you can find those at
bodybuilding not calm
do
the