[music]
Hi, I'm Jamie Eason,
and I'm in
the bodybuilding.com
kitchen today,
and I'm excited 'cause I'm
gonna show you how to make my
Honey Almond Protein Crisps.
I've showed you guys how to
make chocolate protein bars,
lemon protein bars,
carrot cake.
They're all kind
of, like, cakey,
so I wanted something with
a little bit of crunch,
and this is super, super simple
and tastes really, really good.
So let's get started.
For this recipe we're gonna need
3 cups of crispy brown rice.
We're gonna need
1 cup of whole oats.
We're gonna also need
a scoop of vanilla protein,
whichever kind you like.
We'll also need a fourth of
a cup of chopped almonds.
You can either just use whole
almonds and break 'em up
yourself, or you can buy the
chopped almonds at the store.
And then for our
wet ingredients,
we're gonna do almond butter.
We're gonna have honey,
and this isn't actually wet,
but it's gonna go in
the wet ingredients.
That's our xylitol
brown sugar blend.
This recipe is super easy,
and it comes together
really, really quickly.
All you're gonna need is
basically a large bowl so you
can dump all the ingredients in,
and we need a smaller bowl
so that we can actually just
microwave to heat it up just
a little bit, so that it's
easier to actually mix
into our dry ingredients.
And once you do that,
it's pretty much done,
and we stick it in the freezer.
No baking at all, and you can
eat it in about 30 minutes.
To begin with, we've added
already 3 cups of
the crispy brown rice.
Now, you can hopefully
find this at one of your
local grocery stores.
I've seen it at Whole Foods almost every time.
The reason I like
this, it's gluten free.
It's really got very
few ingredients.
It does have some
natural sugar in it,
but it's from evaporated cane
juice and it's organic molasses.
So it's only got 2 grams
of sugar per serving,
which is 3/4ths of a cup,
and we've got 3 cups in here,
so you're looking at less than
5 grams of sugar for the entire
batch, and you're not supposed
to eat the entire batch.
So 3 cups go in the bowl,
and then we've got
1 cup of whole oats...
So we're gonna
dump that on top.
And then we're gonna
add a fourth of a scoop
of crushed almonds.
So you can actually do your own
if you'd like and just use your
trusty rolling pin and, you
know, beat 'em down that way.
Or you can buy 'em already
chopped at the store,
which is what we have...
So I'm gonna add
a fourth of a cup.
And I kind of
sprinkle it around,
because we don't want to
actually mix it up too much
until we have the rest
of our ingredients ready.
And the last ingredient
for our dry ingredients is
one scoop of protein...
So I'm putting that in.
And a lot of you
guys always ask me,
"What kind of protein do I use?"
Whatever kind of
protein you like.
I just like something that's
got a good vanilla flavor 'cause
it's usually a good
base for everything.
And I always look for the
fewer ingredients, the better,
but whichever one you like.
Some people like it
with added aminos,
and all kinds of extra little
things so that they can get,
you know, added nutrition in one
little easy scoop, so all right.
I'm just gonna give
it a gentle shake.
Don't mix it up yet, because
it'll all settle to the bottom.
Set that aside.
And now I'm gonna start
with my wet ingredients.
So we are gonna start
with almond butter.
Now, when you buy this
stuff at the store,
make sure that you're getting
the one that is just almonds
and salt, or just almonds.
Don't get anything that
has, like, added oils.
As you can see, there's
a ton of oil already on top.
I like to pour off
just a little bit.
Don't pour it all off, though,
because you'll have a really
hard time mixing it up
all the way to the bottom.
So I'm gonna mix it up just
a little bit...
and once I get that going,
we are gonna need
three-fourths of a cup of this.
So I like to use my
one-fourth scoop.
I feel like it's a little
bit more manageable,
so I'll just pour that in...
and we'll do that three times.
So I'll get that going.
I have my little rubber spatula
to get it out...
I need three.
And now you can--one of the best
parts of this recipe is that
it's really whatever
you want to put in it,
so if you wanted to use, you
know, peanut butter or tahini,
which is crushed sesame seeds,
or any kind of nut butters
that you like, really.
You can use anything, and that
goes for the nuts that you
choose as well.
You can choose
whatever you wanted.
So one more.
And as you can see, this
is a lot of healthy fats.
You're forewarned at this point
that this is not something you
need every single day,
but it's a great snack.
And we have actually an event
tomorrow where we'll be running
and burning a lot of calories,
so this would be great for that,
because it's great for energy.
All right.
And it's being
a little stubborn,
but I think we
got it all.
Okay.
So that goes in.
So we've got our
three-fourths of a cup.
And then we're gonna
need 2 cups of honey.
And honey, of course, will
still spike your blood sugar,
but honey is so good for you.
It's loaded with antioxidants.
There's all sorts of benefits to
it...so we're gonna add that in.
Again, this isn't for
everyday consumption,
but it's gonna be
an awesome treat.
It tastes
unbelievable, actually,
for so few ingredients.
So we'll get that in,
and one more...
There we go.
And actually, honey is kind of
fun, too, because at the store,
you'll find, like, all
different kinds of varieties.
You might find one that's,
like, lavender flavored.
I got one that was
rose flavored once.
Not so much.
I really felt like I was chewing
on the lawn or something.
Not good, so all right.
We got that.
And then to this, I'm gonna add
a half a cup of xylitol
brown sugar blend.
You don't have to use
this if you don't want to,
because you're fine with
that amount of honey.
This will kind of kick up
the intensity a little bit
and make it a little sweeter.
I think it really
adds a lot to it.
And it does add some
calories, but unlike sugar,
which is like 3.7 or
something like that for sugar,
this is only 2-point-something.
So it's less, and actually,
it's approved for diabetics,
because it spikes
your blood sugar less.
So we're gonna throw that in
there...but I do want to show
you this one other alternative.
Some of you may or may not
be familiar with sucanat.
It's actually a brown
sugar substitute as well.
If you taste it,
it's really granular,
but it does have a little bit
of a hint of a molasses flavor
added to it without
extra sugar or anything.
So this is definitely
an option for you.
So once we've put
this in the bowl,
I'm gonna put it in
the microwave...
[beeping sound]
And we're just gonna
do 30-second intervals
is all we need.
And I'm gonna move
this back over here,
'cause we're gonna need it
to start mixing this together.
[beeping sound]
Sometimes it just takes one.
Sometimes it takes
a little longer.
I'm gonna actually go to
the bigger spatula now.
Actually, that heated it
up pretty well...
Mix it all together...
and you really,
you're just heating it just
enough just so that it'll
spread easily inside here.
I think that's
actually pretty good.
If you needed to, you could
do another 30 seconds
in the microwave.
So I'm gonna go ahead
and pour that in.
You want to kind of spread it out a little bit
and get all of it out.
It's gonna seem like there's
really not enough to kind of go
around at first, but you just
kind of have to really
work it in.
So now I can start
working it together.
I like to kind of use this
little fold-over technique...
so it doesn't stick to my
spatula...All right.
So then you kind of start
chopping into it.
Now, you could actually add
dried fruits if you wanted to,
if this was for your kids.
You know, I know a lot of us
stay away from dried fruits,
but you could do all
kinds of nuts, actually.
Walnuts.
You could do peanuts,
whatever you'd like.
All right.
I think we're
looking pretty good.
I see a few dry spots, but I
think I can fix that when it
put it into the bowl.
So I want to use
a 9 x 13 Pyrex dish.
You can use whichever
dish you'd like.
I just find that works well
because I don't need to spray it
or anything.
There's enough healthy fats in
here that you don't have to add
any nonstick sprays
or anything like that.
All right.
I'm gonna grab my dish
and pour this in...
All right.
And you kind of get it
started--I'll move that so
you can see.
Kind of get it started
with your spatula...
and then I like to finish it with my fingers.
I think it's easier to really
get it pushed down in there.
So wet your fingers just
a little bit...so it doesn't
stick, and just start really
pushing it down...
I could put the towel down underneath this.
It wouldn't be so noisy.
So I'm just really pushing
it in good...and that's it.
And just so you know, one of
my favorite things, actually,
is you can use the same
technique and actually use
cookie cutters,
which is kind of fun,
and make like little shapes
and stuff for the kids.
And now I'm just gonna put this
in the freezer and then in about
an hour to check on it...
All right.
It's been about an hour, so I'm
gonna go ahead and get
the Honey Almond Protein Crisps
out of the freezer.
All right.
It is definitely cold.
It's pretty hard.
So you can either at this
point cut it into squares
and sometimes, I don't even like
to go to all that trouble,
so I just break pieces off.
I recommend you store it
actually in the freezer,
because it'll keep
the texture nice and hard,
and it doesn't get
too hard to bite into.
But if you cut it
into 18 squares,
each one is about 154 calories,
about 8 grams, all of good fat,
21 grams of carbs,
and about 4 grams of protein.
So I guarantee you
will like this.
It's really good stuff, and I
hope you will come back
next time whenever I'm
making something new.
For more content like this,
check out bodybuilding.com.
[music]