the
that
%uh the
%uh mom
%uh home
%uh
%uh inde sentence today I'm in the
bodybuilding got confidence in him
showing
you had a mi my chocolate peanut butter
protein Chris
in a previous video I showed you how to
make my honey almond protein Chris
but now we're going to use to my other
favorite ingredients chocolate
and peanut butter so let's get started
the ingredients for chocolate peanut
butter protein Chris
are three cuts ever crispy brown rice
we've got one cat a whole it's and sq
other than no a protein powder we've got
some crushed almonds 7
seen a better rate here some cocoa and
some
brown sugar and somewhere and you have
got mahany
thats I can name so let's get started to
start
I for it three caps at the crispy brown
rice and just CC
you can't have a reference this is the
crispy brown rice a year its
and gluten free organic it's got very
few ingredients in it does have a little
bit a sugar its natural sugar its target
Lassus and evaporated cane juice but its
two grams per serving this before so the
company serving so
you've got less than five grams if
natural sugar in the whole entire espy
said not bad
and it makes 18 servings so we started
with that but that in and I've got my
cat the whole its that on top
and then I'm gonna add 1/4
cat as crushed almonds so if you don't
have pressed are means you can actually
just
taker an ominous you know about a fourth
a couple dozen just beat him with a
rolling pin
you can ease the back a pot what every
whatever you have and then on top of
that
I'm gonna had once keep vanilla whey
protein powder
I can I sprinkle out on top. spread it
around a bit
now do not mix this up we don't wanna
make
and all that protein powder settle to
the bottom so I just committed to shake
anonymous edits aside
ok set now miss so it's out to
a smaller bowl and in this call now make
sure you use an
a glass wall that's important because we
need to put it in the microwave so
and we're gonna start out with our main
ingredient which
is an all-natural insulted creamy peanut
butter
you can use twenty if you like but the
20 actually doesn't seem to accept quite
as well
but have media and an anti-skid really
good too so it's just your preference
there's a lot a natural oil that comes
up from the peanuts so we're gonna for a
little bit
that of don't pour it all out though
because you really have a hard time
nixon at
so I'm gonna go ahead in makes it see it
sorry kinda hard
see get the muscle in there
mix it up a bit I A
and so where you actually take and three
forces a cat
the creamy on natural peanut butter and
add that to the bowl
so I like to use my little smaller skip
I think it's more manageable but you can
use a measuring cup in just measure to
three-fourths so
I'm going to skip it how up
noon this month slightly chunky slightly
smears so
I think I needed to may be stirred up a
little longer sometimes have been known
to heat it up a little man in the
microwave just to get going but
cease we've got r1 force go in
smaller
and your have to be super super on
careful with the measurements in this
actual recipe
you can add a little take away a little
if you want I've actually figured out
the ratios just to have just enough so
you don't have to you
and emailing it to dry wanted to stick
together a bit
we're trying to make that crispy rice
and everything can all come together
so that when we freeze a actually makes
this crunchy crispy
kinda granola honest Carolina this is
more challenging than
then on better now with that said you
could use the allman better if you'd
like
and you can actually add extracts so if
you wanted to make say chocolate was
like a little bit
orange 10+2 orange or something or
there's coconut extracts there's been an
ass maybe chocolate peanut butter banana
might be pretty good
you can actually use little he sees a
banana if you'd like to you but
they will get a little mushy and I don't
their make it not stick together as well
season sparingly
or do the drive finance but again
there's added sugar should just be
careful about how much do you think is
where are you using
I did the natural sugar mixing in at its
gonna be my honey
said we're gonna do
half a cup honey so since this is my 1/4
measuring skip 72 eighties
sitka one no
spatula
now honey is really really really good
for you I'm often asked about
honey verses agave NIS agaves better
I personally prefer honey I think and
there's so many
health benefits to it with their
anti-oxidants and
it's good for your skin and it's getting
into bacterial there's just so many
great things about it
I'd prefer to use it cuz I got the
interest it
it'll still spike your blood sugar so be
careful because a lot of times and some
others labels can be misleading you make
you think that
that's a better choice but and actually
still payments to the same thing
so alright we've got those two greens in
a bowl and now I'm gonna add
Africa actually as is out all brown
sugar blend
and Allah Ta'ala is a sweet it comes
from rank raspberries plans it's a
natural fit tests
sweetener and it's actually sugar
alcohol its
does not have quite as many calories as
regular sugar
but it still will have a slight insulin
spike it's just a little bit there for
you it is organic it is natural
and they actually use it in toothpaste
it's good for your teeth so
read em that in and the brown sugar part
adds a little bit have a molasses flavor
to it we're making
and if you really prefer you can look
for something right
organic second I which and it has 15
carries for
per teaspoon issue adding some calories
but it's less
sweetness as far as like whiskey and
sugar they also tasteless
the same I and that having he's more so
for me I just like to use this
and just kinda it's mainly SAV re: into
that
and when and as you've got the now I am
miss you X he stands in our
and then I'm going to add my chocolate
now the chocolate
the preferences that to you can add a
couple people sneaking and
allotted tablespoons you can use dark
chocolate Hershey's chocolate
whatever kind you'd like to use some
people like how you can use
anything you'd like so open at
st3 in those I prefer for the recipe to
use dark chocolate
so if you can find the NC in dark
chocolate
i think thats play your best bet so I
Minister this set just a little bit
just to get the dry stuff incorporated a
little
and then we want to stick this in the
microwave for just about thirty seconds
just kinda soften it up so i cant
can stir it all together ok
that
ok me
sternest together a bad up
unit all unduly dry ingredients
incorporated in still help
so doing pretty well you might have to
stick in there for
and maybe another 30 seconds to really
get it 5-all
and i think im gonna do that with when
you add all the cocoa and everything
it's it's not quite
as and liquefied is when the other
espy's at remain like their honey
on protein Chris so let me stick it back
in
for 30 more seconds don't do you the
minute
all at once because you could burn your
chocolate and we definitely don't want
that
sternest together there
up yes
much easier to stir sound now that I've
got it all out
I'm gonna go ahead and poor that on top
a very dry ingredients
here again aspirin smells really good
he prolly just eat the chocolate and
peanut butter but
see
its this and I don't share with my dog
his
ski have chocolate said I'm gonna fall
the dry ingredients over the top I like
to do the little folding technique is it
keeps
I spatula from getting too sticky right
off the bat
very and it does on place might see you
have to really work it to start getting
all their wedding greens incorporated
into the dry
I sent might take a little but a little
work a little bit a muscle
so I think Obama's get it all done
he can see the protein powder still in
there
get probably keeps turning Cecchin
Sam keep down a second it might look a
bit dry
you don't wanna adalat a liquid though
because if you do
and it'll in that going to use often
fall apart
so I think it looks pretty good now
and we in that thing this in the freezer
so it can be hard but
do you know that after while if you take
out the freezer its gonna get softer and
softer and it still tastes awesome
she's not quite the same texture because
of course the peanut butter and
everything softened up a little bit
to think we're good all
even I'm gonna show the first in four is
how I make
like when the shapes I Brian just a
little circle
that's pretty easy one demonstrator and
if I can you don't need a pep you can't
do anything he just use your
feel circle and then he's really take a
little
take a little bit you fingers push it
down in New
takes little the time
it's really pretty pretty simple and
then you just wanna firmly pack it in
there
energy push it all an then just hit me
cannons take the little leap of
you can see how it turns out turns out
that my heart is at
it stays that way and it's really nice
compact pneumatic its staff come
together in mathematics you'd like
so need another one of those maybe
alternate flavors do one kind is
Chris and do a different kinda favorite
Chris
me
pac spending make it a little bit nearly
go
so I would fill up the mess in the tray
and then stick that in freezer
and I'm gonna finish working on these
ever I had left him and put in here and
a commitment
okay the chocolate peanut butter protein
chris has been
in the freezer for about an hour so
we're going to get take that app
daily create at to get the ones that we
cut into shapes
so now they're nice in frozen and solid
Sarah
and if you you are making this and you
actually keep it in 20 days
it makes about a serving 18 for single
serving in these are looking at 153
calories
about seven games a fat 20 1.5 grams
carbohydrates in about 5.6 grams of
protein
so I hope you like them I hope you get
creative and have a little bit of fun
with it
and please come back and visit by
tearing dot com for more information
content like this
do