the
that
%uh
%uh %uh
%uh mom
%uh
are
hi I'm same even in for gay and the
bottling up counting
excited to show you how tiny cinnamon
swirl affecting back
it's where my favorite things I can use
as a snack and meal
because it's got your healthy carbs and
a healthy protein
so let's get started first thing you're
gonna want to do is preheat your oven to
350 degrees
the next thing I did was I got Mike and
ready this is
after eight by eight inspire Xth I just
a light little non-stick spray and you
can set that aside
and then I got all my ingredients
together and for this I want a large
bowl
for my dry ingredients and a small table
for my wedding gradients
so the first ingredient I'm using is ok
flower in a supermarket this is what
helps lower looks like
now I'm often asked if this is
gluten-free and ot
oats typically are gluten-free but one
thing to note is that unless it doesn't
indicated on the bag you never really
sure is maybe it was cross-contaminated
in processing
so for this one it doesn't indicate
gluten-free that for the most part oats
are but if you're concerned
be sure to look for that indication
unlabeled if you can't find
its new supermarket you can actually
make your down you can use a coffee
grinder
in just ran a little bit at a time or
you could use a blender
just make sure to know that sometimes
you can't get it as finely ground as
what's in the package seem I have to
increase the amount you're using for the
rescue
and the slides ball I've added a cap and
a half though far
and to that I'm gonna add as an hour
away protein
now you can use whichever one you
practice to skips in here make sure to
know that
that different flavors and from the
different manufactures will make them
taste different me
so I want to use one that has as few
ingredients and it is possible the
cleaner the better
summit damn fat and smile flower and
then said that
I'm gonna at it myself now if you use a
letting agent like baking soda or baking
powder
he usually need salt because that makes
it react add those in
and then to this dry ingredient batter I
mean actually
add 1/4 cup stevia
this is what's TVL looks like at the
supermarket
i'm steve is a great national sweetener
because it's no calorie
has no car I don't typically use just
stevia around two sweet my recipes
because it can be kinda better
there's different brands st. Viator
stevia and there's another raincoat
trivia
trivia is a great option to that is
typically more expensive
there's two sides to the stevia plant
this one tends to be slightly more
better
it is cheaper and trivia usually see in
packets are in a little tiny tent for
baking
forgoing the cheap route today that's it
for dry ingredients we do have these two
other ingredients used the extra special
ones that just make it
actually ami dorgan eases later
something to eat this aside
to get me my list just like the CEP
really well
let's try get that baking powder on top
rated sometimes if you don't want fake
evenly think that skin Somerset that's
what I and get this smaller bowl ready
for my wedding the ants
for the wet ingredients bringing me to
egg whites
you can see he's a whole egg if your
knees a whole egg but
I prefer to minimize the fat and
payments and USPS I can do that
my second eg if he ever drop
be ok in there indices the same shell is
the shit out it comes right out
so dropped funny and shoe the eggs
I'm gonna had one jar as ABC applesauce
he can use regular after soft but what
are the reasons I like
and the baby food brand is there's
typically no additives as long as you
read the label
there's no additives and it's nice and
forcing portion controlled
so out open at get all the good stuff
off the top
can skip this out again just unsweetened
applesauce
and from the jar that works just like
that's my additional sweetener one of
them to the stevia which
actually will cut some that bitterness
next thing I had is gonna be my
yogurt and I cheese Greek yogurt because
Greek yogurt actually has less sugar
and has added protein so I only need a
half a container this
some rescue cats can add some moisture
to spread
said babysit applesauce and yogurt
actually replace the butter and oil in a
traditional recipe
saw at that and then for
a substitute for milk I'm using my and
sweetened
almond breeze now on NBC again I like
this better than say so we
or rights not because it has again added
protein so it's just more nutritious and
it's healthy fats so
at that meeting about a cat and
spot it through and ingredients Surekha
my happening around
really taste interested take
really get again one of my favorite you
can actually make
s and any candidate I it's like we're
gonna do we can get in a traditional
left and now they have mixed on the wet
ingredients and add the wet ingredients
to the dry ingredients
so get my large ball back now and get my
little rubber spatula so I can get
all the wet ingredients as their choice
great the ball
more moisture the vatican cannot be
icing my niece and
and stay that way not get right out so
added
the lets the dry an expat see
you want it to be. slightly runny
because it needs to poor
so easily so if it's too thick you can
always add a little bit more
%uh on in Greece or on the No whichever
renewing cheese
break that streak end always to go again
but I want to try
eggs in their so I'm now gonna set this
to the site again
because now I'm gonna start using
my special dry ingredients here
got my cinnamon and guess I'll atop now
that I was there other
braniff sweetener that I like to use for
the other type a sweet because
this one and even now it's no calorie
actually has carbs
but it is far less bitter then something
like Steve yes I find whenever is both
it kinda bounces out that bitterness
summit had my sentiment is out on this
is a third of the cut
you can use more or less I i just like
my cinnamon swirl pretty mad face we
and I mean I had it two or three
teaspoons cinnamon again however much
you like
I added three a really really like
center in South poor that an
mix that up really well now that's how
does tend to be a little more granular
then
I'm traditional shaker and more granular
than that
and Steve yet but I think that's good
because it actually helps sorted
maintain that rare
that we're trying to create interpreting
red and also I don't know if you know
that
and that I was actually the same 10
that's used and
fluoride toothpaste and it's actually
good for your teeth
so imagine that sure that's good for you
too
i think thats it's nice it makes looks
pretty good
city now a minute set these things aside
Graham I can now start putting together
desert my poor are really shallow rare
on the bottom at the pier to spread that
out
the thinner the better because if you if
you pour half the batter which
seems like that should be fine typically
you're gonna kind as
and miss that little cinnamon where
that's in between
spend that really wow
expert again and again depending on your
protein
the consistency if your battery might
vary a little bit
so now I'm gonna added my sentiments
I'll atomic share
cinnamon sugar was caught that sounds
better and it's pretty heavy
I like to actually add more then I'm
more than half
so that's covered pretty well got about
that much left
yes for the top and that's my middle
looks like
so than a minute for the rest the batter
on top need is can I wanna do it where
it's
you know even she here are covered in
rate that looks pretty good
some spread that out
men I'm just gonna added the rest the
cinnamon sugar on top
nice thing about this too is that it
looks really pretty and if you make it
actually in the left pane you can
and cut slices and actually use it to
make a difference tests which is pretty
good as well
summit take my knife now and to make
swirl minute drama nice
to the batter yet however you want to
scan make sure it incorporated
I just can't go back and forth a little
bit
now in its third in the event that
remember I P he did before
at 350 degrees
okay and 24 minutes let's text
are cinnamon protein bread
your seven depending on the temperature
they can vary and sometimes it's 24
minutes sometimes it might be more like
30 minutes
so let's check in see how r slept looks
pretty good
I think now is that I let it cool down
for about five to ten minutes before we
can actually cut into serving size: this
okay now many cat this into serving
sizes
see it to about 3
cuts this way 39 upset direction
message make 16 fear
a body didn't PN about two squares
really would be a serving size
for guy get away with maybe three or
even four if you
if you really really wanna in building s
but and two squares is gonna have
you know just around 300 Kallis
and it's about 8 intercell grams protein
about eat carbs it just depends
on and protect proteinaceous ID's asere
looks pretty good you can see the little
hope we can kinda see the little a i've
seen in there
so hard to see here cuz making skills
are poor but
sweet taste like to speak n
from you're gonna wanna make sure the
store these in the fridge rate is no
artificial flavors or preservatives
and assets wanna see how I packed these
to take them with me when I travel
check out the pumpkin protein bar video
and for this recipe
take the bottom of the page even more my
recipes in articles check out body
really not calm
do