i'm natalie hearts and I'm here today in
the bodybuilding icon kitchen show you
how to make my favorite recipes
the strawberry banana oatmeal protein
shake he and I would see it make this
sorted as a healthier version from an
aggressive and creating banana bread I
know it's not very healthy for me
I make this instead and it's also a
really good meal that you can make on
the weekends you can make it in bulk
and you can keep it in your fridge
during the week we can also freeze that
so if you have to get out the door
really quickly in the morning
this is a great item you can meet for
your breakfast now so for today's recipe
these are the ingredients are going
going to you and we have dry ingredients
and wet ingredients organic separately
cell
for dry ingredients we have 2 cups I'll
fashion elf
and I prefer the old fashion out so the
ins and outs just because they've been a
little bit less processed the ins and
outs have actually been
flattened cooked and dehydrated and so
the old fashion it's just been rolled
and their little bit better for you and
then we have four scoops vanilla whey
protein powder
you can use any brand you prefer just
keep in mind that the different brand
will make it a slightly different
we have two tablespoons above ground
flaxseed and this is actually optional
but flack see cuz is forever may get 3
fatty acids
and they tell produced the LDL
cholesterol
the bad cholesterol in a full fiber and
antioxidants so to speak for a skillet a
healthier
and when you find a fax eat it comes in
a bad like this the thirty ground
in usual confinement in usually in the
baking aisle at the grocery store by the
other flowers and things like that
then we have 1 tablespoon of ground
cinnamon
we have one teaspoon baking powder
a fourth of a teaspoon us all and that's
just out the baking powder rains and
then we have
a half cup a stevia in the raw in that's
raised for this recipe if your trivia
or as I'll tell you can use that as well
and then for our wedding gradients I
have
a half a cup unsweetened applesauce
which is also for answers this is the
kind I don't got one here
applesauce you just wanna make sure that
you get one this is no sugar added or
natural apple sauce
and the most important thing you can do
is read the ingredients list
so try to find one that all ingredients
are apples in water
and maybe ascorbic acid and that's just
my tendency to help keep the applesauce
from turning brown
and sometimes I even what all do as I
get a little mark
containers that are for kids in that way
it's like perfect
serving size: and I have those me
covered for my son anyways and I use a
sometimes at the half a cup
and then we have 1/2 cups a unsweetened
vanilla almond milk
inanities almond milk amira fees and
settlement because it's low in calories
and has less sugar
and this is the kind I like iPhone for
his brand unsweetened vanilla almond
milk it only has 40 calories
just be careful when you're buying your
own not because from the flavors at
quite a bit of sugar
so again just read the ingredient list
and make sure that like this one has 0
grams of sugar in it
and then we're going to use
a fourth of a cup a love plain Greek
yogurt
in this is the Greek yogurt we have
today just again make sure that you're
getting the non-fat plain Greek yogurt
make sure you don't get one that's the
number flavored or any other flavor
because
we're gonna have a lot of sugar if you
look at the back
might have anywhere from five to eight
grams sugar and mother over sugars that
naturally occur in lactose
sound and then we're going to use for
egg whites I have my whole X hero
crackin weekly recipe
and I have two bananas for gonna slice
the israeli
then and then we have
four or five strawberries anyone get big
stories that the kinda small anything a
fiery
and sex and those are all the
ingredients were going to use it in a
recipe
burning so first we're going to do is
mix all over dry ingredients together in
a bowl
so you're going to take a larger mixing
all when you want it
but the dry ingredients in a large
mixing bowl because
later intimate mix the wet ingredients
into the dry ingredients
so just quicker when green for 54
seconds
and then we're going to mix to cut serve
0 of for scoops a
protein powder our factory
one tablespoon have
settlement half cup a
stevia in there a 1 teaspoon
baking powder in
8430 soon as I saw and then
think my whiskey and thanks for
everything gets mixed together really
well
sometimes they have gotten lazy and not
make that together
very well and my baking powder doesn't
evenly distributes
and then when it could have a bit kenna
if
flatter than the rest I just wanna make
sure the sentiment is gets evenly
distributed in the baking powder
interest until you can see anymore you
know brown spots are white spots isn't
it looks nice unmixed
out this looks pretty good finance at
the set aside
and then mexico are wet ingredients
and doesn't really matter what order
rent-a-car almond milk
are Greek yogurt in the Greek yogurt
just add some moisture to the recipe
and actually in any recipe
you can substitute Greek yogurt or
applesauce for the better and the oil in
a recipe
so now we're going to put in our
applesauce
industries a rubber spatula to get it
all out
and then we're gonna put interact with
now little trick I learned
I use it just for my egg whites in the
trash can and
for some reason I cannot figure out why
my house found that out
time and then one day I want to go take
out the trash and
it was rose I could tell a great for egg
yolk for seeping through the bottom in
the trash bag
and my we realize that it was because I
was eating so many egg whites reference
only and get some trash can
and so now I just throw them in the
garbage disposal
that way it doesn't think upper half I
know some people have dogs actually let
their dogs ether
egg yolks and it's good for their coats
but
you have any pets %uh to see the garbage
disposal
house one
you also could do the liquid egg whites
if you wanna
that are come in a carton to sling trees
a little bit less than
than ratio calls for me think
now I'm gonna take my mistake my Wes can
just makes us all together really well
sometimes birth egg white skin kinda
stick together a little bit sound slick
centel
it looks nice and unmixed
then we're gonna bring over my
Nick starring gradients you were just
going to
combine the and stern altogether
have a two-year-old and this is his
favorite part
I let him usually do you this fine
cutting up the bananas or
from handle him cut the bananas with me
kinda fun to get the kids involved with
this recipe
it's also a really healthy male you get
your your kids to get some whole grains
into your diet
rights another that's makes women
prepare
RPN to the side in risk amuse and
agent spy p.m. you could use a 9-inch
pie pan as well
if you're happy and you could even just
use a a square castro this
men just really lightly spray and I
don't use a lot of the stuff
but I just use the nonstick cooking
spray and
take a cutting board
you were gonna take one for bananas and
we're just gonna
slice a relief then can
if Houston pretty thin slices because
you want another
banana slices that you can wear the
entire bottom obtain
now finance
and turn color after they've been
exposed to the air
and so know always but sometimes I
neighbors does performer and if I let
said the fridge for a couple days it
kenna turns on with her
a purplish color stuff that happens to
you don't be
alarm that's not there's nothing wrong
with its just because the banana
once they get exposed to the area they
can change color so now what I'm doing
is undertaking the banana slices and
lining the bottom other p.m.
and after I'm done
whining this then we're gonna pour the
batter on top but the main
so they say when you bite into it you
have banana
taste on the bottom and they were gonna
put another way opinion is on the top
alright so this looks pretty good now
what we're gonna do is pour the batter
on top of the banana
means just evenly distributed there
gonna sell the pana
all the way to the edge men just
screen about the rest honor and then
what we're going to do is
slice our second banana we're gonna do
the same things are going to put a nice
where bananas on top
and not only does this
make it taste good but it also
exodus really pretty
so the ferry slice rebellion is the more
you're gonna be able to
put across can
in this recipe makes 4 servings so one
serving really just has
one egg lay a scooper of protein powder
and have a couple votes plus a little
bit Greek yogurt a little bit on the
milk it does have half a banana on a
little bit %uh spices
so this is a really good option for
breakfast in
if you kinda getting tired of just
regular old egg whites and
you
okay so
and distribute the very evenly some
military inskeep from these bananas over
XP and then wanna do is take my
strawberries and again I'm gonna slice
pays
family then can you don't have to
at history's if you don't you know if
you don't have them you can just do the
bananas and I say about this recipe is
it's really versatile to you really
could use any kind for
I've done this before with peaches that
was pretty good
I've done it with blackberries you could
do it with
Apple's you could do it with raspberries
really whatever fruit from cell that
week
you could get with raspberries if you
really cared
and then I just put the strawberries on
top
like that
yeah i four before serve reserve five
star Bruce
and just too so it's not like that
self that say I'm we have other merit
preheated the oven to 375 degrees
some realistic this and other than and
we are going to cook it for about forty
to forty-five minutes
basically the top is going to be a
golden brown and you know it's done once
you put a knife in the center and the
knife comes out clean
of right side effects %uh then we could
differ forty-five minutes of
and I'm just gonna test it to make sure
that the knife comes out clean
looks pretty good and as you can
see the top %uh this is going to be kind
of a golden brown color
in what I'm gonna do is let it sit here
and rest for between five to 10 minutes
just until it cools if I tried to cut
into it now it would also give collapse
together
sir gonna let it cool and set for about
five to ten minutes
and then after that I will cut it into
fourths one serving
is one wage say I just usually just use
a butter knife
handcuffed Throop
mmm sometimes like to take my knife and
ran it along the
fly just in case
so doesn't stick
premiums can take a serving his home
phone
pull out 11 in there you go so what I
might do with
is cut in half again or just to see that
like bad saw this looks really good I'm
gonna try by
and see how it tastes
it is really really good think I'll
rephrase was one of my favorite dishes
suffer for SP checked page below in for
more my recipes and for nutritional tips
and motivation check up on building not
come