up
the home
I have ever seen Monty celebrity
nutritionist
and chef today I'm going to be teaching
you how to make my world famous
ten-minute talk house well before I get
started I just wanna give you a rundown
on what the ingredients are
so very simple we're starting out with
some grilled chicken breast
K I'm going to be topping my tacos with
some shredded lettuce
some salsa could use a little black
beans
and low fat shredded cheese and just as
a side
I've got some brown rice okay we also
are using
white corn tortillas I love these guys
I'm gonna garnish with fresh lime and
some cilantro
thought that a lot and a little bit a
avocado alright are you guys ready I'm
hungry some to get started art soon
start with a little all 10
just a teeny bit just for some cookin
that a chicken cooked up I've got my
piano on
medium-high mmm still at that he at
first i cant
and every good chef love season with
salt pepper and I know people are free
to solve but I'm not friends fault
I help fill the time exercise a lot so
salty not going to kill me
for my clients you have high blood
pressure then that's a different story
so we've got to soften their always on
the go with the face
fresh cracked pepper this chicken breast
see my husband seems like they think
guys really like this this is
pre made a store-bought
cut up chicken breast I'm not the hugest
fan about but if you're in a hurry it's
good just buy chicken breasts are you
cut up in a you could buy the grocery
store
trader Joe wherever some but my chicken
in here it's about 4 ounces
a chicken wrap
K that four ounces
you watch when you're really quick I'm
sorry guys but you can't
cross-contaminate
very so when you touch me
you always want to wash your hands with
hot soapy water because
cross-contamination can be found in the
kitchen
I mean it season infinite using the
packet of taco seasoning that's fine 30
min preservative I mean you some fresh
spices
just a little paper Rica just sprinkling
you don't have to get outta
measuring spoon this is some chili
powder
and if the start smoke I love I
some cayenne pepper I'm crushed red
pepper
and a little bit acumen human is a
price that you will see a lot in Spanish
and Latin cooking were smoking
ok local I literally because it is 3
made chicken breasts I'm just gonna cook
it for just like
a minute just to get the spices on it
and also when you heat a fight
that lets the favor release so kinda fun
kinda cool smells good
and I think that this chicken breast
looks pretty year with the spices on it
alright I'm turning off my heat I'm
moving my pan over
let that cool off yet
despite not making a cop in fact it how
it happened now
what i do. in time to get my party is
ready now if you have a gas range at
home you just turn on your he
kinda too low
throw the forty a right over it feel
pray you don't really fit the courts
here right over it
if you don't have a gas stove at home
you have an electric stove that little
like oil you looking think
heating elements as they call it you can
put it on that issue
medium-high just make sure that it's
clean it's not like coated with like
picky like three weeks from yesterday or
something and you just leave it on there
and then I hope every healthy
coke at home has a set up wrong because
we don't you go buy some
like a dollar at Target K go get
yourself some tongs
because you can use those to flip over
yours for Kia's user for a lot
but the stimulus for tortillas just get
some fire on this
look at how free that is just like a
Martha Stewart
photo nothing to the day when I'm done
with these for Macon so pretty that
Martha will be proud
okay there
almost done and you know it you if you
don't have to if you don't like heating
them on your union
heating element on your stove on your
gas range you can always just my boy
I'm not a big fan microwave but last
case is in re: a worst-case scenario
go ahead don't want their this one looks
like it's clearly on
fire which is fine K
summer turning all the burners of
and I'm going to
very quickly cut up my avocado cuz
that's gonna go into
my taco and I just wanna cut
alignment we want a little bit a lime
juice
at once for ready to build the taco here
of
and then I'm just gonna cut trying to
dislodge graph
stopped after a quick of we've got to
now
these tacos it's not super hot I can
hold my hand it's no big deal
I'm gonna take my chicken
look at this chicken it gorgeous a lot
better looking than that chicken
I had before right fit in there okay for
the hot
out okay I'm with school of course what
I'm in a foot a little bit have a up to
them right thing here
but some black beans
it's kinda hot for life
good okay so mental note
don't grab the tortillas trade of a that
still
give it a second to Google up I am NOT
completely burnings radio emergency room
but number
it hurts okay so there
I'm to put a little bit fresh flooded
the little fresh cheese
how pretty is that there's one thought I
loved
was in mind I think minute
10 min up this badly on here
for my hey mister avocado
do you want to go for a ride unit kept
more chicken again look at this chicken
compared to you
straight from the store okay we got some
cake here we kicked it up a notch
think emerald second part
start washing okay a for their rights
black teens
it's not a ton but you know
it's a nap some people like their cheese
right up against the warm parts we can
get this one like that
she's right there a little bit latest
some avocado slices and I've got some
salsa as well
so we can process also on their when
we're done
a little bit so I fell little squeeze of
lime
I'll make our last tacos
30 was really hot so I was giving few
minutes to cool off
for their feels good to me
last little bit chicken if you guys
don't have
spices at your house like you man
cayenne pepper
peppery guys chili powder you should go
get some because it really
makes the food taste good okay it makes
the taste phenomenal and I think
that we not only do we like good tasting
is that as humans we eat with our eyes
so we want the food to look pretty
as well and just because it's healthy
does not mean have planned
and not fun okay this
pancho of my life again yummy
good morning EP's that's what I wanna
know him
so we've got three tacos we'll talk
shows and he's forty years were pretty
small
want that big and you get a little bit
extra brown rice on
side for a little bit more are
piece of those are only about 10 to 12
grams carbohydrates for
540 s cell that's why we're adding a
little bit more black jeans and brown
rice
do it you feel sick just felt that there
are roughly
for just 13s and
you wouldn't want your beloved we'll
apply
that help flavor and waiting for someone
to cuddle
here's a great thing about this meal
avocado you
I'm loaded with what we call
mono-unsaturated fatty acid
he's not a saturated fatty acids good
fact they've been clinically shown in
several studies one particular Yelp that
actually help reduce belly fat 33
percent in people who was dying
another study showed that my life as a
fatty acid that come from avocado
our dear friend the avocado right there
time for actually
people who were eating the more more
these good fats mother Qatar would lose
more weight than other dieters the Evil
Queen
calorie so it's not only about calories
in versus carries out about what are you
calories
are you feeling very fast are you eating
lean proteins are you being processed
food
3 to process meal that's 400 calories
purses
the whole a meal may have real food
let's work hours trust me the real food
meal is going to help your body it
later in the year faster than anything
else something all now caught on here
the little bit on our rights who says
you can't have avocado and rice right
that my black beans I like to accept my
black beans with my race
I just think for fighting fun
angst here you go he's got my 10 minute
tacos
377 calories this entire plate
28 grams of protein fifty-round the card
get to get alright I received a Monte
thanks for watching me teach you how to
cook
and for more fun recipes and videos
check out bodybuilding
Commons