on okay so today I'm here with more rain
andrea
my client worrying and her daughter
she's ten-years-old Rens 38
and so we're going to be doing I kale
chips Cacau kale chips this is my little
I'm phenomenal recipe that I develop so
they're just grabbin two bunches I have
kale chips
ararat organic kale and
taken off leave spine and here so I'm
gonna let them work away at that
so kale is a super-fit you know people
always ask what the server so there
isn't one super food but this definitely
is a very nutritious food
and it's got a lot of phytonutrients
disease-fighting properties which is
what we what
so Cacau kale chips again to punch is a
kale we've got coconut oil to get
another oh I love your choice you could
do even an hour but I'll if you want I
have almond meal as well
that I have some stevia and organic
cacao powder that they're gonna be
mixing and so with kale chips a lot of
times
I see people on social media postino
that they put him in there off and put
them at 350
that is a choice for you you can do that
for about 10 or 15 minutes however
I'm gonna tell you the importance of why
getting a dehydrator
is gonna actually help with getting
those nutrients and so I have my
excalibur which santa brought to me two
years ago
and i thankful for that up the parts of
the hydrator is it doesn't kill the
enzyme and I'm the enzymes are so
important because it keeps the nutrients
alive the whole reason we're eating
vegetables
I'm is because I've the the powerhouse
foods that they are
so when you're cooking them above a
certain level you're actually killing
all the nutrients
so again I'm 40 years old I didn't have
all these tools when I was in my
twenties or thirties
so it's you know over time I've made an
investment in certain pieces of
equipment that actually helped by
my kitchen I'm in the foods I eat work
better for me
so maureen how to import rate Kayla for
your family fall for 3 I'm
credit for sale nice for school of
excellence
and at home just for dinner and senator
might i sorry I didn't accept other
types less
Spanish or of mustard greens
and you haven't sat
with turkey burger chicken
that some scattered going to get some
rest is from
okay some bread do you like yeah yeah
you don't like thrown in the garbage
pitcher at school on time can see that
you're not eating at
very good very good so they have a great
way to get kale and
for your kids to enjoy it so let's go
ahead if you want to go ahead and
grab the other ingredients here skip
taft
on me on here gonna help these guys were
there
i havent king of all the leaves again
I'm I'm putting in
couple tablespoons here so
like I said measuring great but again
over time
you know an excerpt tablespoon or two
it's not gonna hurt chap
I'm gotta put some stevia and sprinkle
them
so and again some stevia to taste and
then I've got the
cacao powder so I can if you love
chocolate scrape
and then
gonna go ahead and for the oil and so I
can hear you can measure and do a couple
tablespoons
but again I want all that powder to
stick
three people making kale chips
yeah was a good workout for the arms
okay
again
%ah some so here I love these mixing
bowls
they're my favorite okay who wants to
shake it up
your the dancing queen let's go shake it
up there yeah
fun in the kitchen with Priya and
Maureen cell when they're done
I you're gonna see like I said you can
put on the event
and I'm gonna have you scoop for it here
so when she go ahead open that up
let them say so this is how they look
and you can kinda makes up a little bit
more but when they're done they're nice
and crispy
and that no crime
a follow-up so that cell
by Rob I'm mmm
what so thanks for joining us on a call
how the minutes
on