i'm natalie happen here nobody will not
come kitchen showing you how to make
frozen spinach cap
this is a really easy orbited a recipe
is this to thicken high protein shakes
and it's great because we put in a
protein shake
you really can't even taste it now just
turn your protein shake screen so if you
have an issue with the color
protein shake and you can if you will
very to it turns that purple and then
you
don't see the green color and spirits is
a cream dark green leafy vegetable which
is really good it's high in vitamin A&E
an Israeli high in iron and calcium as
well so for the ingredients for Denny's
today
we're going to use pennants in usually
up by between a 6-3 eight-ounce bag
different brands have different sizes
that they sound but
just one bag of spinach and then
water and here have two cups of water in
your we may not use the full two cups
were gonna do is add the spinach in
Philly at the water
until for consistency that we need and
then you're gonna need a blender
and then we're going to use a muffin tin
pan as well he and what we're gonna do
you want to go and everything together
we're gonna pour the
like went into the muffin tin pan and
then free that way
so this just feels really simple all you
do is you put your spin into the blender
and I just take and falls in
and put it in and
you're gonna start by filling about
almost all the way for
and then my rule of thumb is about half
a cup of water per two handfuls of
spinach so
and I just kinda pour the water in
there it looks like we use about 1 cup
so we'll start with and then slowly add
water and mountains
and then you just put the lid on your
lender
can be kinda loud
rights as you can see it really
plans down quite a bit and so
but I'm gonna do. is actually at some
worse than its
you're gonna have their s first then
it's in here
and then we're just gonna keep lending
it I'm I don't think I need to add more
water
I'm just gonna kinda blender if it gets
too thick you basically want it
to pick a liquid consistency maybe a
little bit think you're not quite as
thick as a milkshake consistency
me
I think this looks pretty good basically
you swimming crown fine enough they
don't have big chance with
minutes and then what ideas I take this
and I just
poor right into my mouth and 10 and the
I usually fill these pretty much all the
way for
because what I do is and I'll show you
later as I just
use one each my protein shakes
so it looks like this: made
about six and so we could
double this if we wanted and May 12 and
freeze all 12 but today I think we're
just gonna make of 6 I'm gonna stick
this in the freezer
and then just let it freeze for about
three hours you can even leave it in
there for longer a few
our home after three hours and then
we're gonna puppies out pulling the plug
back east to keep them in the freezer to
use for
are protein shakes later in the week
so I just took the Spanish cuts out of
the freezer they've been in the freezer
for about three hours
and as you can tell they're rock-solid
so you can you want two things you can't
just let them sit on the counter for few
minutes until their
melted a little bit and you can pop them
out or what I like to do it a little bit
faster as I'm just going around the
bottom of the pan and any some hot water
me
like to see the threat
in than what I like to do
is just to take a butter knife and
obviously when I can use all 60 the
Spanish Cup
in a protein shake it once and so I just
take the plot fact
I thought usually three or four the
Spanish cups and has a point back and I
saw them in the freezer
for that way later when I gotta make a
protein shake
I can describe a one-out Astley's these
when I make smoothies fruit smoothies
for me
two-year-old it's one of the few ways I
can get him to next call's
so I'm just gonna pop the Spanish Cup
out of
that's what it looks like and go ahead
a little bit messy but can just read
your hands when you're done
of 43 in a bag
terms I tried to fit too many in there
in and the cat to vet
I up
I'm gonna just for two in this bag and
we're gonna save one
to use in a protein shake today to make
the protein shake
I like to use unsweetened almond milk
'it's
come with the no I just make sure you
get the one that has 35 or 40 calories
and rethinking gradient last because
some almond milk for do add sugar
you wanna make sure unsweetened kind
without any sector if you have on now if
you could also use water or regular milk
I usually use about
eight ounces or so I just kinda by paula
and then means you 1 skills love
whey protein you can use you can you
finish up with any flavor and brand
and then
sensitive ice I'm going to use my frozen
spinach company what it's gonna do is
it's gonna take a nap the shape and also
add from good vitamins vitamin E Kelsey
Ann
has complained that up
it looks pretty good
I'm just gonna portent
my Cup
so it doesn't remember shake a
green-collar
and if I can wear you out you can have
some blueberry service and then it turns
the purple
and actually my son won't drink some of
their green but if they have some
blueberries in the turns and purple
then he has no clue in hearing from just
fine fell
he's like a protein shake you can even
taste the spinach
out of fell for this tip and for all my
other recipes
check the link below and also continue
to visit by Billy not calm for
nutritional information and motivation
tips