the
that
%uh
%uh %uh
%uh mom
%uh
are
%uh I i'm jeannie than welcome to the
body burned out complex
today I'm gonna make my protein bars
and I have been making a whole lot if it
takes a protein bars but don't get
burned out suck at this brand new N
this one actually makes a larger portion
a by eight we've been using
so we're going to get bigger Pyrex dish
this time I practiced by spraying
non-stick spray
to nine by 13 and I also preheat the
oven to 350 degrees
so this is easy because it's all in one
large bowls the first week that two caps
a flower and again no flowers just
ground-up ok me on and
you can buy it at the store in that how
the section you can make your down by
grinding and and coffee grinder or
I in a blender sam skinner that in 2
cups
and I've got to skip 708 protein you can
use any flavor that you like
for me I just like for this year
ingredients the better because then it's
health you usually it takes a little
better to use it to skip to that
and then ima start putting in all their
free rein
ingredients I've got 2 teaspoons have
cinnamon
teaspoon and a half
as ground ginger half a teaspoon of
cloves
closer pretty strong but I think that's
really what gives a six-player
so this guy at teaspoon as at baking
soda and a teaspoon and baking powder
and a half a teaspoon
at Salt for my sweet air
I'm actually adding and a half cup
others out of
you can use the brown sugar plan you can
use the regular I actually like the
brown sugar plans for this must be a lot
but you can always find it this means
just the regular have kept as I'll it
also
that in in except he's trying greens
really well
hey an end to this
gonna start adding the wet ingredients
you can make these in separate bowls you
like but it's really not necessary
some skin put it all right in the same
for some
I'm gonna start with for egg whites you
can use the liquid egg whites if you
like
I used and regular real eggs can I like
those better for me
for baking but it's up to you nah man
had
half a cap on you can use whatever kind
you want you can directly or not he can
do right now
whenever you'd like that I like on oxo
have kept at
an end to that man had
14 ounce as that ABC applesauce
you can use regular and sweet apple
sauce at home if you have that
that in the air comes out to probably
about a fourth undercut if you can use
the dryer at home
to that I'm gonna had my pumpkin
I've used a whole 15 ounce can pumpkin
for this Saeed you can use as little or
as much as you want I really like mine
really company so use the whole entire
can make sure to the pic
the ROP pumpkin and not be pumpkin pie
mix that's loaded with sugar
that in semifinal ingredient
is just two teaspoons vanilla so I've
got all those and
you can use the West if you like but I
don't make a mess so I'm just gonna
fault at all and
with a spatula homie
certainly come together for this recipe
you can use and that's or you can do
without nuts
I'm gonna put some on tax and I really
like pumpkin on it together
so I've got it all mixed up tonight that
I have to go on that
in a little baggie said there is no
dennis is because I didn't 5 a crash
that kinda an actual crush these myself
so I like to buy the ones from the band
usually they're a little bit more fresh
than the ones I've been sitting on a
shelf while
touched them in a bag you can grab
anything you like I like my little
rolling
10 just one expression a little bit if
you read about adding too much
that your dessert he actually don't have
to mix them and you can put it all
together and just maybe sprinkle half
on one side or and just lightly
sprinkling on top
I like to mix my name because I like a
City nets in every bank
it's totally up to you speak any
getting there maybe a little smaller 8
noticed and fees and
now the defense though with
if you make it with or without nuts with
natural looking at probably and
about 67 68 carries without nets you're
looking at
under fifty it's about forty seven
carries so it's totally up to you but
the fat isn't that dan
that different and the amount of protein
really isn't that different
it's like about four grams protein bar
this next 24 bars by the way
stuff got that on mixed and money get
money
fish rennie
just poured in pain
%ah spread out now this when you want to
take it for about
at thirty minutes I would say that it's
totally up to you some people like the
bars a little bit more
soft and some people like my little more
cooked through I suggest that if you're
traveling the peace
I'm definitely keep them in the oven a
little bit longer cuz you want in a hole
that
he's not have them
they get for about 30 minutes
that's right
and then we'll check in about 30 minutes
always make sure when you're baking that
year
at the rack is like usually in the
middle it's too close to the heating
element on the bottom it'll burn
if it's too high at it'll take forever
to Kirk's our we will check on it in
about 30 minutes
alright Tamron of Exchequer bars
hey look good
compy sure these are done but if you
wanna make sure you can stick a
toothpick in if it comes out dry with
and no no witness anything it's pretty
much ready so I'm gonna let the school
and then we'll come back
cut them how she had a rapper Matt came
up from Tim protein bars are fully
called so I many
kept them up see this guy to make 24
squares semi three cats
lengthwise and 5
this way
Hey
skip a few tease out click really good
you can see
something that's in there and then I'm
gonna wrap up the rest
see how iraq them when I travel be sure
to ask
shit store these in a cool place like to
for greater
and because if you leave them just out
on the counter or
not in your cooler the actually spoil
there's no preservers
or anything in these I didn't buy to use
I just placed to I'm just ran at
fold over the 1n rolling over
and fold edges and pretty simple k I'm
gonna finish up wrapping up the recipes
for this recipe can check out the link
below and if you want to check out
other recipes in articles just as if I W
dot com
do