i'm natalie happen here today in the
bodybuilding not come kitchen
funny how to make a recipe that I meet a
lotta morning and free blueberry protein
him this is a really good recipe for
getting tired of the same ol
egg whites and health this is the exact
same
ingredients just mixes them into a
different way I know that a lot of
protein pancake recipes out there but
I like this one because it uses all
Whole Foods and it is really a
you hear all the ingredients are going
to use for today's recipe
bring you think that way and a half a
cup
a old-fashioned outs and with all
passion and it's better than the ins and
outs just because they're a little bit
less processed in finance have actually
been cooked
and dehydrated to make them cook faster
and these have just been
world we have for the couple very you
can use fresh or frozen
where you can substitute it for
raspberries or strawberries
we have a half a cup unsweetened vanilla
almond milk
and just makes her that when you get
the almond milk you're getting the
unsweetened vanilla kind I like the
island breeze friend at forty calories
has no sugar in it and you also if you
wanted you could substitute not but I
prefer
almond ok and then we have one teaspoon
have baking powder this is just to help
the pain keeps rising a little bit
two packets of true we have this is to
make them a little bit leader
have half a couple unsweetened
applesauce in the gases in a min
and those two items were gonna stay to
the end and use it as a topping on top
of the pancakes
for these last few extra innings the
blender to mix everything together
and I'm gonna start with my liquid
ingredients me
porn my almond milk and then I'm going
there
to my egg whites I'm
can attract these right into the blender
now
some people just so they re ok so way
into the trash can actually like to put
mine in the garbage disposal
and I found out the hard way I used it
for my ex into the trash can in
when any I came home in me house not
really bad I couldn't figure out why
and it's because I love the oaks in the
trash can for too long
and so now what i do. as I'll just put
them right into the garbage disposal
some people like to feed their egg yolks
to their
dog and I guess helps with their coat
makes it a little bit shy near you
missed some really good breakfast recipe
if you have kids
I have a 2-year-old and he loves this
rescue even a couple times
a week and it's a really good way to
incorporate from whole grains into their
diet
and the blueberries have some really
good anti-oxidants another thing you can
do is you can make these in book
on the weekend and then free zone
I think that is a little bit better
fresh but you definitely can freeze them
and when I do that I just put them in a
ziploc bag and then
I wanna eat them i suck my grief for
about a minute alright
we have some pics a quiet their names
can add me
both even gonna save the blueberries
until we're actually in the gravel
at my baking powder just gonna do you
gas assault probably find a 8:30 soon if
you were to measure
and into packets of trivia if you
132 pancakes without any apple sauce on
top
you could add a third Paco trivia and
make your pancakes sweet see you would
need to add apple sauce on top
and then I'm scrambling this really fast
share
me
quickly gonna turn my skill onto about
medium-high heat
and I'm just gonna spray it with a
little bit us nonstick cooking spray
man
was gonna take my pattern and
this recipe makes two pancakes you can
takes is one serving so
usually just kinda eyeball it input
about half a battery in the skillet
and then I meant a calf my blueberries
and just drop them
in the top you can blend these the
blueberries into
if you want I've done that before but I
think it is a little better this way mix
in a little bit juicier
so we're just gonna let this Kirk usual
you can tell they're ready to flip
when there's bubbles in the center the
pancake I want him fucking cake we've
been talking about one to two minutes on
each side
in for the first pancake doesn't flat
quite as well the second game cake
and it's because something from the
blender the egg whites tend to
or chemist at the top in the oath fall
to the bottom but this one turned out
pretty good
I'm just gonna king cake and
put it on my plate who
at five not quite as pretty and then
I'm gonna go ahead and put me second
pancake and I'm just gonna plan that for
just the second circuit everything
she cannot spring with Hannah spray
up understand pour the rest my batter in
actually get all those boats out
an address my will vary
emerges through it took about 12 minutes
per side you know it's ready to flip
once the edges look like they're cooked
all the way through and there's bubbles
for uniform in the center and the
pancake
so we are done cooking our second
go ahead and put it on the plate as you
can see this is a lot of food this is
another reason I like this recipe is cuz
through a great way to start the day
with a knife hurting now
and then the pixar release we are on
their own
I think and so what happened actually
eat these even without any
applesauce on top you can use sugar free
syrup if you want but
I prefer to stay away from that just
because I have a lot of preservatives in
it
so sometimes if I want a little extra
something on top are you some
unsweetened applesauce just make sure
you get the applesauce but
says no sugar added or unsweetened
we're here eating green list the only
ingredients are Apple's water and maybe
ascorbic acid which helps keep the
coloring so I'm just going i the
half a cup about off of things going for
it on top
sometimes I like to in a little bit
underneath and then
I like cinnamon so I'm gonna put a dash
of cinnamon on top you don't have to you
then if you like cinnamon
sprinkle a little cinnamon on top
there you go you're a really good
breakfast one serving is to pancakes and
serving have six a white
have come about from we're very thin
solid oak forget that we were a protein
pancake recipe you can check out the
link on the page below
and continue to go to body will not come
to find all my other refugees
as well as nutritional information
workout programs and motivation