but ok
you
I'm do
hi and Amy and I'm inviting really not
come today to show you how I make my
turkey meatloaf muffins
any large offer this got a lot to make
set
okay but the nice thing is just one big
ball for everything
can the first ingredient for the needy
is cat
a quick cooking oats dozen
many that all these ingredients that you
mix in with it
if that 2 tablespoons of garlic now you
can use the patter
version or you can use and the minced
version ass a way
got over here here's the minced garlic
now this one seems to be okay if you
read the ingredients this is Carly water
is a spa spark acid
and no preservatives this is OK could
probably use this as an option
and that someone be really careful read
the the label they actually have oil and
it won't be no prominent won't say on
the top so you gotta really check out
that is ingredients
this is actually rare to be Justin
waters that's an option to you that we
use the powder
since just get that way k then we've got
high 1 teaspoon salt
cactus teaspoons pepper
black pepper we've also got
teaspoons a a dry mustard just right
yellow plastic
and sometimes if you're looking for
trailer mustard and some people
will not be able to find it your
standard like dark
like this one you will have to find its
whateva box
looks a little bit more like pepper but
it's a start oxo
I've noticed it's hard to find sometimes
and that's why
and then we've got 1 teaspoon as
I'm sorry this happened he said have
Kumon communism
a really smoky spice Chile get free a
lot the spices rent accidents so they
really get to you if you're not using a
lot of spices in it
he said start doing so and then we also
have a half teaspoon
I have time time is used a lot
in
all traditions ready you're making
chicken turkey year
and then our last ingredient
is the one that makes the whole dish so
this is not the easiest to find so
tonight take a little while but its very
well worth it
this 2 teaspoons if it's holy pepper
seasoning
I'm serious see find it here's
what it looks like so hopefully you'll
be able to find and it does add some see
so be careful if you're not be on hot
things
the only add teeth in half or something
like that but
I really think it without it there lil
one Plan C definitely want to see
said that's it's so I'm skinnies my
fingers in kinda get all
perforated Spath this whole recipe is
pretty much
about using your hands sound 3
tell it's pretty good on before I really
get messy
come in and take this off pesticide
alright the next thing we need is going
to be chopped onions and chopped celery
now this is very convenient to just come
in a package in your produce section
I'm all about quick and easy so this is
what I'm gonna do I hate of indians
cell nah and if you were to chop it
I hear what can I wanted to you I'm
above everything so
quite a bit you really can't overdo the
vegetables in a few nice and a celery
can use red peppers green peppers
anything you want
and that celery in enhancing to work
really well finished
but the more veggies you add the more
moisture there's going to be in your day
she stuff so overdo the veggies instead
under help Texas I'm
frighten the next thing you're gonna
need
is me crappy service here for this
recipe you can
either use I'm extra lean ground turkey
are you can use extra lean ground
chicken breast army
either one will work really well
actually even be four work to yourself
and open
something and I'm using probably I would
say this is about time
I have high tops you pound me
something and it doesn't have to be
exact that's the great thing about this
restful
as you can and do it all the taste and
just dump it all and
seem to get so then the next thing you
need to add some moisture
is good three egg whites if you're not
concerned about adding any
added fat you can actually do a whole
egg in their bit for this
purpose for going to just used a rights
eg to you
eg three
now before I really get me in there and
get dirty
I'm gonna make sure first I have my
mustn't hand
pets and I've artie said the event
375 degrees so make sure you preheat
it's ready to go before you and
millions of
alright so we're gonna prep this because
I don't have to stop in the middle is
keeping fingers do it so I'm going to
use
I'm my no lo or olive oil spray
and this is 12 muffin tins should make
about 12
and sometimes it goes all over it just
depends on how big or small I make them
K nice frame good to make sure they
don't stay
and save my pain
because I hate when they get gross I
always always always white
excess of top cuz they will get pretty
gritty
if you start making these a lot which is
what I do because
I always have these on hand in mine for
trade or just ready to go
cash to keep this recipe completely
frozen
in your in your freezer just take them
out one at a time in my career in front
see alright so that's really gonna set
that aside
bring this back in get busy South
take any jury of this
quite very
starting to look pretty grody which is
exactly what we want
need don't wanna over makes me
too too much and you doing to make sure
you get all the spices incorporated
and left it up to you know that stuff
outta there and
if you over makes me tho it tends to get
a little more tasks so
don't go crazy skit
all in and the nice thing about
this dish to you is that the muffin tins
are what keep it
in its a serving size so it's all nice
and portable that way and it's got
your car and your protein are next in
line now is a low amount of carbs so
you could still eat them into PDA kid
and at issue rice cakes or something to
them
return my foot that I'm still seeing
spices some makin sure
re: don't over mix of stuff there
all right now we're gonna put them
enormous in 10
and I think he'd do about a racquetball
size
see that might be a little larger than a
racquetball size but
that we'll see how that works and
sometimes I get all the way through and
have to steal a little from the other
one
kinda making me even now can they don't
have to be perfect fit
another thing is and that that the fact
that they're in a mass in 10 this is
essentially just the meatloaf
and the differences most me loves have
like a catch it face kind
in the weather sketch efforts made a
saucer something inside oven
I'm with Calif that out and just put the
eggs in a lot of
veggies in there so they're not quite as
moist you can if you if you want to
you can actually do not call it
something push it down in the middle
and put like a catch up for a barbecue
sauce or something in the you want to
they get a little slimy in a little bit
messy to take with you so
only do that when you play any my at
home I think hey we're doing good
now looking like an overdoing it yet but
and
other PDF having them in a muffin tin
not only is that it's the right portion
but
dead the moisture from the veggies
stays confined in a little tense so its
debt
tends to keep the me from getting overly
dry cuz
you action ground turkey has no fact
really so
really Kenneth just its overcome pretty
easily
go exciting stuff like to do this
which kate looks like I actually
maybe have I can make maybe make them a
little bit figure self
I'm in class 1 at a little bit to hear
now if you were to cookies and measure
them now
and they would usually be about two and
a half ounces each
so that will come to you you know AppID
serving size I care
and mayo Miami Heat's I'm maybe
three or four the square you know we
don't need to you would be her serving
and each one in these I depending on how
large you make it
is gonna be like about seven-year 870
880 calories
here you know maybe a little more if you
do choose two large ones
think these might keep my like Easter I
make every day
I think those packages and check the
exact
we give them need to know want
cell that's good rather have more than
less
these are really means so good for sale
it's pretty good
of
so I'm 0 can you with an actress
I'll about eight carries may be late
cute and fat
i'm looking at four cards and about I
11 grams protein and that's for all for
one mustn't so
in get 20 teens approached protein to my
fans
re: these are ready to go the computer
kid
stick them in the middle rack and we
want cookies for quite a while you never
want
uncut turkey and so depending on how
high revving get
I'm and put mine in about 40 that you
might have to play with that go over go
under
just checkin as you go alright so we've
got forty minutes to wait so
go watch is that congress something and
I'll come back and check me
think these are about done so sperm out
there looking good
or not that's no good hell
my potholders friend count
so they look pretty good okay now we
just need to know
given time to cool I suggest that you
take them out a little bit before
they're completely
cool and I I'm on a paper towel I just
pulled it up on the counter and I them
on and let it
allowed to use is that accumulate in the
bottom to
get a little bit dry so that I think for
a minute that black bag mini fridge
and friends and I just I need to grab
something go
or I'm just looking for something to eat
so hopefully like that's hurting me left
my phone
and hopefully we'll come back to fight
to end up comin check out my recipes
me