Hi.
I'm Jamie Eason, and today I'm
in the bodybuilding.com kitchen,
and I'm gonna make my
Italian Turkey Zucchini Burgers.
I've already started by prepping
my oven and setting it on broil.
You wanna set it on high.
There's high and low settings.
Make sure you put it on high,
and I've moved the rack to the
top about 2 inches
from the heating element.
I've also already
grated my zucchini.
I'm using 2 pounds of turkey
and for every pound of turkey,
I've grated 2 zucchinis.
So we've got quite a bit of
zucchini here, and it makes a
lot of juice but we want
that because turkey tends to be
really dry so that's why we're
putting the zucchini in there in
the first place so
it'll add some moisture.
So I want all of the
liquid--as much as I can get.
Try to balance that
and get it in the bowl.
Alright.
And then after I've added the
zucchini, I'm gonna add all of
my spices.
This is a really
easy, easy recipe.
It's got 1 measuring
spoon which is a teaspoon.
So I've got a teaspoon of pepper
here, 1 teaspoon of garlic,
1 teaspoon of salt, 1 teaspoon
of oregano, and then
2 teaspoons of onion powder
and 2 teaspoons of basil.
So that's it.
It's lots of green stuff.
And then I'm
gonna add the turkey.
Then this is where you
get your hands dirty.
You just reach in and
stir, mushing is out.
You never wanna over-work
protein because then it can tend
to get a little bit tough so
just really kinda squish and
pick it up and fold it
over until you get it all
incorporated.
You can make this same recipe
with really any sort of meat
whether it's beef or
maybe ground chicken breast.
I actually prefer lean
ground chicken breast but it's
actually--it's
really hard to find.
Not every butcher makes it or
every grocery store offers it.
It's looking pretty good.
Now I've already prepped my pan.
I covered it in foil because
this can get pretty messy.
The zucchini adds a lot of
liquid so sometimes it gets a
little runny.
You can make these on the grill
if you prefer, but for me the
broiler is just easy cleanup.
That's why I like it.
Now I just need to
form these into patties.
I get about a palm full,
and you wanna aim
for maybe
about 4 or 5 ounces.
This whole recipe makes
about nine to ten burgers.
This is actually a
really great low carb option.
Zucchinis are a carb, but
there's very few carbs in them.
This recipe's also
really versatile.
Instead of burgers, you could
make them into meatballs and put
them on spaghetti squash and
there's another low carb option.
For me, spaghetti squash is a
lifesaver whenever I'm sort of
in that low carb phase.
And something like this makes
me think that--or makes me feel
like I'm having spaghetti.
Also, using the grater to grate
up your vegetables and things
like that, not only does it add
moisture to your lean meats, but
it adds more volume so even
though it seems like maybe
your--like for instance,
if you're having a party or
something and you've gotta make
your dollar stretch, you can add
lots of grated vegetables to
things and it'll actually create
more food.
So the more zucchini I were
to grate up, if I only had
2 pounds of turkey, it actually
might make more patties.
So it looks like I'm done.
I'm gonna rinse my hands off.
Okay.
Now I've just gotta
get them in the oven.
With the broiler, you're
actually gonna treat it just
like a grill, and this one--
I usually like to do about
7 or 8 minutes
on each side depending
on how hot your oven is.
I'm gonna set mine for 7
minutes and then we'll open it,
flip 'em over, and do
7 minutes more.
Okay.
We've flipped the burgers, and
it's been 7 minutes on one
side and now 7 minutes
on the other.
Let's get 'em out.
They look good.
So you always wanna make sure
it's done so we'll just kinda
poke into one and peak.
No pink inside.
They're really juicy
so that's a good sign.
And then I guess we'll
just put one together.
You can eat them by themselves
if you're doing the low carb
thing or another option is to
use Ezekiel buns or any kind of
bread you really
want, but I prefer these.
They are only made from sprouted
grains so if you look at the
ingredients, there's nothing
artificial in them.
You can only find them
in the freezer section.
These are buns.
These are an English
muffin which is another option.
And then you've also got just
the bread so different ones have
different calorie counts.
I think I'm gonna go
for an English muffin.
You can toast it.
You can leave them soft.
Whatever you'd like.
I'm gonna leave mine soft.
So then I've got my bun ready.
I'm gonna slice up a tomato.
Done a few slices, a
little bit of lettuce,
and then whatever condiments
you wanna put on this.
Ketchup works or
mustard might work.
I like the ketchup.
This is the
reduced sugar variety.
Just make sure you get one that
doesn't have high fructose corn
syrup in it.
So I'm gonna squeeze
some of that one there.
I like quite a bit.
Get a patty.
Put that on there, and
then there's my burger.
It looks pretty good.
Alright.
I'm gonna take a bite.
See if I can get my mouth on it.
It tastes good.
Alright.
For this recipe, just
check the link below.
And if you want more recipes or
articles, you can find those at
bodybuilding.com.