i'm natalie Haasan and I'm here nobody
will not come kitchen today showing you
how to me for my favorite fighters
rescue
and I call it def by garlic roasted
asparagus and it's really good side is
sick overtaken or tilapia
he and it even works great as leftovers
I put it in a ziploc bag in you that the
next day
for today's recipe this is a pretty
simple recipe there really is a few
ingredients
in I have everything here we are going
to use fresh
asparagus and news about one count of
asparagus the usually come in bundles
like this
and some asparagus is little bit more
thin and some asparagus is a little bit
thicker
and it doesn't really matter you can use
either for any is fresh garlic
Inc some growth does come pre minutes
but I prefer the fresh for like
I think me first PT little bit better so
organized by the
garlic clove like this and then we are
going to use garlic powder
and just make sure that you get the
garlic powder and not the garlic salt
they look real somewhere they come in
the same sizeof container
but the garlic father quite a bit if l
added to it in the ground cutters just
straight garlic and then we are going to
use extra virgin olive oil
and risking you want people to know that
some just a little bit and then
Sun paper and I have fresh ground pepper
but you could if you don't have the
fresh ground just regular black pepper
will work as well
and then we're going to take everything
on a cookie sheet in line with aluminum
foil
and i really wanna head in preheated the
oven to 400 degrees so the first thing
your gonna do is line a cookie sheet
with aluminum foil
and this just makes for easier cleanup
so that way when you're done all you
have to do is take your woman file out
thrown in the trash in its really easy
to clean up swimmers can set this aside
first we just take our bench for spare
guess
take off the rubber bands and then
strength of make sure that gets nice and
rinsed
and then when I view as I like to keep
the spare guess
still in punt formation and you want to
cut off the bottom
about into the stock and because the
bottom-up stock is really tough
and it it doesn't he's got its not fund
issue so
what I view as I just take a kitchen
knife and I just cut all at once thats
really fast and easy
of he's cut off the bottom love the
asparagus and then what you gonna do is
evenly distribute the asparagus
over the could be /c men except is
mincing the garlic so
garlic when it comes to clothes has an
outer shell kinda like an anion
and so what I usually do is just cut the
end of 2003 easier to peel
and then there's some stuff I just throw
that away
and then there's if you can see inside
there's a lot of little
water call girl close see just take out
this recipe calls for anywhere from four
to six garlic cloves it just depends on
how much curly Q like
I usually I like a lot acrylic so I air
on the fighter
sex but if you don't like I like as much
or as strong
thing you could do stand for and and
nothing to if you don't like garlic
unit actually make this recipe even
without the girl I can just use on paper
no it's not it's pretty are
sums gonna 5 and we have six garlic
cloves here
now they still have kinda outer paper
resell
on them and so you take that off so what
you do is you just put the garlic clove
far you're cutting board
take a knife has kinda wider flat edge
you just like this we just headed
when it does the concussions your garlic
salt makes a really easy
to pull open actually found out the
phone has
to close and find a bit so I unity again
and then it makes it really easy just a
few of the
out urself so I'm just gonna do this for
all six
I really like I need a fair guess a lot
I really like eating asparagus and one
thing a lot of people don't know is that
asparagus is actually really high in
Foley
and a lot of pregnant women are
recommended to take folic acid
which is the supplemental form fully and
suspect this is really good for pregnant
women to
and asparagus is also a natural diuretic
so
if you feel like you're holding on to
some water waiter for fun kinda bloated
sometimes even some asparagus can
help your body red itself from the water
so your hands are gonna feel kinda sick
you when you're doing this
that's okay that's normal
persons since that original club
actually was to close in Saidapet
that one of them to fine
man I just for all the papers that way
sometimes it fixed your hand a little
bit
print my fingers right so we're gonna
miss the garlic really finally and I'm
just gonna do that with a knife
we already took the outer shell of the
people report
and I just put my hand on the top and
the kinda fun shit together
and I just
min fit like this they just keep
pressure on the top of the knife
and I just kind of keep going back and
forth and then what I do
isn't it back together in just keep
keep me in things like that
in you just want really pretty finely
minced because you don't want
anybody to take a big old chunk a garlic
they might not appreciate you for a
this is looking pretty good
I would say that if about is finely
minced easy one
so I'm going to Prince William
missed and then I'm gonna set this aside
for second
and then we're gonna do is put olive oil
on
so i think is one tablespoon of olive
oil now this
recipe makes 4 servings and so each
serving is going to have less than a
teaspoon of olive oil
so I do I want to measure it out because
sometimes
I have a tendency to use too much olive
oil so I just like to measure now that
we know I'm just using a tablespoon
and I just slowly drizzle it over
just like this
and then i'll do is i'll take either
spatula or even just measuring spoon and
I'll just sort of go like this
tooth just to
texture that were olive oil doesn't
get wasted on the bottom of the cookie
sheet
and then it its overall the affair
so then we're gonna do is we're going to
take for garlic powder
so if you have thicker stocks you may
not be quite as much
garlic powder term
but if you have more stocks you might
need a little bit more if senator stocks
so I just sprinkle this is one teaspoon
and that even cover half its I'm gonna
do it again three teaspoons Eagles 1
tablespoon
cell scan keep sprinkling it looks like
an ease the full table stand for this
because remember this is called death by
Karl Eikenberry if
free pretty heavy on your garlic if you
don't like I like again
you can use lighter garlic or even know
garlic is the salt pepper
and then I I'm many some fresh ground
pepper
and this I just kinda I felt like a
family is about a teaspoon maybe
teaspoons
if you don't have the fresh ground its
regular black performer
if you want to add some salt you can buy
I usually just don't add extra salt
and then what I'm going to do is take my
ninth Lincoln SQ
the garlic onto the knife and then just
evenly distribute this over the
asparagus
so I just take my finger in a just like
this
now if you're the eap raw garlic clove
you're either prolly water up in your
mouth but really start to burn
because it's really spicy but when your
upset like we're going to
on 400 degrees critic's summer the
spiciness
add the garlic and it makes it have more
the garlic flavor that reissue
so that's it I'm gonna do is rinsed my
hands and insects and other than at 400
degrees
and I'm gonna cook it for 15 to 20
minutes so what I'm going to do is put
this in Irvine
set the timer for 10 minutes at 10
minutes and take a spatula in just gonna
rotate the the asparagus a little bit
to make sure that once I doesn't get for
a crispy
and then I'm gonna put it back in the
oven anywhere from five to ten minutes
and if it starts to look to brown then
applied at five minutes usually I cook
it for the full 20 min
rock ok alright so we just take the S
various other
lovin at 10 minutes we take this very
guess just wrote it make sure wasn't
burning
and then at fifteen minutes we checked
again and what I like to look for is to
make sure that the
girl xr6 can turn brown a little bit an
actual 15 minutes
ours looks good so you can cook at 15
and up to 20 minutes so we take our
a fifteen-minute and than what I do
is a test is my satchel and
the asparagus fun to play
asparagus is a little bit senator which
is probably why we were able to take out
50 minutes to
there's burgers is a little bit thicker
you probably want to go closer towards
20-minute mark
in this looks really good and clean up a
super easy idea of
for aluminum foil third in the trash
in this looks really good so I'm gonna
try it
and you can serve this warm or a
conservative elders law
has really good you can find the full
recipe on the page below
in for more recipes and nutritional tips
keep taking up by building not come