Hi.
I'm Jamie Eason.
Welcome to the
bodybuilding.com kitchen.
Today I'm gonna make my
Pumpkin Protein Bars.
I know I've been making a
whole lot of different types
of protein bars, but I don't
want you to get burned out
so I've got this brand new one.
This one actually makes a larger
portion than the 8x8 we've been
using so we're gonna get a
bigger Pyrex dish this time.
I've prepped this by
spraying non-stick spray.
It's a 9x13, and I've
also preheated the oven
to 350 degrees.
So this one's easy because
it's all in one large bowl.
See, first we've got
2 cups of oat flour.
Again, oat flour is just ground
up oatmeal, and you can buy it
at the store in
the healthy section.
You can make your own by
grinding it in a coffee grinder
or in a blender.
So I'm just gonna put that in.
Two cups.
And then I've got 2 scoops
of a vanilla whey protein.
You can use any
flavor that you like.
For me, I just look for the
fewer ingredients the better
'cause then it's healthier
and usually it tastes a little
better too.
So 2 scoops of that.
And then I'm gonna start
putting in all of the flavoring
ingredients.
I've got 2 teaspoons
of cinnamon,
1 1/2 teaspoons of
ground ginger,
1/2 teaspoon of cloves.
Cloves are pretty strong, but I
think that's really what gives
this its flavor.
So then we've got a teaspoon of
baking soda and a teaspoon of
baking powder and then
1/2 teaspoon of salt.
For my sweetener, I'm actually
adding 1/2 cup of Xylitol.
You can use the
brown sugar blend.
You can use the regular.
I actually like the brown sugar
blend for this recipe a lot, but
you can't always find it.
This one is just the regular
half cup of Xylitol so put that
in.
I'm gonna mix up these dry
ingredients really well.
Okay.
And then to this I'm gonna start
adding the wet ingredients.
You can mix these in separate
bowls if you like, but it's
really not necessary so I'm just
gonna put it all right in the
same bowl.
First thing, I'm gonna
start with four egg whites.
You can use the liquid
egg whites if you like.
I used regular, real eggs.
I kinda like those better for
baking, but it's up to you.
Then I'm gonna add
1/2 cup of almond milk.
You can use
whatever kind you want.
You can do regular milk.
You can do rice milk.
Whatever you'd like, but
I like the almond milk
so 1/2 cup of that.
And then to that I'm gonna add
one 4 ounce of the baby food
applesauce.
You can use regular unsweetened
applesauce at home if you have
that.
Put that in there.
It comes out to probably about
1/4 cup if you're gonna
us the jar at home.
To that I'm gonna
add my pumpkin.
I've used a whole 15 ounce can
of pumpkin for this so you can
use as little or as
much as you want.
I really like mine really
pumpkiny so I use the whole
entire can.
Make sure, too, that you pick
the raw pumpkin and not the
pumpkin pie mix
that's loaded with sugar.
So put that in.
Then my final wet ingredient is
just 2 teaspoons of vanilla.
So I've got all of those in.
You can use the whisk if you
like, but I don't wanna make a
mess so I'm just gonna fold
it all in with my spatula.
Okay.
Starting to come together.
And for this recipe, you can use
nuts or you can do it without
nuts.
I'm gonna put
some walnuts in it.
I really like pumpkin
and walnut together.
So I've got it all mixed up.
I've already put 1/2 cup
of walnuts in a little baggie.
So the reason I've done this is
because I didn't buy the crushed
up kind.
I'm gonna actually
crush these myself.
So I like to buy the
ones from the bin.
Usually they're a little bit
more fresh than the ones that
have been sitting on
the shelf for a while.
So I just put them in a bag.
You can grab anything you like.
I like my little rolling pin.
Just sort of crush
them a little bit.
If you're worried about adding
too much fat to your dessert,
you actually don't
have to mix them in.
You can put it all together and
just maybe sprinkle half on one
side or just lightly
sprinkle them on top.
I like to mix mine in because I
like there to be nuts in every
bite, but it's
totally up to you.
That's pretty good.
Getting there.
Maybe a little smaller.
Alright.
Now I'll just dump these in.
Now the difference though--if
you make it with or without
nuts--with nuts, you're
looking at probably
about 67, 68 calories.
Without nuts, you're
looking at under 50.
It's about 47 calories.
So it's totally up to you, but
the fat isn't that different and
the amount of protein
really isn't that different.
It's like about 4 grams
of protein a bar.
This makes 24 bars, by the way.
So I've got that all mixed in.
And I'm gonna get my dish ready
and just pour it in the pan.
Okay.
I'll get it all spread out.
Now this one you wanna bake it
for about 30 minutes I would
say, but it's totally up to you.
Some people like the bars a
little bit more soft, and some
people like them a
little more cooked through.
I suggest that if you're
traveling with these,
definitely keep them in the oven
a little bit longer 'cause you
want them to hold up.
Put these in the oven.
Bake it for about 30 minutes.
Think that's right.
And then we'll check
it in about 30 minutes.
Always make sure when you're
baking that your oven rack is
like usually in the middle.
If it's too close to the heating
element on the bottom, it'll
burn.
And if it's too high up, it'll
take forever to cook so we will
check on it in about 30 minutes.
Alright.
The timer went off.
Let's check our bars.
Alright.
They look good.
I'm pretty sure these are done,
but if you wanna make sure you
can stick a toothpick in it.
If it comes out dry with no
wetness or anything, it's pretty
much ready.
So I'm gonna let these cool and
then we'll come back, cut them,
and I'll show you
how to wrap them up.
Okay.
Our Pumpkin Protein Bars are
fully cooled so I'm gonna cut
them up.
Let's see.
We've got--it's gonna make 24
squares so I'm gonna make 3 cuts
lengthwise and 5 this way.
Alright.
Scoop a few of these out.
They look really good.
You can see some of
the nuts in there.
And then I'm gonna
wrap up the rest.
Show you how I wrap
them when I travel.
Be sure to store these in a
cool place like the frigerator
because if you leave them just
out on the counter or not in
your cooler,
they'll actually spoil.
There's no preservatives
or anything in these.
I do them by twos.
I just place two on the saran
wrap, fold over the one end, and
roll it over, and then fold
in the edges and--it's pretty
simple.
Okay.
I'm gonna finish up
wrapping up the rest of these.
For this recipe, you can
check out the link below.
And if you wanna check out other
recipes and articles, just visit
bodybuilding.com.