Okay, so today I'm here
with Maureen and Bria--my client
Maureen and her
daughter, she's 10 years old.
Maureen is 38.
And so we're gonna be doing
kale chips, cacao kale chips.
This was my little phenomenal
recipe that I developed.
They're just grabbing two
bunches of kale chips--raw,
organic kale.
And taking off the
leafs, putting it in here.
So I'm gonna let
them work away at that.
So kale is a super food.
You know, people always
ask, "What's a super food?"
There isn't one super food,
but this is definitely a very
nutritious food, and it's
got a lot of phytonutrients,
disease-fighting properties,
which is what we want.
So cacao kale chips, again,
two bunches of kale, you've got
coconut oil.
And again, another
oil of your choice.
You can do, even, an
almond oil if you want.
I have almond meal, as well.
Then I have some stevia and
organic cacao powder that we're
gonna be mixing in.
So with kale chips, a lot of
times I see people on social
media posting, you know, that
they put them in their oven, put
them at 350.
That is a choice for you, you
can do that for about 10 or 15
minutes.
However, I'm gonna tell you
the importance of why getting a
dehydrator is actually
gonna help with getting those
nutrients in.
So I have my Excalibur with
me, which Santa brought to me 2
years ago.
And thankful for that.
The importance of a dehydrator
is it doesn't kill the enzymes.
And the enzymes are so important
because it keeps the nutrients
alive.
The whole reason we're eating
vegetables is because of the
powerhouse foods that they are.
So when you're cooking them
above a certain level, you're
actually killing
all the nutrients.
So again, I'm 40 years old, I
didn't have all these tools when
I was in my 20s or 30s, so it's,
you know, over time I've made an
investment in certain pieces
of equipment that have actually
helped my kitchen and the
foods I eat work better for me.
So, Maureen, how do you
incorporate kale for your
family?
Well, for Bria I put it on
her sandwich for school for her
lunch.
And at home, just for dinner
instead of lettuce, or I even
mix it with other types of
lettuce, spinach or mustard
greens.
And we can have it in a salad,
we can have it with turkey
burger, chicken.
That sounds good.
I'm gonna have to get
some recipes from you.
Okay, so Bria, do you like kale.
Yeah.
You don't, like, throw it
in the garbage 'cause you're at
school and Mom can't see
that you're not eating it?
No, I eat it in my sandwich.
Very good, very good.
So there you have it, a great
way to get kale in for your kids
to enjoy it.
So let's go ahead, if you wanna
go ahead and grab the other
ingredients here.
Let's get the
almond meal in here.
I'm gonna help these guys while
they're going ahead and getting
off all the leafs.
So again, I'm putting in a
couple tablespoons here.
So, like I said, measuring
great, but overtime, you know,
an extra tablespoon or 2,
it's not gonna hurt you.
You wanna put some stevia?
Go ahead and sprinkle that in.
So again, some stevia to taste.
And then I've got
the cacao powder.
So again, if you love
chocolate, it's great.
And then I'm gonna go
ahead and pour the oil in.
Again, you can measure and do a
couple tablespoons, but again I
want all that powder to stick.
Three people making kale chips.
This is a good
workout for the arms.
Okay.
We good?
Awesome.
So here, I love these mixing
bowls, they're my favorite.
Okay, who wants to shake it up?
You're the dancing
queen, let's go.
Shake it up.
There we go!
Fun in the kitchen
with Bria and Maureen.
So, when they're done, you're
gonna see, like I said, you can
put 'em in the oven.
And I'm gonna have
you scoot forward here.
So why don't you go ahead,
open that up, let them see.
So this is how they look.
And you can kind of mix
it up a little bit more.
But when they're done,
they're nice and crispy.
And a crunch--they're so good.
So good.
Go ahead, grab one.
Delicious.
So thanks for joining us
on "Nicole's Healthy Minutes."