[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="10" title="Healthy Recipes- Blueberry Protein Pancakes " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FaPX7_KslTo" mode="non-automatic">
I'm Natalie Hodson, here today in the bodybuilding.com kitchen showing you how to make a recipe that I make a lot of mornings, and it's my Blueberry Protein Pancake.<s>
This is a really good recipe.<s>
If you're getting tired of the same old <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient> and <B-Ingredient>oats</B-Ingredient>.<s>
This uses the exact same ingredients.<s>
It just mixes them into a different way.<s>
I know there's a lot of protein pancake recipes out there, but I like this one because it uses all whole foods and it tastes really good.<s>
These are all the ingredients that we're gonna use for today's recipe.<s>
We're gonna use 6 <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient>, and <B-Amount>1/2</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of old fashion <B-Ingredient>oats</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I like the old fashion oats better than the <B-Ingredient>instant</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oats</I-Ingredient> just because they're a little bit less processed.<s>
The <B-Ingredient>instant</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>oats</I-Ingredient> have actually been cooked and dehydrated to make them cook faster, and these haven't.<s>
They've just been rolled.<s>
We have 1/4 cup of <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient>.<s>
You can use fresh or frozen or you can substitute it for <B-Ingredient>raspberries</B-Ingredient> or <B-Ingredient>strawberries</B-Ingredient>.<s>
We have 1/2 cup of <B-Ingredient>unsweetened</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>vanilla almond milk</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And just make sure that when you get the <B-Ingredient>almond</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>, you're getting the unsweetened vanilla kind.<s>
I like the Almond Breeze brand.<s>
It's 40 calories, has no sugar in it.<s>
Also, if you wanted, you could substitute <B-Ingredient>milk</B-Ingredient>, but I prefer the <B-Ingredient>almond</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And then we have <B-Amount>1</B-Amount> <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>baking</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>.<s>
This is just to help the pancakes rise a little bit.<s>
Two packets of <B-Ingredient>Truvia</B-Ingredient>.<s>
This is to make them a little bit sweeter.<s>
I have 1/2 cup of <B-Ingredient>unsweetened</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>applesauce</I-Ingredient> and just a dash of <B-Ingredient>cinnamon</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And those two items we're gonna save 'til the end and use it as a topping on top of the pancakes.<s>
So for today's recipe, I'm actually gonna use a blender to mix everything together.<s>
And I'm gonna start with my liquid ingredients.<s>
Gonna pour in my <B-Ingredient>almond</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>, and then I'm going to do my <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And I'm just gonna crack these right into the blender.<s>
Now some people just throw their yolks away into the trash can.<s>
I actually like to put mine in the garbage disposal, and I found that out the hard way.<s>
I used to just throw my yolks into the trash can, and one day I came home and my house smelled really bad and I couldn't figure out why.<s>
And it's because I left the yolks in the trash can for too long, and so now what I do is I'll just put them right into the garbage disposal.<s>
Some people like to feed the <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>yolks</I-Ingredient> to their dog, and I guess that helps with their coat and makes it a little bit shinier.<s>
And this is a really good breakfast recipe if you have kids.<s>
I have a 2 year-old and he loves this recipe.<s>
We eat it a couple times a week.<s>
And it's a really good way to incorporate some whole grains into their diet, and the <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient> has some really good antioxidants.<s>
Another thing you can do is you can make these in bulk on the weekend, and then freeze them.<s>
I think they taste a little bit better fresh but you definitely can freeze them.<s>
And when I do that I just put them in a Ziploc bag and then when I wanna eat them, I stick them in the microwave for about a minute.<s>
Alright.<s>
So we have 6 <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Then I'm just gonna add my <B-Ingredient>oats</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And I'm gonna save the <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient> until we're actually in the griddle.<s>
I'm gonna add my <B-Ingredient>baking</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>powder</I-Ingredient>.<s>
I'm just gonna do <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>dash</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>salt</B-Ingredient>.<s>
It's probably about 1/8 of a <B-Unit>teaspoon</B-Unit> if you were to measure it.<s>
And then two packets of <B-Ingredient>Truvia</B-Ingredient>.<s>
If you want to eat the pancakes without any applesauce on top, you could add a third pack of <B-Ingredient>Truvia</B-Ingredient>.<s>
It would make your pancakes sweet so you wouldn't need to add the <B-Ingredient>applesauce</B-Ingredient> on top.<s>
And then I'm just gonna blend this really fast.<s>
Alright.<s>
I'm quickly gonna turn my skillet on to about medium-high heat.<s>
Then I'm just gonna spray it with <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> little <B-Unit>bit</B-Unit> of non-stick <B-Ingredient>cooking</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>spray</I-Ingredient>.<s>
And then I'm just gonna take my batter and--this recipe makes two pancakes.<s>
Two pancakes is one serving so usually just kinda eyeball it.<s>
And put about half of the batter in the skillet, and then I'm gonna take half of my <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient> and just drop them in the top.<s>
You can blend these, the <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient>, in too if you want.<s>
I've done that before, but I think it tastes a little better this way.<s>
Makes them a little bit juicier.<s>
So we're just gonna let this cook.<s>
Usually you can tell they're ready to flip when there's bubbles in the center of the pancake.<s>
So I went ahead and flipped the pancake.<s>
We've been cooking it about 1 to 2 minutes on each side.<s>
And sometimes the first pancake doesn't flip quite as well as the second pancake, and it's because sometimes in the blender the <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient> tend to kinda stay at the top and the <B-Ingredient>oats</B-Ingredient> fall to the bottom, but this one turned out pretty good.<s>
So I'm just gonna take the pancake and put it on my plate.<s>
I'll flip it I guess.<s>
That side's not quite as pretty.<s>
And then I'm gonna go ahead and put my second pancake in.<s>
I'm just gonna blend it for just a second to get everything shaken up.<s>
Gonna spray my pan with the spray.<s>
Then I'm just gonna pour the rest of my batter in.<s>
Make sure to get all those oats out.<s>
And I'm gonna add the rest of my <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient>.<s>
And we're just gonna let it cook about 1 to 2 minutes per side.<s>
You know it's ready to flip once the edges look like they're cooked all the way through and there's bubbles starting to form in the center of the pancake.<s>
Alright.<s>
So we are done cooking our second pancake.<s>
I'm gonna go ahead and put it on the plate.<s>
Oops.<s>
As you can see, this is a lot of food.<s>
This is another reason I like this recipe is 'cause it's really great way to start the day with a nice hearty meal.<s>
And then--the pancakes are really sweet on their own I think, and so a lot of times I'll actually eat these even without any applesauce on top.<s>
You can use sugar free syrup if you want, but I prefer to stay away from that just because it has a lot of preservatives in it.<s>
So sometimes if I want a little extra something on top, I'll use <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>unsweetened</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>applesauce</I-Ingredient>.<s>
Just make sure you get the applesauce that says no sugar added or <B-Ingredient>unsweetened</B-Ingredient> or if you read the ingredient list, the only ingredients are apples, water, and maybe ascorbic acid which helps keep the coloring.<s>
So I'm just gonna go with this half of a <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>applesauce</B-Ingredient>.<s>
I'm just gonna pour it on top.<s>
Sometimes I like to put a little bit underneath.<s>
And then I like cinnamon so I'm gonna put a dash of <B-Ingredient>cinnamon</B-Ingredient> on top.<s>
You don't have to do that if you don't like <B-Ingredient>cinnamon</B-Ingredient>.<s>
Sprinkle a little <B-Ingredient>cinnamon</B-Ingredient> on top and there you go.<s>
You have a really good breakfast.<s>
One serving is 2 pancakes, and each serving has 6 <B-Ingredient>egg</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>whites</I-Ingredient>, and 1/2 <B-Amount>a</B-Amount> <B-Unit>cup</B-Unit> of <B-Ingredient>oats</B-Ingredient>, <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>blueberries</B-Ingredient>, and <B-Amount>some</B-Amount> <B-Ingredient>almond</B-Ingredient> <I-Ingredient>milk</I-Ingredient>.<s>
So to get this Blueberry Protein Pancake recipe, you can check out the link on the page below, and continue to go to bodybuilding.com to find all of my other recipes as well as nutritional information, workout programs, and motivation.<s></transcript></transcripts>