and I'll add them I'm thinking I've got
a new variation on potato salad for you
it just at the potato salad has a posted
on Instagram
I love you were like pay our know how to
make that so I wanna show you know just
in time for the weekend for our love
your cooking and grilling out
stuff they're not even inviting me to
injure the
that
when I so for the potato salad and got
some potatoes
there in that hot Harry boil them
appreciation thing I do that
meanwhile we're gonna make this stress
things that got a man is in here if you
don't you mean and you can use our crane
and a monad San apple cider vinegar
is my favorite vinegars I like to get
the one at unpasteurized
that's how I really did probiotics in it
that means it's good for your intestines
and lol well and some mastered this is a
fun little mustard
that Susan sent from germany and it's
got pink peppercorns and green
peppercorns and
f you can't find the switch I've never
seen it
and the US cell mispriced you can just
use some have brown deli mustard
be very similar about tailspin that in
because that's just bad see
we're gonna Shealy hey outer and this is
just
at Ground New Mexico Chile para thou
any additional staff in it PID have
deduced
that's not terribly spicy but it's got a
nice earthy flavor
and then for this path a little bit a
kind
an ass optional and now leading up to
your day so that was a few dashes
ansohn black pepper sisters got multiple
types
peppers and super fun and
salt more get the swift whisked
with two here web
pay we can set that I'm and
cut up our potatoes so I boiled sign red
fingerling containers thats fingerling
gentlemen I'm not only the skins on you
could use
a some read new potatoes or something
like that to you or someone taters bet
why a rare yukon gold there are really
nice for potato salad
same income lengthwise just basically
bite size pieces
and its best to dress potatoes
mix it up the dressing want details are
still a little bit warm
because that way they'll absorb more the
flavors from there
dressing one the potatoes are on their
way back since salary
and you know you can have this app me
also as you want to know
aren't cuddling client and and and sorta
smallish squares that
below and Manama and this time
red onion that they step to try to come
to keep other nationals except celery
red get it spicy red
Devils cupid's okay
some fresh red bell pepper enemies are
Peppa do
peppers which are it look like chair
covers but they're
not really very spicy are and they're
usually
packed and kinda Swedish Brian so
they've got a nice flavor profile that's
pretty calm plaque
you can buy manage our were at your
grocery store has won a psych fancy
am I love parse they're usually also
there
said that a couple those you could
totally use some cherry peppers
instead although they're gonna be hotter
than
to keep that in mind or sometimes you
can find pickled red how apenas
perfect that's all in there and then
start renowned Stannis ridiculously
small
for this job 19 any it don't answer that
here we go 22 meters have potato salad
the spiciness an extra vinegar goes
really well with ground me it's and
barbecue
like heavy meats like beef brisket or
lamb
airing girl there's bass a Butthead
Laila
hmm mmm so if you like
this recipe meter check out that Greek
pasta salad recipe that I just named
last week
and also check out I wouldn't think that
had anything at this point for SP
announcement posted
ain't grill plan rapid heat-up to
her alongside talent
turned out this weekend send me a
picture and way made
and I'll had for
with my clothes on
a
bad go
and that solicit detainee
refreshing it. I love it try it really
like thanks so much for watching please
don't forget have an hour you later
bad