kids & Highland today on high like a
game or making breakfast angela Attison
with potatoes entries on top with pride
and
the home into a fast these are gonna go
great with Alan your breakfast
margaritas well
home
well numero uno
that means number one and Spanish we're
gonna make our chili sauce I've got here
a couple have dried appear showing a
share
am pretty sweet and team delicious
just gonna break the stems of and I've
already given them a little rounds just
to get any like
dashed for pesticide residue or anything
like that often them since they're not
only can hack
Farid ji Zara mad
about Cup a water many online
our in Indio is bring this to a boil
when it boils on a
turn the heat off and just let sit for
about 10 minutes to get
and reconstituted I'm actually gonna
move this
this background while that happens
to a little magic switcheroo here
and work on new around here totally look
like
a number to hear right what this says
has not returned
and Sam trees assets from Fresh Mex
can't resist that urge
was gonna cook this overs or to
medium-high heat until
its cooked through and in relief fine
crumbles you can totally leave this out
and I've mean these vegetarian before
and they're
just delicious but am had some trees are
so many at it
dump
want most the fat has released you can
be pretty sure that it am
almost cut them in at some diced onion
and I just wanna
soften us a little bit i Sol I still
wanna keep sounds like they're
crunch integrity and the onion that
maybe not like Foley rocks onions
Alito like it 2009 like this every fight
for SP as long as you have
the chili sauce and the potatoes and he
then you could totally dissed by Kanye
Angeles ass and make enchiladas concern
for breakfast with an eye on top
I dealt give to Shia
okay SR water on that show is boiling
that's great I'm gonna drop in a couple
clubs
a brother like just like that you
to look back on it turn it off and just
let it sit there for 10 minutes to get
softened up companions are going just
barely translucent we go ahead and turn
the heat off
and I've got to red potatoes here that I
and boil
a couple days ago and then peel
and has cut into pretty big kid and then
also can add San
baby spinach tear it up there year
rose I want my money back but like I
said yeah like this is totally still
hurting me know if you leave
you know just leave the jury's out to
meet is not
in 10 role integral now and take it out
it's not and necessary for the SP to
work just a little
extra bonus test results and you make
any on I just a plan that for 2014
pass it on can a mash-up those potato
chunks a little bit
to help this feeling stick together and
that's just going to make it easier to
rollout do
Hannah laughing a man to the filling is
some crumbled up could he had she is
and this is a Mexican she is it's very
firm and salty
Penn around me and a man's dick cats
furman faulty ok anyway
that I'm just imagining that merman have
perpetual by respecting my
just a little bit that maybe announcer
cell dad and I saltiness
so whenever any other saltiness because
between the trees and the QWERTY however
we've got it made but if you were
leading
either one of those out in power went
out a little bit assault mix at around
and this is not a melting cheese it
stays in chunks and I just coming it's
soft
so add a nice little text rolled by in a
little chewy like
cheese curd kinda feel you can use
either
types to choose to use
scam pulling out by the tip good at it
and let all that feeds dropout you could
leave a man if you want and
a release by fast that i dont me this
isn't going to be like super
hi the papers have a really nice free
Fleener
and a little garlic cloves that I drop
down
so they'll still have a little bit %uh
Veron after them but they're not gonna
be like so
sharp and spicy so
add to start with about a half a cup
the soaking liquid and that's why I
wrenched these papers of first because
you want to be able to use this liquid
but not at Fulham weird gross ship just
give it a renowned
huh
important safety net when year and
blending hot things in a blender
pressure buildup and I'll in control of
so make sure that you are allowed to
like a vent
to space RF leaving a little thing like
that or if you don't have like a little
cap you can
just cover the blender with like a towel
or something
double that say don't spider your hand
with hot liquid okay
safety lesson over
world I've now it's loud okay gonna
check the conflict in
CE I don't pretty good melville is she
also I'm gonna add a little bit assaults
unique or did he spare cell and that's
it are soft is done
so nevertheless magically and goes over
there
and then for that anti-apartheid got
some quite Proteus
typically are traditionally there sort
of like
warmed up and softened and some warm why
all the freeroll the
enchiladas I have a cheer white
chromatid
and can actually spray them up with a
little bit us pretty well
food to through
who clue
who and then stick on a migraine for
about 30 seconds and you will see how
beautifully pliable they become
okay says see these are nice and hot
softie now your mileage may vary my
needed put in for a little bit longer
sixty seconds or so
but looks good to me time you put it
well above our soft down here and he
just like me
dredge each tortilla in a little bit at
the sauce
it's going to be like Messi don't wear
your best shirt
couple tablespoons earlier filling mmm
ship it on that a lot of times when I'm
just making these for Chris and I i
Justi like a half batch
and I won't even bother like heating up
in the analyst do it on a plate
and Mike microwave them or something
do
to this last one you gonna do a little
maneuvering
a little Whodini ng to get it covered
but you can't do it
I promise you'll manage more a movie n
now it's gonna pour the rest the sauce
over the top well maybe save a little
bit back as it looks really pretty it
when you travel with the and you know a
little bit more sauce
on top in the egg to you K gorgeous
alright method is in heaven
month really just until I have some
eggs fried or poached her Harry wanna do
on the phone if video
recipe tet how to fry an egg in a cast
iron skillet you happy and butter
do not screw around with oil and finance
and a cast iron skillet I have no idea
why doesn't work
but it doesn't work have to use backup
Sherman to get a million comment on me
I'm totally wrong but in my kitchen
I have to use better or the eggs just
stick in the making huge mess
he never over pretty hi he and what this
better
can have it'll get a little for me and
then the phone will subside
don't let me down but her do what I said
field okay I think that on a nap
sort of popping and stuff me almost
about to turn brown
that's good
30 put a dent in it starts popping like
that that's good it means you're
probably not gonna have your egg stick
to the pan
enough to mean you're probably at some
across the ground that's what I
personally like pat down anyone
anti-poaching Yanks or
night cast iron skillet just gonna
sharing it
the handle will get hot eventually if
Ryan much Excel
have to be like me and beyond student
turn the heat down
thats having too much so let's get the
bottoms of that
white getting like this and then
good like that turn the heat off
immediately
that residual heat gonna keep cooking
and so it's not like totally done
I get my into a lot of money and track
enchiladas are done scrunched at
that's okay in and his staff down na
minha Cara with
hopefully still runny egg hun
I'll just do that perfect okay
nato breakfast enchiladas I cannot wait
to dig in I have
many other enchilada recipe is on mine
website
and on videos and also check out my and
breakfast
playlist if you are so inclined let's go
and see if they get this or any
K not running exactly but its
waste why does that work restaurant not
so much
okay kid honest good staff gonna take a
big ol how can I
get p.m. Kenyan fork
forecast trader in me numb
that is I'm talking about this is what I
want for breakfast
evander come stay at your house like
impromptu
like Ben back to session and I want you
to make me okay
thanks thanks for watching please
subscribe if you haven't already check
out how to begin for printable recipe is
and I'll see guess next time bad
when pay what the crab favorite Mexican
did
pinch a lot of get it