[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="12" title="Healthy Recipes- Chocolate Peanut Butter Protein Crisps - Bars " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PlJPzEmQFGM" mode="non-automatic">
[music] Hi, I'm Jamie Eason and today I'm in the BODYBUILDING.COM kitchen and I'm showing you how to make my <entity type="Recipe">chocolate peanut butter protein crisps</entity>.<s>
In a previous video I showed you how to make my honey, almond, protein crisps.<s>
But now we're gonna use two of my other favorite ingredients: <entity type="Ingredient">chocolate</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">peanut butter</entity>.<s>
So, let's get started.<s>
The ingredients for our <entity type="Recipe">chocolate, peanut butter, protein crisps</entity> are <entity type="Amount">three</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of a <entity type="Ingredient">crispy brown rice</entity>, we've got <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">whole oats</entity>, <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity> of a <entity type="Ingredient">vanilla whey protein powder</entity>, we've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> crushed <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity>, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">peanut butter</entity> right here, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">cocoa</entity>, and <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity>, and somewhere around here I've got my <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
That's all you're gonna need, so let's get started.<s>
To start I've put <entity type="Amount">3</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of the <entity type="Ingredient">crispy brown rice</entity>.<s>
And just so you see.<s>
You can have a reference.<s>
This is the <entity type="Ingredient">crispy brown rice</entity> I used.<s>
It's gluten-free, organic.<s>
It's got very few ingredients in it.<s>
It does have a little bit of sugar.<s>
It's natural sugar.<s>
It's got organic molasses and evaporated cane juice.<s>
But it's 2 grams per serving.<s>
There's 3/4 of a cup in a serving, so you've got less than 5 grams of natural sugar in the whole entire recipe, so not bad.<s>
It makes 18 servings.<s>
So, we've started with that, put that in.<s>
And then I've got my <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">whole oats</entity>.<s>
I'm gonna put that on top.<s>
And then I'm gonna add <entity type="Amount">1/4</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of crushed <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity>.<s>
So, if you don't have crushed almonds, you can actually just take your own <entity type="Ingredient">almonds</entity>, you know, scoop out <entity type="Amount">1/4</entity> of a <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of those and just beat them with a rolling pin.<s>
You can use the back of a pot, whatever you have.<s>
And then, on top of that I'm gonna add <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">vanilla whey protein powder</entity>.<s>
I kind of sprinkle that on top, spread it around a bit.<s>
Now, do not mix this up.<s>
We don't want to make all of the <entity type="Ingredient">protein powder</entity> settle to the bottom.<s>
So, I just give it a gentle shake and then I'm gonna set it to the side.<s>
So, now I'm gonna switch out to a smaller bowl and in this bowl--now make sure you use a glass bowl.<s>
That's important because we're gonna need to put it in the microwave.<s>
So, we're gonna start out with our main ingredient, which is an all natural, <entity type="Ingredient">unsalted creamy peanut butter</entity>.<s>
You can use chunky if you like, but the chunky actually doesn't seem to mix up quite as well.<s>
But I have made it and it tastes really good too.<s>
So, it's just your preference.<s>
There's a lot of natural oil that comes up from the peanuts, so we're gonna pour a little bit of that off.<s>
Don't pour it all out though, because you'll really have a hard time mixing it up.<s>
So, I'm gonna go ahead and mix it--see, it's already kind of hard.<s>
Let's see.<s>
I have to get the muscle in there.<s>
Mix it up a bit.<s>
Alright.<s>
And so, we're gonna actually take <entity type="Amount">3/4</entity> of a <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of a creamy, all natural <entity type="Ingredient">peanut butter</entity> and add that to the bowl.<s>
So, I like to use my little smaller scoop.<s>
I think it's more manageable, but you can use a <entity type="Unit">measuring cup</entity> and just measure to <entity type="Amount">3/4</entity>.<s>
So, I'm going to scoop it out and put it in there.<s>
This one looks slightly chunky, slightly smooth, so I think I needed to maybe stir it up a little longer.<s>
Sometimes I've been known to heat it up a little bit in the microwave just to get it going, but--let's see.<s>
So, we've got our 1/4 going.<s>
Do some more.<s>
And you don't have to be super, super careful with the measurements in this actual recipe.<s>
You can add a little, take away a little if you want.<s>
I've actually figured out the ratios just to have just enough so you don't have to--they don't end up too dry, 'cause we want them to stick together a bit.<s>
We're trying to make that <entity type="Ingredient">crispy rice</entity> and everything kind of all come together, so that when we freeze it, it actually makes this crunchy, crispy, kind of granola.<s>
I've almost got it all out.<s>
This one's more challenging that the <entity type="Ingredient">almond butter</entity>.<s>
Now, with that said, you could use the <entity type="Ingredient">almond butter</entity> if you'd like.<s>
And you can actually add extracts.<s>
So, if you wanted to make say <entity type="Ingredient">chocolate</entity> with like <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">orange</entity>--hint of orange or something or there's <entity type="Ingredient">coconut extracts</entity>.<s>
There's <entity type="Ingredient">bananas</entity>--maybe <entity type="Ingredient">chocolate</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">peanut butter</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">banana</entity> might be pretty good.<s>
You could actually use little pieces of <entity type="Ingredient">banana</entity> if you'd like too.<s>
But they will get a little mushy and that'll make it not stick together as well.<s>
So, use that sparingly or do the <entity type="Ingredient">dried bananas</entity>.<s>
But, again, that's added sugar, so just be careful about how much you're using, 'cause we're already using quite <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">natural sugar</entity>.<s>
Next thing I'm gonna add is gonna be my <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
So, we're gonna do <entity type="Amount">1/2</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
So, since this is my <entity type="Amount">1/4</entity> <entity type="Unit">measuring scoop</entity> I'm gonna do 2 of these.<s>
So, we've got one.<s>
Need my little spatula.<s>
Now, <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity> is really, really, really good for you.<s>
I'm often asked about <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity> versus <entity type="Ingredient">agave</entity> and if <entity type="Ingredient">agave</entity> is better.<s>
I personally prefer <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
I think there's so many health benefits to it with the antioxidants.<s>
And it's good for your skin.<s>
It's a good antibacterial.<s>
There's just so many great things about it that I'd prefer to use it, 'cause <entity type="Ingredient">agave</entity> in truth it'll still spike your blood sugar.<s>
So, be careful because a lot of times some of those labels can be misleading and make you think that that's a better choice, but it actually still pretty much does the same thing.<s>
So, alright, we've got those two ingredients in the bowl and now I'm gonna add <entity type="Amount">1/2</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> actually of xylitol brown sugar blend.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Xylitol</entity> is a sweetener.<s>
It comes from like raspberries, plums.<s>
It's a natural fructose sweetener.<s>
And it's actually a sugar alcohol.<s>
It does not have quite as many calories as regular sugar, but it still will have a slight insulin spike.<s>
It's just a little bit better for you.<s>
It is organic.<s>
It is natural.<s>
They actually use it in toothpaste 'cause it's good for our teeth.<s>
So, I'm gonna dump that in.<s>
and the <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity> part adds a little bit of molasses flavor to what we're making.<s>
If you really prefer, you can look for something like <entity type="Ingredient">organic sucanat</entity>, which it has 15 calories per teaspoon.<s>
So you're adding some calories, but it's less sweetness as far as like less grams of sugar, but it also tastes less sweet.<s>
So, you might end up having to use more.<s>
So, for me I just like to use this and just kind of eat it sparingly, so.<s>
Alright.<s>
Into that I want to add--let's see we've got <entity type="Ingredient">vanilla</entity>.<s>
I'm gonna do <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">teaspoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">vanilla</entity>.<s>
And then I'm going to add my <entity type="Ingredient">chocolate</entity>.<s>
Now, the chocolate the preference is up to you.<s>
You can add <entity type="Amount">a couple</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity>.<s>
You can add <entity type="Amount">a lot</entity> of <entity type="Unit">tablespoons</entity>.<s>
You can use <entity type="Ingredient">dark chocolate</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">Hershey's chocolate</entity>, whatever kind you'd like to use.<s>
Some people like <entity type="Ingredient">cacao</entity>.<s>
You could use anything you'd like.<s>
So, I'm gonna open that up.<s>
Let's do 3 of those.<s>
I prefer for the recipe to use <entity type="Ingredient">dark chocolate</entity>.<s>
So, if you can find the <entity type="Ingredient">unsweetened dark chocolate</entity>, I think that's probably your best bet.<s>
So, I'm gonna stir this up just a little bit just to get the dry stuff incorporated a little.<s>
And then we want to stick this in the microwave for just about 30 seconds just to kind of soften it up.<s>
So, I can stir it all together.<s>
Alright, let's stir this together a bit.<s>
You want to get all of the dry ingredients incorporated into the wet, so it's doing pretty well.<s>
You might have to stick it in there for maybe another 30 seconds to really get it pliable.<s>
I think I'm gonna do that with--when you add all of the <entity type="Ingredient">cocoa</entity> and everything it's not quite as liquefied as one of the other recipes that we made like the honey, almond, protein crisps.<s>
So, let me stick that back in for 30 more seconds.<s>
Don't do the minute all at once, because you could burn your <entity type="Ingredient">chocolate</entity> and we definitely don't want that.<s>
Alright.<s>
Let's stir this together a bit.<s>
Yeah, that's much easier to stir.<s>
So, now that I've got it all out, I'm gonna go ahead and pour that on top of our dry ingredients.<s>
There we go.<s>
Now it's pouring.<s>
It smells really good.<s>
I could probably just eat the <entity type="Ingredient">chocolate</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">peanut butter</entity>, but--let's see.<s>
This one I don't share with my dog, 'cause she can't have chocolate.<s>
So, I'm gonna fold the dry ingredients over the top.<s>
I like to do the little folding technique, 'cause it keeps my spatula from getting too sticky right off the bat.<s>
Alright.<s>
And it doesn't look like much.<s>
You have to really work it to start getting all the wet ingredients incorporated into the dry.<s>
So, it might take a little bit of work, a little bit of muscle.<s>
So, I think I've almost got it all done.<s>
If you can see the <entity type="Ingredient">protein powder</entity> still in there, you've got to probably keep stirring, which I can.<s>
So, I'm gonna keep going a second.<s>
It might look a bit dry and you don't want to add a lot of liquid though, because if you do, it'll end up getting too soft and fall apart.<s>
So, I think it looks pretty good.<s>
Now, we end up putting this in the freezer so it can get hard, but do know that after a while if you take it out of the freezer, it's gonna get softer and softer and it still tastes awesome.<s>
It's just not quite the same texture, because of course the peanut butter and everything softens up a little bit.<s>
So, I think we're good.<s>
And I'm gonna show you first and foremost how I make like one of the shapes.<s>
I brought just a little circle, 'cause that's a pretty easy one to demonstrate with.<s>
And I brought a pan.<s>
You don't need to prep your pan or do anything.<s>
You can just use your little circle.<s>
And then you just really you take a little bit in your fingers, push it down in there.<s>
It takes a little bit of time, but it's really pretty simple.<s>
And then you just want to firmly pack it in there.<s>
And as you push it all in then just gently kind of take the little loop off.<s>
You can see how it turns out.<s>
Turns out like that.<s>
And when it hardens up, it stays that way.<s>
And it's really nice you can pack them up.<s>
You can stack them together and wrap them up if you'd like.<s>
So, let me do another one of those.<s>
You could maybe alternate flavors.<s>
Do one kind of crisp and then do a different kind of flavored crisp.<s>
Alright, so I packed that in there.<s>
Wiggle it a little bit and there we go.<s>
So, I would fill up the rest of the tray and then stick that in the freezer.<s>
And I'm gonna finish working on these.<s>
Whatever I have left I'm gonna put in here and then I'll come right back.<s>
[music] Okay, the <entity type="Recipe">chocolate, peanut butter, protein crisp</entity> has been in the freezer for about an hour, so we're gonna go take that out.<s>
They look great.<s>
I took out the ones that we cut into shapes.<s>
So, now they're nice and frozen and solid, so.<s>
If you are making this and you actually keep it in one big dish, it makes about a serving of eighteen.<s>
For a single serving of these you're looking at 153 calories, about 7 grams of fat, 21.5 grams of carbohydrates, and about 5.6 grams of protein.<s>
So, I hope you like them.<s>
I hope you get creative and have a little bit of fun with it.<s>
And please come back and visit BODYBUILDING.COM for more information and content like this.<s>
[music]<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>