[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="16" title="Healthy Recipes- Frozen Spinach Cups " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gDz0uGSB_4k" mode="non-automatic">
I'm Natalie Hodson here in the bodybuilding.com kitchen showing you how to make <entity type="Recipe">Frozen Spinach Cups</entity>.<s>
This is a really easy--more of a tip than a recipe.<s>
I use this to thicken up my protein shakes, and it's great because when you put it in a protein shake, you really can't even taste it.<s>
Now it does turn your protein shakes green so if you have an issue with the color of your protein shake then you can add <entity type="Amount">a few</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">blueberries</entity> to it and it turns it purple and then you don't see the green color.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Spinach</entity> is a green, dark green leafy vegetable which is really good.<s>
It's high in vitamin A and it is really high in iron and calcium as well.<s>
So for the ingredients we're gonna use today, we're gonna use <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity> and usually I buy between <entity type="Amount">a</entity> 6 to an 8 ounce <entity type="Unit">bag</entity>.<s>
Different brands have different sizes that they sell but just <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Unit">bag</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity>.<s>
And then <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity>.<s>
And here I have <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">cups</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity>.<s>
And we might not use the full 2 cups.<s>
What we're gonna do is add the <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity> and slowly add the <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> until it's the consistency that we need.<s>
And then you're gonna need a blender, and then we're gonna use a muffin tin pan as well.<s>
And what we're gonna do is once we blend everything together, we're gonna pour the liquid into the muffin tin pan and then freeze it that way.<s>
Okay, so this recipe is really simple.<s>
All you do is you put your <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity> in the blender.<s>
And I just take handfuls and put it in.<s>
And you're gonna start by filling it about almost all the way full.<s>
My rule of thumb is about <entity type="Amount">1/2</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> per <entity type="Amount">2</entity> <entity type="Unit">handfuls</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity> so I just kinda pour the <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> in.<s>
There it looks like we used about <entity type="Amount">1</entity> <entity type="Unit">cup</entity> so we'll start with that and then slowly add <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> as we need to.<s>
And then you just put the lid on your blender.<s>
It's gonna be kinda loud.<s>
Alright.<s>
So as you can see, it really blends down quite a bit, and so what I'm gonna do is actually add some more <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity>.<s>
And so we're gonna add the rest of our <entity type="Ingredient">spinach</entity> in here.<s>
And then we're just gonna keep blending it.<s>
I don't think I need to add more water, but I'm just gonna kinda blend it.<s>
If it gets too thick--you basically want it just like a liquid consistency, maybe a little bit thicker.<s>
Not quite as thick as a milkshake consistency.<s>
Alright.<s>
I think this looks pretty good.<s>
Basically you just want it ground fine enough so you don't have big chunks of spinach.<s>
And then what I do is I take this, and I just pour it right into my muffin tin.<s>
And I usually fill these pretty much all the way full because what I do is, and I'll show you later, is I just use one in each of my protein shakes.<s>
Alright.<s>
So it looks like this made about six.<s>
And so we could double this if we wanted and make 12 and freeze all 12, but today I think we're just gonna make all 6.<s>
I'm gonna stick this in the freezer and then just let it freeze for about 3 hours.<s>
You can even leave it in there for longer if you aren't home after 3 hours.<s>
And then we're gonna pop these out and put them in Ziploc baggies to keep them in the freezer to use for our protein shakes later in the week.<s>
So I just took these spinach cups out of the freezer.<s>
They've been in the freezer for about 3 hours, and as you can tell, they're rock solid so you can do one of two things.<s>
You can just let them sit on the counter for a few minutes until they're melted a little bit and you can pop them out or what I like to do--it's a little bit faster--is I'm just gonna run the bottom of the pan underneath <entity type="Amount">some</entity> hot <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity>.<s>
Alright.<s>
That should do the trick.<s>
And then what I like to do is just take a butter knife.<s>
And obviously we're not gonna use all six of these spinach cups in a protein shake at once, and so I just take Ziploc bags and I put usually three or four of the spinach cups in a Ziploc bag and I put them in the freezer.<s>
So that way later when I go to make a protein shake, I can just grab one out.<s>
I also use these when I make smoothies, fruit smoothies for my 2-year old.<s>
It's one of the few ways I can get him to eat vegetables.<s>
So I'm just gonna pop the spinach cup out.<s>
That's what it looks like.<s>
And just gonna go ahead--it's a little bit messy, but you can just rinse your hands when you're done.<s>
So I'll probably do three in a bag.<s>
Sometimes I try to fit too many in there and I can't get it to zip.<s>
Oops.<s>
I'm gonna just put two in this bag and we're gonna save one to use in a protein shake today.<s>
To make the protein shake, I like to use <entity type="Ingredient">unsweetened almond milk</entity>.<s>
I like to use the kind with vanilla.<s>
Just make sure you get the one that has 35 or 40 calories, and read the ingredient list because some of the <entity type="Ingredient">almond milks</entity> do add sugar, and you wanna make sure it's the unsweetened kind without any sugar.<s>
But if you don't have almond milk, you could also use <entity type="Ingredient">water</entity> or regular <entity type="Ingredient">milk</entity>.<s>
I usually use about <entity type="Amount">8</entity> <entity type="Unit">ounces</entity> or so.<s>
I just kind of eyeball it.<s>
And then I'm gonna do <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Unit">scoop</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">whey protein</entity>.<s>
You can use these spinach cups with any flavor, any brand.<s>
And then instead of ice, I'm gonna use my <entity type="Recipe">frozen spinach cup</entity>.<s>
And then what it's gonna do is it's gonna thicken up the shake and also add some good vitamins: vitamin A, calcium, and iron.<s>
Just gonna blend it up.<s>
Alright.<s>
That looks pretty good.<s>
And then I'm just gonna pour it into my cup.<s>
So it does turn the shake a green color, and if that kinda weirds you out, you can add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">blueberries</entity> to this and then it turns it purple.<s>
And actually my son won't drink them if they're green, but if I add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">blueberries</entity> and it turns them purple, then he has no clue and he drinks them just fine so--tastes like a protein shake.<s>
You can't even taste the spinach at all.<s>
So for this tip and for all of my other recipes, check the link below and also continue to visit bodybuilding.com for nutritional information and motivation tips.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>