[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="33" title="Spicy Potato Salad |  Hilah Cooking " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tY2w5ho_Pzc" mode="non-automatic">
Hey dudes, I'm Hilah, and today on Hilah Cooking I've got a new variation on <entity type="Recipe">potato salad</entity> for you.<s>
It's a <entity type="Recipe">spicy potato salad</entity>, because I posted it on Instagram and a lot of people were like hey, I want to know how to make that.<s>
So, I'm going to show you just in time for the weekend for all of you who are cooking and grilling out some stuff that you're not even inviting me to, you jerks.<s>
Okay.<s>
For the <entity type="Recipe">potato salad</entity> I've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity>.<s>
They're in the pot.<s>
I already boiled them.<s>
I'm pretty sure you can figure out how to do that.<s>
Meanwhile, we're going to make this dressing.<s>
I've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">mayonnaise</entity> in here.<s>
If you don't want to use <entity type="Ingredient">mayonnaise</entity> you can use <entity type="Ingredient">sour cream</entity>.<s>
I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">apple cider vinegar</entity>.<s>
This is one of my favorite <entity type="Ingredient">vinegars</entity>, and I like to get the one that's unpasteurized because it's got a lot of really good probiotics in it.<s>
That means that it's good for your intestines.<s>
<entity type="Amount">A</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">olive oil</entity> and <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">mustard</entity>.<s>
This is a fun little <entity type="Ingredient">mustard</entity> that Suzanne sent me from Germany, and it's got pink peppercorns and green peppercorns in it.<s>
If you can't find this, which I've never seen it in the US so I wouldn't be surprised, you can just use some kind of <entity type="Ingredient">brown deli mustard</entity>.<s>
It would be very similar.<s>
About <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoon</entity> of that.<s>
Because this is spicy we're going to add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">chili powder</entity>.<s>
This is just <entity type="Ingredient">ground New Mexico chili powder</entity> without any additional stuff in it.<s>
Good, hefty dose of that.<s>
It's not terribly spicy, but it's got a nice earthy flavor.<s>
Then, for the spice, <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">cayenne</entity>, and that's optional.<s>
Leave it up to your taste.<s>
That was a few dashes.<s>
<entity type="Amount">Some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">black pepper</entity>.<s>
This has got multiple types of <entity type="Ingredient">peppers</entity> in it.<s>
Super fun.<s>
<entity type="Amount">Some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">salt</entity>.<s>
We'll get this whisked together.<s>
Okay.<s>
We can set that aside and cut up our <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity>.<s>
I boiled <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">red fingerling potatoes</entity>.<s>
That's fingerling, gentlemen.<s>
I'm going to leave the skins on.<s>
You could use <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">red new potatoes</entity> or something like that, too, or <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">white potatoes</entity>.<s>
White, or red, or Yukon gold, those are all really nice for <entity type="Recipe">potato salad</entity>.<s>
Let's see, maybe cut them lengthwise, just basically bite-size pieces.<s>
It's best to dress the <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity>, mix it up with the dressing while the <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity> are still a little bit warm, because that way they'll absorb more of the flavors from the dressing.<s>
Once the <entity type="Ingredient">potatoes</entity> are in there we've got <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">celery</entity>.<s>
You can cut this up any old size you want to.<s>
I like to cut them lengthwise and then in sort of smallish squares.<s>
Add that to the bowl, then I'm going to add <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">red onion</entity> that I've diced up.<s>
I tried to kind of keep all the <entity type="Ingredient">vegetables</entity> except the celery red.<s>
Get it?<s>
Because spicy, red, devils, cupids.<s>
Okay.<s>
<entity type="Amount">Some</entity> fresh <entity type="Ingredient">red bell pepper</entity>.<s>
These are <entity type="Ingredient">peppadew peppers</entity> which look like cherry peppers but they're not really very spicy at all.<s>
They're usually packed in kind of a sweetish brine.<s>
They've got a nice flavor profile.<s>
It's pretty complex.<s>
You can buy them in a jar, or if your grocery store has one of those, like, fancy olive bars they're usually also there.<s>
I've got a couple of those.<s>
You could totally use <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">cherry peppers</entity> instead, although they're going to be hotter than these, so keep that in mind.<s>
Or, sometimes you can even find <entity type="Ingredient">pickled red jalapenos</entity>.<s>
Perfect, that's all in there.<s>
Then, stir it around.<s>
This spoon is ridiculously small for this job.<s>
What am I, an idiot?<s>
Don't answer that.<s>
Here we go.<s>
To me this kind of <entity type="Recipe">potato salad</entity> with the spiciness and the extra <entity type="Ingredient">vinegar</entity> goes really, really well with grilled meats and barbecue, heavy meats like beef brisket or lamb.<s>
There we go.<s>
There's our <entity type="Recipe">spicy potato salad</entity>.<s>
If you like this recipe be sure to check out the Greek pasta salad recipe that I just made last week.<s>
Also, check out hilahcooking.com.<s>
You can get this printable recipe, and also I posted a grilled lamb recipe that would be superb alongside this <entity type="Recipe">potato salad</entity>.<s>
Try that this weekend, send me a picture of what you made, and I will love you forever, with my clothes on.<s>
Did I go out of frame?<s>
Sorry.<s>
That's delicious.<s>
It's tangy and refreshing and spicy, and I love it, and I hope you try it.<s>
I think you're really going to like it.<s>
Thanks so much for watching.<s>
Please don't forget to subscribe, and I'll see you later.<s>
Bye.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>