[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="4" title="Cracker Barrel Fried Apples -  CopyKat.com " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P8xo3vjLnB0" mode="non-automatic">
Hi, this is Stephanie Manley with CopyKat.com.<s>
Don't you just love <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel's fried apples</entity>?<s>
Well, guess what?<s>
I'm going to show you how to make <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel's</entity> famous <entity type="Recipe">fried apples</entity>, at home and in your own kitchen.<s>
All right, so I'm just finishing chopping up my <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>.<s>
You can make this recipe with about <entity type="Amount">five</entity> or <entity type="Amount">six</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>.<s>
My recipe calls for either <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity> or <entity type="Ingredient">bacon drippings</entity>.<s>
Now the Cracker Barrel doesn't use <entity type="Ingredient">bacon drippings</entity> in theirs, but you know what?<s>
This tastes really good with <entity type="Ingredient">bacon drippings</entity>, and that's how my grandma used to do it, so I can testify that that makes them very, very tasty.<s>
This recipe just has a few ingredients in it.<s>
That's about <entity type="Amount">five</entity> or <entity type="Amount">six</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">tart apples</entity>, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity>, <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">nutmeg</entity>, <entity type="Amount">some</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">cinnamon</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">lemon juice</entity>.<s>
So after you finish slicing up all of your <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>, you want to keep them a nice pretty color, so we are going to add just <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">lemon juice</entity> to this, and give it a stir before we take this over to the stove and start cooking our <entity type="Recipe">fried apples</entity>.<s>
Okay, so we're going to get started on our <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>.<s>
We're going to take our <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity> and melt that in the bottom of our skillet.<s>
Again, you can go ahead and use <entity type="Ingredient">bacon drippings</entity> if you happen to have <entity type="Ingredient">bacon drippings</entity>.<s>
It'll taste just as good.<s>
I'm going to let that <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity> get nice and melted, and next I'm going to add my <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>.<s>
I'm just going to pour them evenly on the bottom of my skillet.<s>
I'm cooking these on a medium heat, not too high, and not too low.<s>
I am using an all-clad skillet here, but you know what?<s>
I've seen many chefs use far less expensive skillets, so I think any skillet will really do.<s>
In fact, an iron skillet will be great for this as well.<s>
All right, so my <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity> is all nice and melted right now, and the <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity> are just beginning to release some of their juices.<s>
So now we are going to sprinkle in our <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity>, so we've added in our <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity>, it's just beginning to melt.<s>
I am going to add in my <entity type="Ingredient">cinnamon</entity>, and I am going to add in <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">nutmeg</entity>, and I'm just going to stir to incorporate.<s>
These smell just incredible.<s>
Now this <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity> and <entity type="Ingredient">brown sugar</entity> is going to make a really, nice, thick syrup, so these <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity> will fry in syrup, and the <entity type="Ingredient">butter</entity>.<s>
It's going to take about 15-20 minutes for these to finish up.<s>
Then we'll come back, when they're all nice and done.<s>
All right, so we're about halfway cooking these <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>, and you can see we have this wonderful thick syrup right here.<s>
So while these are cooking, just be sure to stir them every couple minutes.<s>
You're going to have some fabulous <entity type="Recipe">fried apples</entity>, so now you know how to make <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel fried apples</entity>, but you know what?<s>
I've got lots more great recipes online at copykat.com, and if you're watching this video on YouTube be sure to like or give the video a thumbs up, and let me know what recipe you would like to see next.<s>
These are my <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>, and you can see this wonderfully, creamy, syrupy sauce is all over these <entity type="Ingredient">apples</entity>.<s>
They're nice and soft now and they're going to taste just great!<s>
We're going to give this one a try, so good.<s>
Hi, I'm Stephanie Manley.<s>
Have you ever wondered how your favorite restaurant makes that special dish?<s>
Well, I've put together over 1500 recipes that taste just like they do in the restaurant.<s>
Visit copykat.com and find recipes from The Olive Garden, Outback Steakhouse, The Cracker Barrel, and so much more.<s>
Visit copykat.com, and discover recipes such as the Olive Garden Alfredo sauce, Olive Garden salad dressing, and Hooter's fried pickles.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>