[non-automatic.xml]
<transcripts>
<transcript id="5" title="Cracker Barrel Grilled Chicken Tenders " url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rLxiWv67tl4" mode="non-automatic">
Thank you for joining me here on Copycat Recipes.<s>
Today I'm going to show you how to make <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel chicken tenders</entity>.<s>
They are really easy to make and they're going to taste just like they do in the restaurant, and they have just four simple ingredients in them.<s>
Let me tell you what's in them.<s>
We're going to have <entity type="Ingredient">chicken tenders</entity> in here.<s>
Now if you don't have <entity type="Ingredient">chicken tenders</entity>, you can use <entity type="Amount">a</entity> boneless skinless <entity type="Ingredient">breast</entity>.<s>
Just cut it up into strips that are about one-inch wide and those will be perfect.<s>
We're going to use <entity type="Ingredient">Italian dressing</entity>, any brand will do.<s>
Honestly, don't spend a lot on this.<s>
Just buy what's ever on sale.<s>
It's going to be great.<s>
We're also going to use <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity> and <entity type="Amount">a couple</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">limes</entity> for <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">citrus zest</entity>.<s>
We're going to mix up the marinade.<s>
We're going to marinade these <entity type="Ingredient">chicken tenders</entity> for about an hour.<s>
Then we're going to cook them and they'll be perfect and they'll taste just like they do in the restaurant.<s>
So we're going to begin by making the marinade and this is really, really easy to do.<s>
You are going to take <entity type="Amount">one</entity> <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity> and slice it, and we're just going to go ahead and squeeze the <entity type="Ingredient">lime</entity> into our container.<s>
Now, I am mixing my marinade in the same container that I'm going to marinade the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> in.<s>
That way I can save a dish.<s>
Be on the lookout for any seeds, just in case that they come in.<s>
You're going to need about <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">tablespoon</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">honey</entity>.<s>
Then you're going to need about half <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">bottle</entity> of the <entity type="Ingredient">Italian dressing</entity>.<s>
This is a 16 ounce bottle.<s>
So we're going to use about half of this for the marinade.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Italian dressing</entity>, you can marinade anything in it.<s>
<entity type="Ingredient">Vegetables</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">steaks</entity>, all kinds of stuff.<s>
All right.<s>
So I'm going to give this a quick little stir.<s>
Then I'm going to simply put my <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> in here.<s>
Now I have about <entity type="Amount">a</entity> <entity type="Unit">pound</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> in here.<s>
If you have a little bit more, that'll be fine.<s>
We're going to marinade the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> now.<s>
Now marinade only works for the first time.<s>
So after we finish cooking the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> you need to discard the marinade and don't use it again.<s>
So we're going to give this a quick little shake.<s>
Put this in the fridge and we're going to come back in an hour and we're going to show you how to cook these up.<s>
All right.<s>
So our <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> has been marinating for just about an hour and it's time to go ahead and cook it.<s>
Now, I'm just using a regular skillet, just a nice large flat bottom skillet.<s>
I'm going to stick <entity type="Amount">a</entity> little <entity type="Unit">bit</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">oil</entity> in the bottom of the pan.<s>
You can use <entity type="Ingredient">olive oil</entity>, <entity type="Ingredient">vegetable oil</entity>, it really doesn't matter.<s>
You want to let this get a little bit warm.<s>
And remember for when it comes to this chicken marinade, don't use it again.<s>
It's for one time only.<s>
You can see it smells really good right now.<s>
And we will begin cooking it in just  a second.<s>
Okay, so we're going to begin cooking the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity>.<s>
Our pan is hot now.<s>
So you're just going to shake off the marinade here and just drop it in the pan.<s>
You're going to need to cook these on a medium, medium high heat for a couple of minutes on each side.<s>
It's not going to take any time at all.<s>
All right, now that I've put all the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> in the pan, you don't want to crowd it, you want to give it a little bit of space so it cooks nice and evenly.<s>
Be sure to discard the fork that you use for the marinade and get another one.<s>
We don't want raw <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> to contaminate anything else, so it's a clean fork right here.<s>
These are again, going to take about two to three minutes on each side and we're going to have perfectly cooked <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel chicken tenders</entity>.<s>
So you're going to know the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> is starting to cook, if you look on the side of the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> you'll see that it's starting to turn white.<s>
This will help you know that the <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> is actually cooking.<s>
No one likes raw chicken.<s>
So go ahead and make sure your <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> is cooked thoroughly.<s>
So my <entity type="Ingredient">chickens</entity> not yet ready to turn over just yet.<s>
So I'm going to put it back down and wait another minute or so and it should be nice and brown.<s>
You can see this <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> is just starting to brown nicely, so I'm going to go ahead and flip it.<s>
Okay, you can see this <entity type="Ingredient">chicken</entity> is wonderfully browned now.<s>
We're going to go ahead and take it out of the pan here.<s>
This stuff is great on salads.<s>
You might just want to make some up.<s>
Serve it on a plate with <entity type="Amount">a couple</entity> of <entity type="Ingredient">vegetables</entity> and you have dinner that didn't take too long at all.<s>
You could marinade this before you leave for work or even the night before for a little extra flavor.<s>
And here you go.<s>
There are some wonderful <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel chicken tenders</entity>.<s>
So we've just made the <entity type="Recipe">Cracker Barrel grilled chicken tenders</entity>.<s>
That was really easy.<s>
It just took four ingredients.<s>
So please be sure to subscribe to this channel and rate this video and leave me a comment in the box below and let me see what you'd like to see next.<s>
</transcript>
</transcripts>