done
hi guy lardner Catalina from Miami
kitchen
I'll bring you know what I like to call
my confetti birthday cake now
I can in November I
M I've never had a birthday party in
former
out what I did last weekend celebrated
my birthday
with birthday cake and I think yesterday
said to be with you because so many view
write me an email saying I can you show
me a birthday cake
you know I don't make for any pain see
cake for fun dont in all these cool
character that's just not my style I
love really good
food I love anything homemade for the
thing gorgeous fluffy white
vanilla cake with a gorges buttercream
so
it is absolutely amazing let me to human
being greedy
so to get started ily all-purpose flour
baking powder
salt granulated sugar egg white unsalted
butter softened at room temperature
her cream got the whole milk vanilla
extract and gas and %um even
this is with going to go all the way
through my battered economy so good now
coming below and let me know why
childhood
birthday cake what now to be completely
honest with you when I was a child
I didn't want a birthday cake I want my
fear I and I'll
the birthday cake a choice but I would
love to know from you
and I would love to know what your
either
your birthday month what the kick that
he would like to have maybe you might
see a pop-up all our ticket
fell that would be fine I think my a
white and I'm gonna use my
any mixer to with stop always how they
affect hun their
couple here for now
I PDF white actress Carey okay actually
need them later on in the recipe
but like a kid out previously in a
different episode
if I need to work egg white and within a
stand mixer I might as well get them
done at the way
because you can't with a white and a
dirty ball for you want to get those
done
and the way so now that that's done and
don't worry for a little bit remain
they have back totally fine now put the
on I know switch to a
paddle attachment I am going to
had in my beautiful egg whites Hathaway
I'm going to ask my softened butter
really important it's nice and soft
and sugar and you get these get
think creamed up to and could get the
thin Nathan creamy and fluffy
night excitement is making me like
center but that doesn't require J
you notice we have added whole eggs that
because I want this to be a gorgeous
white
for a eat cake actively delicious really
a treat I have the favored so worth it
to get your birthday
it's my birthday you know what eat cake
well I want by 10 per day anyway
I'm upset with this app or make sense I
thank you that's looking good and
add splash a vanilla extract
and at this point also can add my sour
cream I'm not
adding very much but this little tiny
bit gonna go a long way
you the luckiest thing ever the 550 ever
but if you don't have it you can use
yogurt if you don't have your work just
need a little extra milk
be totally fine sup ap
get these combine in the meantime I'm
just a quick second to make
together my flower baking powder and you
have to do a perfect but
the now I'm gonna add
have I have my flower half
and happen now brings back
up make that together and then add the
referee flower director the milk
any batter almost
at cooking courses hack mine came now
and that her I to you her
I prefer I'm going to just take that of
narrow
I'm gonna be able to I want to be able
to fold
pain the egg whites by hand their way i
can.
make sure that they're not being over
the next and then the plate
but to leave it at the tire that the
first thing you wanna do of course the
up in preheated 350 in a couple 9-inch
baking pans or
cake pans whatever you call them lined
with parchment paper and spread them
well
with some non-stick spray those are
ready and waiting
and now I'm doing and just taking my
spatula and want to make
everything from the bottom up
gorgeous that'd and I'm gonna take my a
white come to happen time
and make that in there this is gonna be
just
be you to follow and and hope the cake
why
season mister stunning is gonna make
that
wanted all makes you want divide
your batter email lean towards even you
can manage
among your people can
weekly okay now
these are gonna going to make preheat
oven to 350 for about 30 to 35 minutes
on Tyler
fully cooked and then we go into making
the butter cream which
if you love like wedding cake frosting
that about agree with it is just a
the a dream act opposite I
cakes baked for about 30 minutes now let
them cool completely on a wire rack and
I've done with one of them
they don't they're not cute don't
because remember we didn't add the egg
yolks we just have worked at the end
white
and fall the best comic the pavlova most
but where did I put on a
cake stand and then I just for a few
pieces
parchment paper around taught that the
cake then top doesn't get dirty ones I
go ahead
of day when make it really simple
buttercream and I'm really couldn't be
easier the first thing to do
as you need to start with paraffin
softened at room temperature
like that it's so so crucial you
absolutely need to be
at proper speech so to have here
a good amount of butter because again
this is parked free making this is my
standing mixer
because it easier it is to with with for
a long time so
gonna pop that and just add
some vanilla extract about tablespoon a
bit
that is a vanilla buttercream after all
and I'm scale
what this up until it just the butter
such got no
get selling have some concessions here
from holmdale for this highlighting
this year okay
lol so happy are they failed to mention
is just a small pinch of salt because
it all perfection show you what I know
is a lot but it is a buttercream
and just me Adelaide also out to cut all
the sweetness
it really does it's a great balance
understand add me sugar
trying to not get it all over the place
I think it's a pretty well
a/c well and then just a splash of milk
only couple tablespoons
milk and now I'm going to get this %uh
and get it going and mixing in this
could take up
10 minutes I mean buttercream goes from
St Sep crumbly for perfection
the EQ have patience and by hand do you
feel it so it makes life a lot easier go
let companies
all-girl perfect here
backed
is perfection it took a good four-minute
mixing but I mean look at that I so
fluffy
so worth the wait so
quite there yet again it's really rich
but I promise you
this is that once in awhile tree typical
wedding cake you don't hear very often
the most the time
frothing is the wedding cake are
prepping
so just gonna mix have again immense
pleasure
because the buttercream because if you
make buttercream at home that you know
the consistency that you looking for
sell
there's just something about it I just
give me great pleasure so this is
completely done
and now will be going on frosting and
its political little bit a bit
not too much about say
third and I'm just using
of that fashion here
black fashion chest smear that you don't
have to go
all the way to the edges are like
doesn't matter because we are going to
cover the whole thing
from thank you we have applied for this
human no idea
ever did in the summer jealous very
jealous
take the remaining frosting
China all adults here
now I have my birthday the November
have never had remember one year my
mother through birthday party for me in
the stomach
as I remember crying good all my friends
and I was a child
out their birthdays were in in warmer
months they could have parties outside
and I never could
I remember my mother once threw me a
party in like middle and chill I
which was amazing cell I be those who
have summer birthdays because they get
to be outside at parties
but I'm just going to frost this as you
can see I'm drinkin down
and then this is why I love favorite
eating cake stand this is why by the way
you put parchment down because
if that were to happen especially if
you're anything like me your like
complete and total mess when you
frosting cake
it helps a lot
and I just want to take the top and just
do little for a lifetime
don't have to do this clearly I'm not
now after a decorating cakes
it is just ahead my way million look
beyond in
terrible I know think not my forte
okay or my mother's that's why
department so beautiful
because now you get the pic Department
happened you have
no mess on your hands don't know lab
when that happened no math and over the
pro
and they don't tell your friends that
the district that later like
how did you manage to do and I am like
I'm not good and now
and I want to take additional Jimmy
because I want everyone to see
that this is the perfect birthday cake
them and put them all over the top
the more the merrier when it comes to
Jimmy now
somehow is a plane for confronting
which lead me to believe that even know
if my only pretend birthday
I should stop happy the cake I'm going
to
gonna go in for going over there right
that's gonna be a big piece Lara but it
is you pretend birthday so you really
should
indulge I
now if you don't like it much frosting
have the recipe make happy about
crossing I'll be really thin layer
but way to protect work that you do what
you want gonna
the dimethyl ether lick if you had a
confetti cake for your birthday
thumbs up this video and I love you and
Joe you
you and I really do like my theater
thats red-top
in
such a beautiful flavor cake
that buttercream like that way crossing
that we all know and love it we get that
you know maybe once a year
absolutely divine girl Laura in the
kitchen a company that's what the f open
interest going to let me let me know
what you think a birthday cake is I
would love to recreate it for your
special day
think happy mine