done
%uh
one
hi I alarm tally end today
binary quite we are making cookie dough
ice cream i've had cell many people
after this recipe
it insane any that she will you really
simple
has some people ask me if cookie dough
ice cream is just simply
crushed up at a cookie thin ice cream
not
six-day we can meet the real thing so so
easy and
ice cream is something that I really
only make in the summertime so
I'm always looking forward to sharing a
new recipe with you
the recipe to make the custard it pretty
simple and basic even any some whole
milk
heavy cream egg yolks sugar have asylum
in a pinch of salt
any their vanilla bean or I have got
some bonilla be peace
here so it makes my life well it'll be
easier this is really easy
now we are gonna meet the custard now
and I'll show you later headed the
cookie dough and then we combine
everything together is going to be
money okay let's get started so simple
a good large saucepan here in here I'm
going to add make repayment ok
and both were at the same time we think
of and tonight facts
and now an added a good spoonful love
the vanilla paste
you would need wanna vanilla bean
that you would scrape down and get rid
of erupting all the seen out on
bring here no means I'll but music know
the peso
and healthy spoonful that's sure to
check
just can't take this of you to put this
on my serve topped I like this come to
temperature to a simmer
over that medium-low heat now while my
milk mixture is coming to a simmer
I'm going to just take my egg yolks and
sugar with a little pinch assaults
am gonna with teeth together until the
mixture becomes really nice
think and pay all collar actually looks
like when he gets there basically
essentially what we're making right now
is the I am
target the %um the unit nothing but
was all she became difficult to be is
just egg yolks
sugar delivered the news in a bit ago
but this needs to be with
implored really late and pay off and
about doubled
in volume actually looks like what if
they are keeping I
out on your milk mixture you do not want
to come to a boil because it does a will
flake
and then you have to start all over and
waste all that milk and cream and now I
so keep an eye on that in just a couple
minutes
and then you should be done sleepin egg
yolk mixture it
well and you're getting of the all work
at all while you're at it
i'm looking at the right temperature you
can feed as little bubbles are starting
to form around the edge up the pot which
is when I know
it and a perfect simmer by and get as
you can see I
texture this Anthony see kinda falls
down as on a ribbon
now that's perfect let 'em pretty egg
yolks by just taking
little bit I love my milk mixture just
about a half a cup or sell
and this is all doing is tempering the
egg yolk for that
they don't come in you don't get shocked
when you pour them into
the pan the hot liquid that's all you
need to do
going to now poor my egg yolk mixture
aimed shoot my pant very simple
just making it easy easy and very
classic
ice cream custard pink and now I'm going
to look at the color that
look at back collar just because they're
happy you have no idea
okay I switched back to my wooden spoon
and let cook this over about a low heat
until if they can really nicely and
coats the back of my spin
and I will show you what it looks like
one they are just make sure your
you keep this on a low heat and take
your time and be gentle
because of this comes to a boil or gets
too hot
it will split it want to split again you
will
no one is split and there is no going
back for just take your time
stir it like a figure in Figure eight
motion I like I'm doing right now
and then just be patient and when he
gets nice and thick you be able to
notice it
immediately my custard is ready
been cooking for about six minutes and
you can see it coming back a spoon if I
run my finger down
and Custer see separated you know if
they can a does it again he didn't act
with a path mister
save can't think Anthony eggshells
remaining or anything
colonel whatever if they've backed it up
again to your final
mixture as you can see this is smooth
sailing
all the way that's how I like it
I like it ice and snow there's really
nothing
maybe a little little tiny bit or
something remaining but for the most
part everything is really nice and
okay now you need to wrap this like
plastic back and you want to make sure
that the Catholic it actually typing
the surface %uh the custard on what are
they just forms are really weird looking
skin
that you don't want an eighth definitely
not gonna be smooth and delightful
want to go ahead and freeze there's
something a pop this into the fray
janiece to be in the fridge for about
four to six hours or best overnight
death
even better cricket but this is the free
in the fridge overnight even better some
gonna
leave this and it's pretty early in the
day to day thought get to finish this
afternoon and I'll show you what it
looks like
what's this chill will be going on
making our cookie dough and they will
put the whole thing off
an can't while the custard if telling
we're gonna go into making the cookie
dough batter now actually making a
chocolate chip cookie dough batter here
and now if back travel to cookie dough
if dat
bothers you because nothing net ne this
week up to you
kinda eating rocky del which I love and
I know everybody
eat raw cookie dough at some point in
their lives now if this bothers you then
you might wanna skip this ice cream
on in its entirety can make my chocolate
ice cream you can make my
strawberry mint chocolate chip banana
whatever you want I got to recipes on my
website
but more time cookie dough ice cream
have actual cookie dough and that'll
make the so delicious I wanna make
like we would make chocolate chip
cookies but really easy and to do that
you'll need some
am all-purpose flour I'm going up into
thought that and got them
instance press a pattern you just a
small little pinch
found sugar granulated sugar some
softened unsalted butter
and egg but now axed after what I have
here are some chocolate chip type of
in my food processor something you can
see it got little bubbles at that time
there are bigger
I found a kind a whole everything I love
about cookie dough ice cream is that you
actually get bits and pieces of
chocolate chips or chocolate throughout
the entire ice cream
and I think this type of thing in a few
times in breaking the peace
a bit just give it a little more
interest and I think these AT PT almost
dust
like pieces I love the chocolate is what
makes this so divine
in my opinion so if you wanna skip going
up part by all means do that I think
crucial have to have a nine by 13 inch
baking pan here
Lancaster a big piece of parchment paper
cuz you wanna make sure
18 lifted up that setting aside so that
they got
I'm going to just came together make
butter and both kinds of sugar
gonna do this just a smaller balks and
feel like a
and getting my mixer africa is a small
batch just gonna make these two together
until combined
at the time did not have been added me
ank and Kenny wanna make sure that
whoever you making this for what eat
raw cookie dough just wanna make sure
that you don't sound
have anyone that Kenny row and the one
not just
given a heads up the switch to my with
briefly
just kill mix everything together a
little bit better
just mixing together the coffee and
sought
adding any leavening agents this no
baking soda at
you need to me you know 8 yet cell them
make a difference in the put my egg make
sure you normally would put the dry
into my wet but I switchboard for some
reason
and our the flower was inevitable when I
just 1/2
to have room to make this together next
breath basically on doing I'm just gonna
combine this until it performs into a
Dell
making at in can actually and my top it
now because it's almost there
time as well 101 overworked this anyway
had in mind chocolate chip mixture
in of add I'm take a bar of chocolate
chopped up if you want to that would be
lovely
adding chocolate chips when you can add
me to check
but yes see what I mean when I say that
I think this is so much better because
that way
you really getting chocolate iraq every
little p.m.
time bite and the cookie dough I just
get to watch it here
a talkative their I want to completely
abuse throughout the entire
cookie dough so that's why I like the
part of the NFL her little thing that
really make a difference otherwise you
know I would get better
now okay now I'm gonna put the first
me get my cookie dough out of here
apps will fix that in a minute do not
panic
talk to myself by the way now
on doing in this is Camille little bit
tricky I'm trying to get this into
pretty thin layer because I'm only free
says tonight for the fed a free
there we're gonna need to chop it into
smoky
said but co-lead you can see but I'm not
too worried about getting a perfect
and I want to be that way about it
either and it doesn't have to be all one
layer I'm just doing it this way because
it
easier till cut it when the prison
cell just gonna do that and I'm gonna
pop this
into my finger how it for several hours
are a long it takes for the custer to
chill
caught the more frozen the better e65 to
chop it up from the happened fan
look I'm now the trust me when I tell
you it worked wonders
pop in the thin waiting for my culture
to can I think all
and I will go on and but all in all
machine and Daggett that much closer to
you but I don't think
by custard with in the fridge overnight
to what's going on in there for a few
hours but then we had my aunt over and
maybe a cocktail or two and we decided
to wait till tomorrow
ice cream which is good because it's the
weekend perfect time for entertaining
and ice cream now I have my ice cream
machine here
you want to make sure that the insert
the ice cream machine which is this guy
right here that's going up
basically for your ice cream for you is
frozen
now you wanna check always you
manufactures instructions because
every ice cream machine is different
when other one so my face to put in
there overnight to death to do it really
nice and solid for a sandwich it's
really important so make sure that you
read instructions because some I just a
couple hours
amor most the time will take overnight
so now I have my really cold custard
which is
absolutely fantastic I mean look at that
and this would be good on its own as it
is
I am over top maybe barey these or what
not
the poor that in the air get it all out
up now is how to turn this on now and
again
check the manufacturer's instructions
because it's gone but I'm gonna marry
mine takes a good 25 to 30 min you free
the ice cream
but there are also different some gonna
wait for this to be pretty much
virtually frozen and then we'll get
going on adding
our cookie dough
Ari my it exactly where I wanted about
25 minutes and now
gonna take my cookie dough the in the
freezer overnight
as well which is what we want in this is
why did good on parchment because it's
so easy
and now I just take a shark Night ending
no
particular way I just I'm gonna just
wrap this up into bite-size pieces that
is it
you ken you really can do in this
an a couple different ways of doing it
the way I'm doing it you can take
little teaspoons love the batterer we
know months you may get and then put me
on a baking sheet lined with parchment
and fried it that way and then that you
can just clip but the anti ice machine
I to do it this way I don't know why I
just think it's easier
and I'm get the job done a lot faster
and you can also leave certain pieces
bigger or smaller like that perfect so
now I'm just gonna go across
and Jess broth cha page
on everything into that bite size pieces
and it
and do want to mention that it sounds
like this is really hard could it
its it's not it just sounds hard because
you were rough
you know cutting through chocolate I'm I
just want to mention that the as I'm
done there's something ken
you can hear the crunch for the crunch
is just because we're chopping up
the chocolate tell anyway figured I'd
let you guys know that act
announced and take the pieces in a you
can cut these as big or small
as you want and you can add as much or
as little as you want to
your cookie dough batter it's up to you
I'm gonna have no service but most
likely not all I think the from my
and of for people to served
of recalled
and this is money yeah buddy
now I only added about half a
the chocolate in cookie dough mixture in
here because I didn't want to add to
queue much because then
you can also have a hard time with your
machine being able to handle
all that but look at this I mean and you
seeing what I'm seeing and also
are you see how those little rubble Dove
chocolate
kinda spread all throughout the batter
and that's from
when I took the chocolate pieces the
child chips and put them through
different processor kit that is
personally what I like
obviously you want big chocolate chips
here and there but
why have a little bit when you can have
chocolates row
are look at that I mean just if you get
up close you can see
that it's really creamy it's got this
big chunks
have cookie del I'm just to make myself
a little ask
okay path just just just scoop
just scoop on a town I am deserving
work 0 go to pieces
I'll mmm you love this
a promise you will love this
it's so easy in taste so
much better store-bought I cannot stress
enough I can sing the easy to do
doesn't take a hard time doesn't take
any fancying gradient that's very basic
but it done
the right where you can seem me it's
just
it's phenomenal the chocolate pieces in
there then
on time thing in my head that
Lauren did not come I have the right to
be ready for you let me know what ice
cream you wanna teaneck
open endorsement mean and I
I'm useless
my left hip at
use what they tell you youth
come tony Horton's nothing on this
for while
our custard can be anywhere
so our beer
cookie dough ice cream how don't