done
hi guy la Riva tally 9 that was an
online tickets now wanna share with you
my recipe for what I call my jelly roll
i three bomb now
there are so many variations you can
make and yes really
let me know if you wanna see different
variation and then this one
even coming down below but day other
sure with the use of mine
a jelly roll that's good strawberry jam
in the air and that's gonna be
with strawberry ice cream and mango
sorbet it but
nominal it looks incredibly can be
easier you could definitely take a
shortcut
by jelly were already pre-made but today
I think it'd they already have my ice
cream and sorbet
done we meet the jelly roll together
being green don't need to make the
actual jelly roll a very
plain and simple wondering all purpose
flour baking powder salt
grain and sugar the bank that separated
into yolks and whites
now pay for you can use an hour extract
some milk
I went preheated 375 I'll to have 10
15 by 10 inch baking pan here
I've lined with parchment you want to
use spray with nonstick spray as well
because cam stick even to parchment
paper so
precaution now I'm everything in my
stand mixer just because it's really
easy in the first thing I'm gonna do
the National with the egg whites I'm
gonna take my way to put them in my
stand mixer mix restating mixers clean
and I just go with and other like coffee
like 50 family top
stately good needed to be skip actually
going to sleep attachment
now take my paddle attachment to finish
the rest the batter but first
I just wanna get the white out that I
don't eat them into the and I wanted to
do them first because
egg whites do not clear if you bowl
dirty cell a case like this a Mike Dunn
first and I think about the matter
that way to have to dirty up and another
bowl okay adding my
egg yolks and my sugar and now I'm going
to just put on my pal attachment
and crane pose together until the really
liked and KL
fluffy a couple minutes but doing a buy
and sell
let it go the I
the Alex excellent just gonna and an
a spoonful love my Penelope's by all
means you can use vanilla extract but
companies now pay if they were really
want that now a favor plan just perfect
thank you her
lower the stamp mixed together my
flour with baking powder and assaults
and then up
along with now and i wanna
well as backup and I just think that
until it all come by
you want this to be fairly slip don't
over mix
otherwise here not as lucky
court just but we do have to kill
folding
the egg whites understand it up with my
spatula after that I don't deflate them
too much
trying to get all the batter of your
little better here or your power
attachment
as much as you can anyway I love to
always give
everything a good stir from the sides
and bottom
an ad in my egg whites do half
at a time so that I don't deflate them
and I think and work
quickly you can see I'm falling and take
my
spatula stick it right in the middle and
then you fold over
stick in the middle foldover that
such a gorgeous batter I love that you
can see
the bubbles from yet quite that's gonna
give you
really beautiful lights key
it I'll do my best Chiefland this is
from
s me they can manage with my spatula
don't panic if it's not perfect because
let's face it
no one will know the difference and I
just always biting around
the pan I think that just makes it
easier get as
evenly as possible excellent
this is gonna go into your preheated
oven to 375 for twelve to fourteen
minutes
or into what a lovely light golden color
in cooked all the way through them
is pretty finishing take that long from
the gate but that anasazi comes I will
show you
and the next make it completely cooked
they cooked for exactly 40 minutes and i
was just take a trip beginning with a
jockey
spaghetti they get enough parts there's
no what batter on
it's good now let it cool for about two
to three minutes no longer
maybe five now I have here a wind
free kitchen towel about the same side
as the cake
and I'm going to cover death
and from confectioner sugar because we
need to roll the up
so you wanna make sure that you
sprinkled with sugar and or if you get
on your counter
too early fine and now going to now I
did take
a night a butter knife n it just
releases really easily corrected
I am I did but if Greece that really
really well
I'm going to just in Perth this
just like that 6 do not panic
BC making sure that it's really name
and greased really helped and then I
just tried to straighten is better like
and now I'll call us around this by so
that you can think exactly what I'm
doing
about that now just you you fold
literally the tower in the cake shooting
shorting her story for one another stir
and
just roll this tightly but not too tight
just like that and that will take she a
a jelly born and this has to cool
completely
could take a couple hours something I
just placed on equalling math
allow it to cool completely and then
we'll move on to the next step
now I did I do have my ice cream in the
freezer already
against rubber ice cream and I have got
my mango sorbet
but I do know a great website our
internet com
we have to both recipes for you if you
wanna make them from scratch
or if you want a shortcut by the grocery
store the choicest
entirely up to you know that that's cool
completely and then we'll move on to
next
and this was calling for a couple of
hours announced going to
I'm wrapping and don't worry if it can
look
walking because that you know you want
to do that want to go back into
same shape now a happier if some
strawberry preserves
you can use whatever preserve like I
mean it totally
up to you and what I'm doing it I am
just spreading
a nice then layer up there I'm not gonna
go all the way up because as I rolled it
will squeeze out
and as you can see there's some actual
pieces obstruct barry's here in their
cell
I'm gonna try and get this and even as
possible
kinda concentrating with leaving a cup
about an inch or so
I'm from all sides open because I get
again when this gets rolled ask us went
out what's
really fine but no one overdo it
this looks good enough and I want to be
too cubic
I think that looks perfect to me spatula
but
clearly a spoon works really really well
and now I'm going to just roll it back
up
this time you're not gonna roll beam
kitchen talent and Android just
like that
her and now I'm going to put this
she squirted a little tiny bit
we didn't pick you too much so sheet
okay many places here I'm going to just
racked this with some I'll up plastic
wrap
a little bit because I don't want this
to get through hard in the pocket into
the fridge for a half hour
or until it see knock-on effect on hold
shape
and then we will get ready to start
building are welcome
ice cream my Delhi bowlers in the fridge
for a bad hour now let me show you what
I have here
at a large bowl and don't worry about it
mention the measurement on every think
they will
right everything in detail on the on the
recipe and will be online to get him to
calm
and i'm taking a bow and headline that
well with some parts up with a plastic
bag ban on each other the plastic
wrappers
overhanging I have a small bowl
which I show you later I have got some
strawberry ice cream and left a
room temperature for out fifty-minute I
said you want this to be a little
often easy for you to work with nail to
have an orange
on argue that it's over ardent 28
echoing you the mystery knife I am going
to cut slices
on my jelly roll now cut them choo-choo
think actually
company would be will be better if I
just use this now I'm
I'm going to just cut my spices not to
think not to
then the bath I would say for half an
inch they could be a little bit less
than that
now I'm just taking slices up my jelly
roll and if you need to tighten them up
a little bit you can
I really do not do this in any
particular order I don't worry about
things looking perfect because the end
result
is just so too late for that it does not
matter
you just wanna make sure that you
covered fry
and the bottom up your bowl
you can cut them to fit to totally fine
just like taking a little bit my orange
juice in just drizzling
on the cake and keeps a little bit more
moist in some time
I'm be very honest with you depending on
one making its for
dependent on a year some time until it
agreed Monday
I'm doing a cherry base and although
cherry brandy
doesn't matter but today and using our
expertise aback
the ice cream should be softened enough
at this point because you do
need to be able to maneuver this around
the net looking
good benefit peeks through
little hole than that sparking just do
like and then you
gonna push it on the side
just like so try again and even as you
can
now show you are gonna do with Apple in
just a minute because the center
is going to be where we put our mango
sorbet and not just yet analyze
everything we're kinda bland
altogether I'm just going to do this and
even as possible as quickly as possible
good don't want the ice cream to melt
keep it clean
night take my ball but why make sure to
clean bowl
and you want to make sure that it's just
fit perfect
I'm not going to do it just like that
sorry if I'm moving a little fast but
arguing with ice cream okay now I'm
gonna do
I'm just going to cue rap aside like
this
pop this into the freezer for about an
hour or so or until
the strawberry ice cream is Foley for
then
again and then we'll be going quite a
lot by I know
now actually passed this into the
freezer overnight
at o'hare point-man what can I say girl
gotta do what a girl's gotta do
and also even better because I where you
can completely forget about a nigga
Nathan for than
now quick it it when you had a ball in
there it can be quite frozen so I do if
they take a kitchen towel
and I sort of right now one on the hot
water and
set my kitchen tile in the bowl for a
couple minutes until
it kinda starts shoot thought the right
the ice cream
right around the board just a little bit
and then it comes up super easy and
simple
now I have here some mango sorbet any
that room temperature
one at room temperature I left it out
room temperature for a bit because I
want this to be really nice and smooth
and pliable
never ever move the ball I'm going to
fill
this with my mango sorbet
that really lovely see that for myself
gonna cover the backup with my plastic
wrap
because you wanna make sure it's nice
and cover am actually going
to take this little plates
just sorta squeeze everything together
now I'm gonna pop that
back into the freezer for several hours
any that me
may look for baby three completely for
the could take up to a couple hours
and they don't it will be time to on
bail
the beauty so what
everything it's for that solid it's good
to go to What done anything in a small
paring knife
and you've got around the edges and just
come fly them so that it was
just almost one flat layer that wait
hold
better I'm it to the wall as much when
you try to cut it but don't throw them
away
Cook Street I would have to have those
the best for the job
identified a threat it's right that but
i wanna have here
is my flatter has just a cake stand
around cake stand
now flip the surrounds
now we have passed the crap cell that
really help
make the job a lot easier just I think
my chefs like
and I'm kind ducking into warm water
now I'm drying off on a clean kitchen
towel
and they'll go n really easy
and that makes for a really nice clean
that this is a really big slice
because mainly I wanna show you quite
how beautiful this is on the outside and
mean yes
the outside just gorgeous Indian
catch-twenty pretty SL
and take nap look at that
if that now beautiful now want to carry
deal you can also make this multiple
layers of them doing two layers ice
cream like I did
you get a cherry ice cream chocolate
just do a bunch a different layers
to be really fine but I like the company
should I think the jelly roll with the
show berry jam and a strawberry ice
cream which is
so creamy and delicious with the mango
sorbet I think absolute magic
I'm gonna give this a try that be to
fall
that give this a go I'm have to hold on
just a little pick the really big piece
yep their my little bit of everything
I was gonna do that them so used to it
mom one
work although that
off from
it got everything they possibly want
legal
cool the whole
I have everything it possibly I'm a
beautiful sweet punch cake
a little sweetness from the jam the
combination up the chart very and mangos
the combats meet in food heaven
and we couldn't be easier you make this
way ahead of time if you do have a
dinner party or make the sport
perfect for summer opening just plain
come with me girl our index no comp the
rain recipe
let me know if you have a special that
the specific combination of flavors
you like with the ice cream Bangalore
love Chinese combination
in fine