done
%uh
one
hi guy a heart attack million on for
personal art and get a non-issue repeal
a treaty ally to call my floor
cookie-cutter now I know this and really
anti
that they could not be easier not the
perfect treat it give us more
that you don't have a campfire or had a
bagel Aboriginal you
fire outside an all-black these are easy
to make in their
absolutely delicious thing green
journeyed are very the OMB think that
very simple one especially
if you love to make forcing my already
have anything green
on hand let me take you over there to
get started Lisa
all-purpose flour baking soda from Salt
some ground graham crackers I've got
going into sugar brown sugar
on talk about its release of a different
temperature and got a little Hershey
bars I'm just little bars the side that
I just cut up into little squares and I
have some shredded chocolate at about an
imminent
and all mini marshmallows and vanilla
extract and that its it
couldn't be any easier now wicked I took
a plan to these little app
Hershey bars and I just for separate
them but they needed like 48
little pieces and they took some good
idea about a quarter cup grated
chocolate and I just took up
microplane you can use your box grater
or anything that's sort of like a
not as finance a and Esther
so I don't discredit just like that in
about a quarter cup star lead the rest
and make it a try and the first thing
you want okay
I'm in preheated 375 what I happier
company must contend that I increased
with nonstick cooking spray if you wanna
get that out of the way
and I'm just gonna make everything in
life team expects to make my life a lot
easier
now in this poll going to add in mind
butter
thats borderline melted because I've had
it on the stove
while the other was preheating such
sites not a little bit but that's
perfectly fine
felt kinda sure and going cream
together to sugar if thou well combined
with the butter bath looking great I am
just going to scrape down
the paddle attachment and just society
the ball
side at the borders gonna make sure
everything is incorporated adding in my
bank in the good splash vanilla extract
and I'm just gonna make this together
until every combined now why
did I took some graham crackers thank
you
whole family law like her I'm so it with
a fine powder
tackling one left here and speaker
make some I'm trying to bring together
just to give them a head start
it doesn't have to be perfect because
gonna get picked up anyway
and baby think it fit fight make p
I the perfect
give it a little scraper ru and now
we're just gonna
at and Ryan very simple guy like you
making a chocolate chip cookie man to
tackle chip
is gone and enjoying reading in and the
great chocolate and looking totally
I'll make the great talk but if you want
to but they make thirty p and while you
must keep on chocolate is beyond me
but you can omit if you want to to feel
like this make them twenty got still
come
in toledo come together and there will
be ready Sheila
if you think Allen that is exactly what
I'm looking for
it had the right consistency if for my
walk
I'm going to stick that I love how come
that really nice and clean and
effortless which yeah pushed
baby i love the way now you can you
a tablespoon or ask any other nights an
ice cream scoop Michael Heaney any ice
cream scoop that's about a tablespoon
decided the tables turn and I am just
going to take that
and Papa into each little muffin cash
once you have them off scooped out and
just role in your hand for that their
tournament when I me ball and then you
put it in your mouth in 10 now
issues healthy and fit oppressing them
down you
can use whatever you want to make indent
a rolling pin
is not only my Nana a weapon but it also
multi-purpose in the kitchen
her I that the evidence
and going pee and it works perfectly for
that I need so on a different kind of
cookie cups I magnin telhami chorionic
putting could pick up
you name it and if you like to see them
coming down below I'll
but this was perfectly I just think the
and my I'm
growing pain and I just wanna press it
right in the middle and wiggle it around
and you can see and make the perfect
indent miss gonna continue to do that
all around up
her back now to pop baby into my
evidence been preheated 375
know been there for about seven to eight
minutes or until the edges started a
lovely golden brown color it when they
come out
show you what did my little cups for in
the oven for about nine minutes
now when they come out and the Middle
Calif a little bit have top but what you
do is you take the N double rolling pin
where spoon whatever you using
and then you just reinforce that indent
that we made cell we have those done
these just mad the other now I'm
done that turned my I other non to broil
because I'm not I no longer need the
oven on to border on
they take away a piece of chocolate
optional but
you now chocolate and I'd take a little
tiny piece
usually cut this little square in half
and I put that
very bad I'm a peach wine
okay now they have backed you can add a
couple March melting each one
I'm gonna do probably three or four
marshmallows depending on how many I can
it I do like me some marshmallows now
some probably gonna try and do for each
one
some may only be able to do three yeah
because they're gonna pop up at the peak
so let's just do with three
I'll be he I'm gonna pop
this under boiler and just boil them
long enough to the top of the
marshmallow to look at the light golden
brown color and indie pop up a little
bit
only keep them in there for like many
keep I on them because they can go from
perfect the burned in
second cell about a minute she did a job
at
just keep your eye on day
look help direct now you can meet acted
because you do have a chocolate
on the bottom act I mean
well you know I just like a little tiny
bit on
ap just say the middle
her she love that way you can tell
Thomas morn
want to have a little square chocolate
on top each one
allow it to fit for about five minutes
what happened if the heat from the
marshmallow
starts a beautiful enough to talk with
the yeah
a little Pete apathy in the same shape
watch
might take one out is this one comes up
absolutely beautiful the cabin of a
lightning golden that is
watch Death she had a chocolate actually
beautifully soft aha %uh I now
if they look at the bar tacked on top
right
Iron Man Cromar
I want to seem the liars shop at the
bottom
not well to be put up on top
incredible base
I quit
I planned I don't but I'm only kidding
is
a phenomenon such killed a twist on a
classics more
I would absolutely love for you to
recreate this recipe
and share a picture with me on Instagram
Facebook Twitter whatever you prefer
nothing beats me more joy and seeing you
recreate the recipe
I hope you enjoy spending time with me
at a what these
will be the star ever next cookout I
think its producer
in the choir thing about the time I
penny that the top look at the bar
chocolate but
but not telling doing a delicious just
do it
girl aren't company recipe going to
explain County
about law
them
the 1